<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>
    Data Center on ForwardingPlane.net
    
    </title>
    <link>https://forwardingplane.net/tags/data-center/</link>
    <description>Recent content 
    
    in Data Center on ForwardingPlane.net
    </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2019, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 16:42:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    
        <atom:link href="https://forwardingplane.net/tags/data-center/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ravello Systems review and use case study</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ravello-systems-review-and-use-case-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 16:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ravello-systems-review-and-use-case-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a vast number of entities that offer the seemingly ubiquitous “cloud”. “SaaS”, “IaaS”, “BLAHaaS”, buzzword compliance is truly a sought after thing by marketing folks. With the proliferation of virtualization, containers and other “time slicing” of hardware by software the chatter can quickly become noise. As technical professionals and the warm bodies with the responsibility for actually making things work and keeping them running, the onus is on us to be able to decipher the useful from the fluff. A staggeringly large number of institutions, enterprise, education, research, and government all rely heavily on virtualization as a cornerstone for cost savings and operational ease. This makes sense, there is real cost savings in both operational and capital money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ravellosystems.com/&#34;&gt;Ravello&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I was given access to an interesting emerging product brought about by the original developers of the venerable &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linux-kvm.org/page/Main_Page&#34;&gt;KVM&lt;/a&gt;. Ravello offers something new, something a bit different and something potentially useful for a number of different applications. Ravello is essentially a cloud overlay. I find the interfaces for both the Amazon EC2 and Google compute engine clunky and unintuitive from an operational perspective. While APIs are decent, I am a poor developer and really have no desire to write code to their APIs. When I need results now, I want compatibility and a good interface and I’ll wager most other operational folks do too. This is an element that is hard to acheive and where I was a tad surprised by the Ravello platform. The interface for their cloud overlay was quite elegant and &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; intuitive. That’s important. However, what it actually does is more significant. The Ravello overlay allows a VM admin to import an existing image in its native form (either VMWare or KVM), deciphers the networking metadata from the images and builds the network for them automatically. This is cool in and of itself, but the real power is the combination of that “admin candy” and the ability to tune the knobs for things like which cloud provider (AWS or GCE) to push your resources to, allow optimization for things like cost or performance and the option to time shutdown of the resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For smaller institutions and enterprises the value seems self evident. As an example, lets say you want to model a change to your data center network which includes an SRX firewall, 3 window servers, 10 linux servers and a load balancer. These resources can all be uploaded into the ravello cloud. It does its best to figure out the network, allowing for some reasonably powerful changes to the configuration right from their interface. Snaphot the entire network from their canvas (which looks like a nice network diagramming tool), make the changes and monitor the result. If it doesn’t work you can roll it back or hack at the consoles of the devices using their VNC based console access to figure out what went wrong.&lt;br /&gt;
In addition to the aforementioned benefits, there were some other surprises. The time to provision was quite good, importing at the speed of upload and then fairly quickly deciphering the needed pieces. It is also obviously self service, meaning I can import, enable, tweak and disable within a choice of cloud based hosting services; flexibility is always good, especially when it is well implemented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall my impression of Revello is that is provides some pretty interesting and useful stuff, especially when considering utilizing it as a lab for testing upgrades, changes, etc. Many small to medium sized environments do not have resources to put into a physical lab, virtualizing it for a fraction f the cost has a lot of merit and value. Overflow for event based demand is also an obvious use case and again ease of use implementation is key.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The NEC surprise</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/the-nec-surprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 06:52:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/the-nec-surprise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href=&#34;http://necam.com/&#34;&gt;NEC&lt;/a&gt; began talking about SDN at &lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/event/nfd9/&#34;&gt;Network Field Day 9&lt;/a&gt;, I was not sure what to expect. I knew they had been heavily involved with openflow since the early days, and many years ago I was able to get my hands on their early OpenFlow controller and was immediately frustrated by its cryptic nature and frankly, poor documentation. Their switches were fine and were heavily utilized in early OpenFlow deployments. I knew they had decent support and were squarely on board the SDN train. Their controller, in 2010, was not terribly fun to work with. It was (if memory serves) prohibitively expensive and the support manual was nearly as cryptic as the controller. Because it&amp;rsquo;s my personality type, I went in with a very open mind, hoping to be surprised. After all, it&amp;rsquo;d been 4+ years since I&amp;rsquo;d seen that controller. Well, I am here to report that I will happily eat some crow. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Eat-Crow.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Eat-Crow.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Eat Crow&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;   A few things became very apparent to me as I sat and watched the presentation from NEC, which you can view in its entirety below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NEC is not messing around with their SDN offering. They&amp;rsquo;ve been in the openflow game since the beginning and the polish on their controller shows it. The topology is quite nice and they&amp;rsquo;ve got a finished looking product that would find itself at home in a decent sized NOC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NEC is playing well with others. Their demo consisted of both NEC and DELL whitebox switches. To me this is an indication of both great forward thinking and a clear message that the controller is a product that can stand on its own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NEC is setting the barrier of entry low. Very low. They&amp;rsquo;ve got an entry level &amp;ldquo;SDN in a box&amp;rdquo; that consists of their controller and a few switches for like 3k. They&amp;rsquo;re also offering a 90 day free trial on their controller that is bundled with &lt;a href=&#34;http://mininet.org/&#34;&gt;mininet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Like most other controllers, the NEC controller is topology aware and using openflow 1.3 for it&amp;rsquo;s communication. Unlike any other demo I&amp;rsquo;ve seen, NEC used CLI to make changes and displayed the updates in near realtime on the controller.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;ve got a tap product aimed at security tap aggregators a la &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gigamon.com/&#34;&gt;gigamon&lt;/a&gt;, so they&amp;rsquo;re seeing the value of SDN and openflow from a security lens as well as a network operations perspective, a good play in my opinion. SDN and openflow in particular have a great deal to offer the security community (think of all of the wacky stuff your security team has asked for and then map that into an openflow network. You&amp;rsquo;ll probably hit 80% match). NEC has done some tight integration with &lt;a href=&#34;https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/windowsserver/dd448604.aspx&#34;&gt;microsoft hyper-v&lt;/a&gt; too, so environments leveraging hyper-v as a virtualization technology can drop this in to take advantage of the network programmability on top of their virtualization environment. This is something that I&amp;rsquo;d not seen before [although it may exist and I just don&amp;rsquo;t know it]. In addition, NEC has spun up an &amp;ldquo;app store&amp;rdquo; for SDN apps and allowed for some cross pollination, with a handful of caveats, with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opendaylight.org/&#34;&gt;opendaylight&lt;/a&gt; for testing. &lt;speculation&gt; There are a few things I find interesting about the NEC offering and about NEC in general. Being in a service provider environment off and on for most of my career, the fact that NEC is getting involved so heavily is intriguing. Unlike most of the other DC focused companies, NEC plays in the carrier market. While this particular briefing did not include any carrier updates, it would surprise me if this wasn&amp;rsquo;t being investigated behind some big doors. It makes sense to me and it would be a surprise if it did not occur to someone else. The SP market is fickle and slow to change, but ripe for fresh ideas. I see a lot of potential both there and in the DC / campus / enterprise. &lt;/speculation&gt;   &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/119508255&#34;&gt;Introduction to NEC Networking&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/sfoskett&#34;&gt;Stephen Foskett&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/119508725&#34;&gt;NEC ProgrammableFlow vCOps Solution&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/sfoskett&#34;&gt;Stephen Foskett&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/119510207&#34;&gt;ProgrammableFlow SCVMM Demo&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/sfoskett&#34;&gt;Stephen Foskett&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Field Day 9</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/network-field-day-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 15:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/network-field-day-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ll have the opportunity to participate in another &lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/event/nfd9/&#34;&gt;Network Field Day&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve been lucky enough to have the opportunity to attend&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2014/02/network-field-day-7/&#34; title=&#34;Network Field Day 7&#34;&gt; in the past&lt;/a&gt; and have done some &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2013/03/network-field-day-5/&#34; title=&#34;Network Field Day 5 – Participate Remotely&#34;&gt;remote participation&lt;/a&gt; when possible, but like some of the other rare &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2012/11/scinet-a-privileged-few/&#34; title=&#34;SCinet, a privileged few&#34;&gt;opportunities&lt;/a&gt; I have had in my career, NFD is fairly unique in that it is constantly evolving in both the information provided and the individuals involved. As the saying goes, variety is the spice of life. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly excited about the presentations and have been looking forward to talking to a few of the participant companies for a while. There is a tight line up for NFD9, but I am very intrigued as I am either unfamiliar or have been looking for more information about several of them for quite some time now. &lt;a href=&#34;http://netbeez.net/&#34;&gt;NetBeez&lt;/a&gt; is  an interesting one, they provide a service not unlike a project I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with for years called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.perfsonar.net/&#34;&gt;perfSonar&lt;/a&gt;. The data that these kind of projects provide is absolutely invaluable, so I&amp;rsquo;m very interested in NetBeez and how they&amp;rsquo;re accomplishing their tasks and presenting their data. I met with and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2014/04/blending-the-network-pluribus-serverswitch/&#34;&gt;wrote about&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pluribusnetworks.com/&#34;&gt;Pluribus Networks&lt;/a&gt; at (and around the time of) &lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/event/nfd7/&#34;&gt;NFD7&lt;/a&gt;. I was impressed then and I&amp;rsquo;m impressed now. I see a great value in what they&amp;rsquo;re doing for so many practical applications and am very anxious to see what they&amp;rsquo;ve added, changed or tweaked since our last meeting roughly a year ago. &lt;a href=&#34;http://cumulusnetworks.com/&#34;&gt;Cumulus networks&lt;/a&gt; is another one I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to get lab time with since they came out. I am looking forward to having them in a room, they&amp;rsquo;re doing something to networking that, like Pluribus, is pretty unique and arguably game changing. At then end of the day, though, the best part of this is not that there are a few interesting topics, it is the fact that all of the topics and players are unique, top shelf and potentially game changing. It&amp;rsquo;s essentially an all star lineup (again) with the likes of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brocade.com&#34;&gt;Brocade&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.solarwinds.com/&#34;&gt;Solarwinds&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nec.com&#34;&gt;NEC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.velocloud.com/&#34;&gt;VeloCloud&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cloudgenix.com/&#34;&gt;Cloudgenix&lt;/a&gt;. This entire line up is right up my alley, as a large number of them are WAN or SDN oriented, which is where I spend the majority of my normal working days. In addition to all of that, I&amp;rsquo;ll finally get to meet &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/networkingnerd&#34;&gt;NetworkingNerd&lt;/a&gt; in real life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BigSwitch Labs for SDN learning: a sneak peek!</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/bigswitch-labs-for-sdn-learning-a-sneak-peek/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 10:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/bigswitch-labs-for-sdn-learning-a-sneak-peek/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently granted access to the beta &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bigswitch.com/&#34;&gt;BigSwitch Networks&lt;/a&gt; lab site, a purpose built classroom in the cloud focused on teaching the BigSwitch SDN environment.  I had seen some of the BSN offerings in the past and always held them in high regard, but I was thoroughly impressed with both the completeness of the lab and how polished the controller environment was.&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Screenshot-2014-09-12-10.28.50.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot 2014-09-12 10.28.50&#34; /&gt; At the time of this writing, the lab consists of 3 modules: Building cloud fabric, monitoring fabric and dynamic provisioning of monitoring fabric.  Since there is quite a lot going on with this cloud based SDN classroom, for the scope of this post I&amp;rsquo;ll concentrate on the first, building cloud fabric.  I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of the CLI*, and one thing that jumped right out to me was that they provide the GUI and the CLI, and that the CLI is familiar to anyone that has worked on an IOS device.  The lab is useful, even for someone that has done some SDN, both on production or in a lab, in that it presents the fundamentals in a way that both demonstrates the purpose and function and lays out the technology and product. From the technology presentation standpoint, the BigSwitch offering is quite impressive. The reality of it is that, in my experience, GUIs don&amp;rsquo;t always have the most intuitive or complete implementations and they&amp;rsquo;re hard to automate.  Now, from what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen to far the bigswitch offing is the exception to that rule.  The setup is very functional and goes through a range of great material. for comparison, below is the tenants display from the web interface: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Screenshot-2014-09-12-10.47.37.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Screenshot-2014-09-12-10.47.37.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot 2014-09-12 10.47.37&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;   and the corresponding show command: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Screenshot-2014-09-12-10.33.49.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Screenshot-2014-09-12-10.33.49.png&#34; alt=&#34;show tenant&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Nevertheless, part of my usual workflow is to use one to define the other when I can.  What I mean by that is that if I don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly how to accomplish my goal in the GUI, I switch to the CLI and see what I can do from there, returning to the GUI to see what has changed and then reverse engineer it from that perspective.  The opposite is also true, I have used the CLI to define the GUI &lt;em&gt;:cough:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.juniper.net/us/en/products-services/security/netscreen/&#34;&gt;netscreen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;:cough:&lt;/em&gt;. The important thing to note here, though, is that the tools all work as if it is a real environment, because it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a real environment. The god among men here, really, is the &lt;em&gt;debug rest&lt;/em&gt; command.  This command, when issued in the CLI (displayed below) allows the commands sent to the terminal to automatically pop up with the rest interface commands necessary to utilize them.  Wrap your head around that one for a minute.  Are you thinking automation?  Me too; seeing that made me want to go write code, and I am a horrible developer. &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Screenshot-2014-09-12-10.50.19.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot 2014-09-12 10.50.19&#34; /&gt; In the time I&amp;rsquo;ve spent within this system I have been thoroughly impressed with how well it functioned.  I had no issues whatsoever with how the training presented the material, executed the commands or displayed the responses.  My only suggestion would be to add a configuration guide for the CLI =) Below is a quick youtube video of some of the functions.    * Yes, I know SDN is supposed to &amp;ldquo;kill the CLI&amp;rdquo;.  I don&amp;rsquo;t by the sensationalism for the short to medium term.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tail-F NCS: upsetting network management...in a good way.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/tail-f-ncs-upsetting-network-management-in-a-good-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 04:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/tail-f-ncs-upsetting-network-management-in-a-good-way/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Hopefully there are some things here that will make you really upset in a very good way”&lt;/em&gt; is how &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/cmoberg&#34;&gt;Carl Moberg&lt;/a&gt; of Swedish based company &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tail-f.com/&#34;&gt;tail-f&lt;/a&gt; opened up to the crowd at &lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/event/nfd7/&#34;&gt;Networking Field Day 7&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/appearance/tail-f-systems-presents-at-networking-field-day-7/&#34;&gt;Feb 19, 2014&lt;/a&gt;.  Tail-f is a sleeper, I had actually never heard of them before NFD7, but they&amp;rsquo;ve got a very unique product in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tail-f.com/network-control-system/&#34;&gt;NCS&lt;/a&gt; and in my opinion it can change the way existing &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; future networks are managed.  Right now.  It&amp;rsquo;s not a platform that is green, unpolished or unfinished.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tail-f.com/network-control-system/&#34;&gt;NCS&lt;/a&gt; is in the ring and it brought its A-game.   Their site describes it better than I ever could: _&amp;ldquo;Tail-f Network Control System, or NCS, enables network operators to manage all of their services and network devices with a single tool.&amp;ldquo; _A bold statement, and I tend to be pretty skeptical of such statements. However, I was really intrigued by the NCS platform and as I discovered, it is not hype. Watching the demo of this got my brain racing, it was exciting to think about all of the things it could simplify; I was excited about networking.  So many things In fact, I&amp;rsquo;m really just going to scratch the surface of what this software toolkit can tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;any-network-of-of-ambitious-size-that-needs-to-get-people-out-of-the-loop&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Any network of of ambitious size that needs to get people out of the loop”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CTO says that NCS is for &amp;ldquo;_Any network of of ambitious size that needs to get people out of the loop_”, and I tend to agree, which is what makes this so powerful. In a world of openflow this and sdn that, most of which is still under heavy development, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but think of NCS as a &amp;ldquo;rosetta stone&amp;rdquo; of network management tools. It’s a controller, but in a different way. Its not openflow, but it knows openflow, so it is looking forward, but it also supports everything that is already there, an absolute necessity for 95% of networks that are not greenfield. From the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tail-f.com/network-control-system/#which-types-of&#34;&gt;NCS FAQ&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rose-lg-http-www-forwardingplane-net-wp-content-uploads-2014-02-rose-lg-jpg-http-www-forwardingplane-net-wp-content-uploads-2014-02-rose-lg-jpg-any-device-that-can-be-remotely-configured-can-be-managed-by-ncs-this-includes-routers-switches-load-balancers-firewalls-web-servers-and-a-whole-host-of-other-devices-both-virtual-and-physical-since-it-is-not-limited-to-one-type-of-device-or-particular-vendor-ncs-allows-for-management-of-the-entire-network-from-a-single-pane-of-glass&#34;&gt;_&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/rose_lg.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/rose_lg.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;rose_lg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ldquo;Any device that can be remotely configured can be managed by NCS. This includes, routers, switches, load-balancers, firewalls, web servers and a whole host of other devices (both virtual and physical). Since it is not limited to one type of device or particular vendor, NCS allows for management of the entire network from a single pane of glass.&amp;rdquo;_&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets face it, network management is not exactly easy to do in a sane and robust way, there are always quirks, one-offs and proprietary goo. That&amp;rsquo;s probably never going to change.  From the open source to the commercial, I&amp;rsquo;ve used, evaluated or extended a wide swath of them in my time in the industry, and this one really shocked me in what it was able to do in such a demonstrably elegant way, which we all know is not an easy task since we all have odd, uncommon or sometimes unreasonable requirements. A few things are really compelling about NCS.  First, it&amp;rsquo;s all &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/YANG&#34;&gt;YANG&lt;/a&gt;, meaning it is an established standard for doing exactly this and it can be referenced by any number of protocols for obtaining or setting the desired data or parameters.  This also means that it can very quickly and easily be extended to support new products, software loads, communications mechanisms and features. Tail-F changed the way I was thinking about network management.  They&amp;rsquo;ve taken the religion out of equipment vendors, because you can choose how to interact with them.  They allow for management of a myriad of platforms from an operator-chosen, familiar CLI.  Have guys that like JunOS?  Great, no problem.  Team members that prefer IOS?  No worries.  They can manage the Alcatel-Lucent, Brocade, Extreme Networks or one of the many other CLI variants from their choice of IOS or JunOS-like command sets.   No longer is it important to understand a particular CLI.  I wish I could have had access to this product 5 years ago when, at a previous job, we introduced JunOS to a team that had been working on IOS and Foundry for the majority of their careers.  It would have solved so many issues and driven the learning curve to nil. The CLI translator is really just the icing.  The configuration validation is immensely powerful and I could easily see it preventing many typos and misconfigurations (you know you&amp;rsquo;ve done it, we all have).  It can also provide compliance reporting, service management and configuration reconciliation, all of which are generally in-house written tools or manually accmplished tasks in my experience. Standardize and deploy ACLs across a range of platforms in geographically diverse areas, provision BGP policy on huge numbers of peers very quickly, reconcile MTUs on interfaces of devices that have been neglected, &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/Neutron/ML2/Tail-f-NCS-neutron-ml2-driver&#34;&gt;interface with OpenStack Neutron&lt;/a&gt;.  The use cases are pretty open ended, really. Anything that needs to be done at scale can be, and it can be error checked in the process. Don&amp;rsquo;t take my word for it, I&amp;rsquo;m clearly excited about it and can&amp;rsquo;t wait to get my hands on it.  Watch the NCS demo: Tail-f Systems NCS Demo at Networking Field Day 7   All of the videos can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/appearance/tail-f-systems-presents-at-networking-field-day-7/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Rosetta Stone images courtesy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ancientegypt.co.uk/writing/rosetta.html&#34;&gt;http://www.ancientegypt.co.uk/writing/rosetta.html&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://taboodada.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;http://taboodada.wordpress.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CentOS KVM Install - Quick Start to a VM</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/centos-kvm-install-quick-start-to-a-vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 01:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/centos-kvm-install-quick-start-to-a-vm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a network engineer by profession, but with the proliferation of SDN and OpenFlow, I have had to spend a lot of time re-learning a lot of system admin skills that I&amp;rsquo;d shelved years ago.  Now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been a virtualization user forever. From &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com&#34;&gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt; (Fusion, ESX), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.virtualbox.org&#34;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt;, to &lt;a href=&#34;www.parallels.com&#34;&gt;Parallels&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ve used them at least in testing if not in production environments.  I&amp;rsquo;d not really spent any mentionable amount of time with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xen.org&#34;&gt;XEN&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.qemu.org&#34;&gt;qEMU&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;www.linux-kvm.org&#34;&gt;KVM&lt;/a&gt;, but some projects I was working on suggested it for the virtualization mechanism, so I figured I&amp;rsquo;d try to pick it up.  I think the hosting provider  of this blog is using it to provide the VPS that this site runs on, so it is clearly production quality.  In looking around for a straightforward how-to, a few things became obvious pretty quickly: KVM is very robust. KVM and qEMU have got a lot of documentation, but not all of it is straightforward. They have a lot of pieces needed to make it work efficiently. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a plug and run experience, by any means.  I wanted a headless, remotely manageable system that ran on a bare minimum install (i.e. no GUI).  After a late evening of hacking at it,  here is what I finally had to do to get it running and build a functional VM on a fresh install of CentOS 6.3. Install all the dependancies.  And there were many.  Coming from using the VirtualBox CLI, little things that I expected didn&amp;rsquo;t work if I didn&amp;rsquo;t have this or that installed.```
yum install -y qemu-kvm.x86_64 qemu-kvm-tools.x86_64 &lt;br /&gt;
kvm libvirt bridge-utils tunctl python-virtinst.noarch avahi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Restart the deamons```&#34; data-lang=&#34;Restart the deamons```&#34;&gt;/etc/init.d/messagebus restart
/etc/init.d/avahi-daemon restart
/etc/init.d/libvirtd restart&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make the new daemons start at boot:```
/sbin/chkconfig messagebus on
/sbin/chkconfig avahi-daemon on&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
I want to bridge rather than NAT.  My VMs need to have a public (or same LAN segment) address as the rest of the hosts for external management and availability of inbound services.  For this, we need to adjust the interfaces.  I want to run the bridge on a second interface and keep the host system management on a dedicated interface.

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;vi /etc/sysconfig/network-scripts/ifcfg-eth1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Your file should look something like this when done:```&#34; data-lang=&#34;Your file should look something like this when done:```&#34;&gt;DEVICE=&amp;#34;eth1&amp;#34;
HWADDR=&amp;#34;c0:ff:ee:c0:ff:ee&amp;#34; # (leave this as your MAC address)
NM\_CONTROLLED=&amp;#34;yes&amp;#34;
 BRIDGE=br0
 ONBOOT=&amp;#34;yes&amp;#34;
UUID=&amp;#34;a9c26927-7650-42e9-a86a-1ae1227eac4b&amp;#34; #leave this as your UUID)
``````
vi /etc/sysconfig/network-scripts/ifcfg-br0&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your file should look something like this when done:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;DEVICE=&amp;quot;br0&amp;quot;
TYPE=&amp;quot;Bridge&amp;quot;
BOOTPROTO=&amp;quot;static&amp;quot;
IPADDR=&amp;quot;10.10.10.50&amp;quot; # Use your own IP address
NETMASK=&amp;quot;255.255.255.128&amp;quot;
GATEWAY=&amp;quot;10.10.10.1&amp;quot;  # Provide your gateway
IPV6INIT=&amp;quot;yes&amp;quot;
IPV6\_AUTOCONF=&amp;quot;yes&amp;quot;
NM\_CONTROLLED=&amp;quot;yes&amp;quot;
ONBOOT=&amp;quot;yes&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Restart the network to make it active.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;service network restart
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re going to use virt tools and virsh to manipulate the guests.  I tried it a few other ways and this seems far more supportable.  I wanted to install a CentOS 6.3 guest, I grabbed the install media from a &lt;a href=&#34;http://cosmos.cites.illinois.edu/pub/centos/6.3/isos/x86_64/&#34;&gt;local mirror&lt;/a&gt;.  I have a volume mounted as /services that I keep stuff in.```
mkdir /services/vm/template-host
cd /services/vm/template-host
wget &lt;a href=&#34;http://cosmos.cites.illinois.edu/pub/centos/6.3/isos/x86_64/CentOS-6.3-x86_64-bin-DVD1.iso&#34;&gt;http://cosmos.cites.illinois.edu/pub/centos/6.3/isos/x86_64/CentOS-6.3-x86_64-bin-DVD1.iso&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Now use the virt-install command to boot the system with the following parameters: 2G of RAM 50G disk named disk.img Console redirected to a VNC instance on port 5901 Network interface attached to br0 4 CPUs CDROM points to install image```&#34; data-lang=&#34;Now use the virt-install command to boot the system with the following parameters: 2G of RAM 50G disk named disk.img Console redirected to a VNC instance on port 5901 Network interface attached to br0 4 CPUs CDROM points to install image```&#34;&gt;virt-install --name template-host --ram 2048 --disk /home/vm/template-host/disk.img,size=50 \\
--graphics vnc,port=5901 --network bridge=br0 --vcpus=4 --os-type=linux \\
--cdrom=/home/vm/Install\_Media/CentOS-6.3-x86\_64-bin-DVD1.iso&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, to connect to the console, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to tunnel VNC over ssh.  This can be adjusted, but that&amp;rsquo;s outside of the scope of this. I like to redirect real port numbers for my own sanity.```
ssh -N -p 22 -c 3des buraglio@vmhost -L 5901/localhost/5901&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-The above command will redirect localhost port 5901 to port 5901 on the host vmhost Connect to the VNC server:&#34; data-lang=&#34;The above command will redirect localhost port 5901 to port 5901 on the host vmhost Connect to the VNC server:&#34;&gt;[![Screen Shot 2013-03-01 at 2.00.37 PM](http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-01-at-2.00.37-PM.png)](http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-01-at-2.00.37-PM.png)

Once connected you should drop right into the console of the KVM instance. Install as a normal system at that point.

Once installed It&amp;#39;ll appear as a normal host console.

[![Screen Shot 2013-03-01 at 2.01.21 PM](http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-01-at-2.01.21-PM.png)](http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-01-at-2.01.21-PM.png)

I found virsh to be the most useful for manipulating the virtual machine.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[root@behemoth Install_Media]# virsh list
Id            Name                                      State&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9              template-host                         running
```Helpful commands I found after 30 minutes of poking around and playing with virsh: virsh list &amp;ndash;show the list of virtual machines virsh destroy &lt;vm name&gt; &amp;ndash;hard shut down a host (I believe) virsh undefine &lt;vm name&gt; &amp;ndash;remove the VM from registration &amp;ndash;this one was hard for me to find.   &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/unix/kvm-virsh-command-referenc/&#34; title=&#34;KVM virsh command reference&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is a complete list of the commands.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watch out, Gigamon (and others), Arista is bringing their A game</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/watch-out-gigamon-and-others-arista-is-bringing-their-a-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 03:11:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/watch-out-gigamon-and-others-arista-is-bringing-their-a-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of the model &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aristanetworks.com&#34;&gt;Arista Networks&lt;/a&gt; is using to make gear and provide innovative services and products. In my opinion, they&amp;rsquo;re changing the landscape of campus and data center networking gear. I&amp;rsquo;m always a fan of the little guy trying to change the world and this falls under that category. For those that don&amp;rsquo;t know, Arista Networks is a &amp;ldquo;hardware&amp;rdquo; networking company that is using merchant silicon wrapped in their custom linux based operating system (which is very much like IOS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/ARISTA-TAP.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/ARISTA-TAP-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ARISTA-TAP&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This model does a few things. It takes the time it would normally take a vendor to engineer and spin an ASIC, typically 1-3 years) and completely removes it. Instead, they rely on silicon manufacturers like Intel and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fulcrummicro.com&#34;&gt;Fulcrum&lt;/a&gt; for their already engineered and tested chips. Arista is generally touted as an extremely low latency box and has been widely deployed in the financial industry because of this. However, they&amp;rsquo;re not a one trick pony, not by any means. Their open architecture and OS allows for &lt;strong&gt;heavy&lt;/strong&gt; customization. In fact, unlike most others, it&amp;rsquo;s encouraged. Arista has put together an &lt;a href=&#34;https://eos.aristanetworks.com/home.php&#34;&gt;ecosystem for extending and expanding&lt;/a&gt; their &lt;a href=&#34;https://eos.aristanetworks.com/2011/03/eos-so-what-is-it/&#34;&gt;EOS&lt;/a&gt; networking operating system. Want something added to the CLI? Easy, it&amp;rsquo;s all python and can be changed on-box and submitted back to the community. They also have a very, very slick internal mechanism called the sysdb, but that&amp;rsquo;s another blog post altogether.   None of this is really new. Folks have been using merchant silicon forever. What is new and refreshing is the open nature of it. Additionally, the exclusive use of merchant silicon is something [I believe] is now in this class of hardware. With the open nature of this platform, it also lends itself well to the OpenFlow movement in that it&amp;rsquo;s essentially a linux box on well documented hardware of which the vendor is encouraging modification. In addition, it is a well tested data center product. I&amp;rsquo;m calling it now, this platform is going to go places in it&amp;rsquo;s market. For the newest addition to the capabilities portfolio, this is where it really gets interesting. As of 2/13/2013 Arista has added some very &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aristanetworks.com/en/news/pressrelease/532-pr-20130212-01&#34;&gt;compelling tap aggregation options&lt;/a&gt;. What this means, is that you can now aggregate Nx1 or 10G at 40G, then symmetrically hash that across another 10G array to an IDS cluster. Why is this important? Monitoring fat links. Have some 100G? Good luck finding a security mechanism to watch that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/ARISTA-TAP.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/ARISTA-TAP.png&#34; alt=&#34;ARISTA TAP&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until now the only options for this are players like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gigamon.com&#34;&gt;Gigamon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cpacket.com&#34;&gt;cPacket&lt;/a&gt; and maybe &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mrv.com&#34;&gt;MRV&lt;/a&gt;. All are very expensive and one-off solutions. Arista offers a standard ethernet switch that can be managed by an existing networking team, integrated into existing network tools and maintained like any other router or switch. OpEx is a wash. Capital expenditure is standard [probably cheaper] than a normal Layer2 switch. It looks JUST like IOS, so the old networking guy that hates change will only complain a little that it&amp;rsquo;s not a blue box with a bridge on it. This may seem like a small deal, but the implications for passive security monitoring are huge. This feature alone will have a trickle down effect over the next few years since it&amp;rsquo;s something that is only recently being exercised in enterprise worlds. I suspect this will also have a very large impact to gigamon, who is really the current industry leader in this corner of the market, but is priced well beyond what many can afford. Arista can now do the symmetric hashing on layer2, layer3 or layer4 parameters. ACL support is also coming, although I&amp;rsquo;ve not seen it work like I have the hashing.   Oh, you want to know how to do it? =) It currently doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist in the CLI, but here is basically how it&amp;rsquo;s done. Thanks to an awesome Arista rep, the heavy lifting of parsing through the Acons interface is all condensed to a simple script. from the CLI: Log in and enable.```
7150-Source#bash
Arista Networks EOS shell
[arista@7150-Source ~]$ cd /mnt/flash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[arista@7150-Source ~]$vi set_hash.sh
#!/bin/ti
rm /mnt/flash/set_hash_log.txt
cat &amp;lt;&amp;lt; EOF | Acons FocalPointV2 &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /mnt/flash/set_hash_log.txt 2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1
from FmApi import *
fmDbgWriteRegisterField(0,0,0,0,&amp;ldquo;FM6000_HASH_LAYER3_PROFILE&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;SymmetrizeL3&amp;rdquo;,1)
fmDbgWriteRegisterField(0,0,0,0,&amp;ldquo;FM6000_HASH_LAYER3_PROFILE&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;SymmetrizeL4&amp;rdquo;,1)
fmDbgWriteRegisterField(0,0,0,0,&amp;ldquo;FM6000_HASH_LAYER2_KEY_PROFILE&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;SymmetrizeMAC&amp;rdquo;,1)
EOF
exit 0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Done. This, of course, doesn&#39;t include any of the port channel and monitor interface configuration, but if you&#39;re this deep, you probably know how to do that already. If you&#39;d like to dump this to a log, add the following lines to the end of the script before the &#34;EOF&#34;```&#34; data-lang=&#34;Done. This, of course, doesn&#39;t include any of the port channel and monitor interface configuration, but if you&#39;re this deep, you probably know how to do that already. If you&#39;d like to dump this to a log, add the following lines to the end of the script before the &#34;EOF&#34;```&#34;&gt;fmDbgDumpRegisterV2(0,0,0,&amp;#34;FM6000\_HASH\_LAYER2\_KEY\_PROFILE&amp;#34;)
fmDbgDumpRegisterV2(0,0,0,&amp;#34;FM6000\_HASH\_LAYER3\_PROFILE&amp;#34;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*As the CLI bits become available in EOS 4.12, this post will be amended to the more supportable way of managing this awesome new feature.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where will Cisco go from here?</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/where-will-cisco-go-from-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 00:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/where-will-cisco-go-from-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.fosketts.net/about/stephen-foskett/&#34;&gt;Stephen Foskett&lt;/a&gt;s post &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.fosketts.net/2013/01/02/cisco-recover-consumer-strategy-blunder/&#34;&gt;How Will Cisco Recover From The Consumer Strategy Blunder?&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;, it got me thinking.  It&amp;rsquo;s a very different world than when Cisco got started all those years ago.  I don&amp;rsquo;t have any brand loyalty to Cisco, I learned on cisco gear 14-15 years ago for the most part, but I try to keep the mentality of &amp;ldquo;the right tool for the job&amp;rdquo;, which means constantly surveying th emarket for new and interesting ways to do things.  In doing this, it&amp;rsquo;s really opened my eyes over the last 10 years.  There are so many more ways to do what needs to be done in networking day to day that are cheaper, supportable and in some cases easier, than going with the big Cisco.  that&amp;rsquo;s not saying that their gear isn&amp;rsquo;t fantastic.  I do love it, it works well for the most part and is very sell supported and documented.   &lt;img src=&#34;http://lcolumbus.files.wordpress.com/2010/10/ciscosystems.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt; I mostly agree with his sentiments.  I think Cisco needs to re-evaluate all of their offerings.  Re-focusing on what worked before is one strategy, but it may not be the best one. They&amp;rsquo;ve gone into the data center in the last 10 years with new products, their aquisition of topspin gave them IB when it was hot.  I&amp;rsquo;ve personally not seen much of anything from them with Infiniband in recent memory and I believe they killed off their IB switches. They&amp;rsquo;ve done deals and made purpose built servers in the past (think call manager and compaq) that were less than stellar.  Storage is key, but he&amp;rsquo;s right, they&amp;rsquo;d have to buy some key or upstart gold mine players since it&amp;rsquo;s a total shift in technology.  Convergence is a nice idea.  I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen it really done well but I&amp;rsquo;d love to, so if they can pull it off that&amp;rsquo;d be a great feather in their cap.  Brocade is very well positioned to master convergence and steal that away. The Nexus is a fine box, but it&amp;rsquo;s got a lot of competition from the likes of Brocade, Arista, Extreme and even Juniper for the DC. In the service provider space they&amp;rsquo;ve been getting inched out by Juniper for a very long time and technically speaking Alcatel Lucent has a very good platform in that area as well. Their large / carrier security platforms have a lot of arguably better offerings from the likes of Juniper, Fortinet and Palo Alto. Their core routers have been getting inched out by Brocade, Extreme, Juniper and even Alcatel Lucent. And what about price? Is their venerable IOS enough to warrant the double and triple price tags and high cost of maintenance? In my small corner of the world it isn&amp;rsquo;t. Operationally it&amp;rsquo;s no harder or more cost for us to run a box that is IOS-like, or JunOS. From my admittedly skewed perspective their bread and butter is in the MPLS PE devices, smaller security appliances and possibly the ASR series. &amp;hellip;unless they can pull a Hail Mary SDN solution and corner in the already entrenched customers. It&amp;rsquo;s a very different world in networking today than when Cisco took the Lions share of the market. There is real competition. More competition. Cheaper competition with just an many features that is every bit as reliable. My opinion is that they need a complete rethink of their world, they have good, widely deployed products, leverage existing relationships and get some fresh ideas in.  Or buy someone with some.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing OwnCloud on CentOS</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/291/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2012 13:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/291/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;wget http://dl.fedoraproject.org/pub/epel/6/x86\_64/epel-release-6-8.noarch.rpm
wget http://rpms.famillecollet.com/enterprise/remi-release-6.rpm
yum -y install apache2 php5 php5-json php-xml php-mbstring php5-zip php5-gd
yum -y install php5-sqlite curl libcurl3 libcurl3-dev php5-curl php-pd
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;php5-sqlite isn&amp;rsquo;t available in the repos I use. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to find it elsewhere either. Per &lt;a href=&#34;http://php.net/manual/de/sqlite.installation.php&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt;, I have to install it by source.&lt;code&gt;
cd /etc/yum.repos.d/
wget http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/isv:ownCloud:community/CentOS\_CentOS-6/isv:ownCloud:community.repo
yum install owncloud
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Tech Predictions for 2013</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/random-tech-predictions-for-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 19:39:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/random-tech-predictions-for-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a love-hate feeling about &amp;ldquo;predictions&amp;rdquo; about the upcoming year, especially tech predictions.  I don&amp;rsquo;t like media sensationalism of any kind, and a lot of the tech predctions are just that, sensational, extreme talk to draw in readers or viewers.  I&amp;rsquo;m choosing to go down a more subtle path, these are things I&amp;rsquo;ve thought about lately but will likely forget in the upcoming year, unless they actually happen, in which case I&amp;rsquo;d likely do an &amp;ldquo;ah, I remember thinking that may happen&amp;rdquo; gesture.  Additionally, many of these things are well underway already, but I have a mind like a FIFO pipe, so I&amp;rsquo;m gonna write them down here to remember to go back and look at them in a few months.  They&amp;rsquo;re sort of a mixed bag of stuff, in no particular order. Lets call these, &amp;ldquo;plausible but not necessarily inevitable; possibly already happening&amp;rdquo;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/crystal-ball.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/crystal-ball.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;crystal-ball&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 1. Google buys or invests in a mobile carrier.  I was thinking Sprint, but T-Mobile makes more sense because of their GSM network and more global compatibility.  Thins kind of thing has been proposed many times over the last few years and it still makes sense. 2.  Apple buys or invests in Twitter.  This makes a lot of sense to me and would solidify their place in the social networking arena. 3. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aristanetworks.com&#34;&gt;Arista Networks &lt;/a&gt; moves into a larger data center and cloud computing role.  I see big things for this company. they have a very solid pedigree, have an innovative business model and a &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; compelling product.   Which leads me to #4. 4. Talks of larger companies (Cisco, Juniper, Dell, Google) purchasing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aristanetworks.com&#34;&gt;Arista Networks&lt;/a&gt;.  This hapens to many of the very innnovative companies.  Remember &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Procket_Networks&#34;&gt;Procket&lt;/a&gt;?  Yeah, most folks don&amp;rsquo;t.  I had the same thoughts about them.  cisco purchased, absorbed and buried them.  I believe their routing pieces were shoved into the nexus. 5. SDN controllers become more mainstream.  BigSwitch stands more or less unchallenged in the commercial controller space and has done it right.  Seed the opensource community and make a commercial product for those that want it (i.e. businesses that need support, don&amp;rsquo;t want to deal with code).  It makes sense to me that this become a big market in the next few years, and next year will likely be the mad dash.  I expect to see SDN controllers from big names and hopefully some start ups. 6. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.plexxi.com&#34;&gt;Plexxi&lt;/a&gt; starts to become a more well known name.  They&amp;rsquo;ve got a really cool product and a unique and innovative feature set.  I also wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised if a big name tried to buy them. 7. More and more &amp;ldquo;Ethernet Fabric&amp;rdquo; products emerge.  This is the new marketing favorite son and there are &lt;a href=&#34;http://gnodal.com&#34;&gt;many&lt;/a&gt; new players here.  Sprinkle in SDN and &amp;ldquo;Cloud&amp;rdquo;, shake with &amp;ldquo;data center&amp;rdquo; and you&amp;rsquo;ve got a buzzword cocktail worthy of a king. 8. Productized optical (WDM) SDN starts to mature and become available. This is already happening in he background and on the periphery. 9. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crn.com/news/networking/240007827/microsoft-confirms-more-details-of-lync-skype-integration.htm&#34;&gt;Skype is integrated into MS Lync&lt;/a&gt;.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think this is really unexpected or a surprise at all since it&amp;rsquo;s been announced.  I think it&amp;rsquo;ll happen in 2013, though. 10.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openstack.org&#34;&gt;OpenStack&lt;/a&gt; starts taking a more publicized role in production cloud computing.  This is sort of inevitable and obvious, I think, and it&amp;rsquo;s already starting to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Tech Predictions for 2013</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/random-tech-predictions-for-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 19:39:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/random-tech-predictions-for-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a love-hate feeling about &amp;ldquo;predictions&amp;rdquo; about the upcoming year, especially tech predictions.  I don&amp;rsquo;t like media sensationalism of any kind, and a lot of the tech predctions are just that, sensational, extreme talk to draw in readers or viewers.  I&amp;rsquo;m choosing to go down a more subtle path, these are things I&amp;rsquo;ve thought about lately but will likely forget in the upcoming year, unless they actually happen, in which case I&amp;rsquo;d likely do an &amp;ldquo;ah, I remember thinking that may happen&amp;rdquo; gesture.  Additionally, many of these things are well underway already, but I have a mind like a FIFO pipe, so I&amp;rsquo;m gonna write them down here to remember to go back and look at them in a few months.  They&amp;rsquo;re sort of a mixed bag of stuff, in no particular order. Lets call these, &amp;ldquo;plausible but not necessarily inevitable; possibly already happening&amp;rdquo;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/crystal-ball.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/crystal-ball.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;crystal-ball&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 1. Google buys or invests in a mobile carrier.  I was thinking Sprint, but T-Mobile makes more sense because of their GSM network and more global compatibility.  Thins kind of thing has been proposed many times over the last few years and it still makes sense. 2.  Apple buys or invests in Twitter.  This makes a lot of sense to me and would solidify their place in the social networking arena. 3. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aristanetworks.com&#34;&gt;Arista Networks &lt;/a&gt; moves into a larger data center and cloud computing role.  I see big things for this company. they have a very solid pedigree, have an innovative business model and a &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; compelling product.   Which leads me to #4. 4. Talks of larger companies (Cisco, Juniper, Dell, Google) purchasing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aristanetworks.com&#34;&gt;Arista Networks&lt;/a&gt;.  This hapens to many of the very innnovative companies.  Remember &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Procket_Networks&#34;&gt;Procket&lt;/a&gt;?  Yeah, most folks don&amp;rsquo;t.  I had the same thoughts about them.  cisco purchased, absorbed and buried them.  I believe their routing pieces were shoved into the nexus. 5. SDN controllers become more mainstream.  BigSwitch stands more or less unchallenged in the commercial controller space and has done it right.  Seed the opensource community and make a commercial product for those that want it (i.e. businesses that need support, don&amp;rsquo;t want to deal with code).  It makes sense to me that this become a big market in the next few years, and next year will likely be the mad dash.  I expect to see SDN controllers from big names and hopefully some start ups. 6. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.plexxi.com&#34;&gt;Plexxi&lt;/a&gt; starts to become a more well known name.  They&amp;rsquo;ve got a really cool product and a unique and innovative feature set.  I also wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised if a big name tried to buy them. 7. More and more &amp;ldquo;Ethernet Fabric&amp;rdquo; products emerge.  This is the new marketing favorite son and there are &lt;a href=&#34;http://gnodal.com&#34;&gt;many&lt;/a&gt; new players here.  Sprinkle in SDN and &amp;ldquo;Cloud&amp;rdquo;, shake with &amp;ldquo;data center&amp;rdquo; and you&amp;rsquo;ve got a buzzword cocktail worthy of a king. 8. Productized optical (WDM) SDN starts to mature and become available. This is already happening in he background and on the periphery. 9. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crn.com/news/networking/240007827/microsoft-confirms-more-details-of-lync-skype-integration.htm&#34;&gt;Skype is integrated into MS Lync&lt;/a&gt;.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think this is really unexpected or a surprise at all since it&amp;rsquo;s been announced.  I think it&amp;rsquo;ll happen in 2013, though. 10.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openstack.org&#34;&gt;OpenStack&lt;/a&gt; starts taking a more publicized role in production cloud computing.  This is sort of inevitable and obvious, I think, and it&amp;rsquo;s already starting to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plexxi could be WDM for the rest of us.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/plexxi-could-be-wdm-for-the-rest-of-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 05:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/plexxi-could-be-wdm-for-the-rest-of-us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.plexxi.com&#34;&gt;Plexxi&lt;/a&gt; is an interesting product that has recently emerged in the data center space.  While data center, fabric and cloud are all the rage in the buzzword world of data networking, this one caught my attention because it was something unique that I&amp;rsquo;d not seen before.  Their TOR boxes have a few interesting additions to them, the first of which is a WDM port on the back. Now, I&amp;rsquo;m not really a stranger to the WDM world.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been helping maintain a DWDM network in one capacity or another for a little over a decade, but seeing this, by default, in a data center positioned switch?  Now that got my attention. For those that don&amp;rsquo;t know what that is, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wavelength-division_multiplexing&#34;&gt;Wave Division Multiplexing&lt;/a&gt; the ability to slice up light into what telco (and other networking folks) call waves. Each wave is a different &amp;ldquo;color&amp;rdquo; or wavelength.  Plexxi calls their flavor &amp;ldquo;Affinity Networking&amp;rdquo; and it allows for the ability to provision more bandwidth over a single pair of fiber, just like typical WDM. For example, say you have a pair of fiber from one data center to another, either in the same facility or across your city (distances up to 10K now, 70K on the roadmap).  You&amp;rsquo;d normally plug in a 1G or 10G (or 100G if you&amp;rsquo;re really, really well funded) and provision service over that pair of fiber, assuming it is in within distance and optical power spec of the other side.  You&amp;rsquo;re stuck with that interface speed, right?  Wrong. Enter WDM.   On WDM systems you have the ability to provision channels, sometimes in huge amounts, over the same pair.  I&amp;rsquo;ve seen multiple 100G waves, OC192 Waves, a plethora of 10G waves and a few 1G waves all working fine over the same pair of fiber, and where fiber is sparse or prohibitively expensive, this is a big deal. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/prism4c.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/prism4c.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;prism4c&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Plexxi &amp;rdquo;Affinity Networking&amp;rdquo; boasts the ability to do WDM right in the back of their 32 port 10G switches. Very slick.  But that&amp;rsquo;s not all.  Enter part 2.  They also boast software defined (but not OpenFlow) control over the product, enabling dynamic provisioning of  bandwidth, on demand.. They&amp;rsquo;ve purpose built their own proprietary and described as &amp;ldquo;extended&amp;rdquo; version of SDN, geared toward a bigger picture of their network equipment and what it can do.  Their  SDN is called called &amp;ldquo;Plexxi Control&amp;rdquo; and it ties all of their switches together, allowing for a flattening of the network.  I find this approach intriguing, I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of the fabric approach to layer 2 a la &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.juniper.net/us/en/products-services/switching/qfx-series/&#34;&gt;Juniper Qfabric&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2012/12/brocade-vdx-first-impressions/&#34;&gt;Brocade VDX&lt;/a&gt;, but the WDM port and the decoupled control together is unique &amp;hellip;.and enthralling. Now, I have not yet had my hands on these boxes, but I think that they will be a piece in what has become a rapidly changing landscape of data centers.  WDM has been around forever in the service provider wide area, but the ability to change bandwidth allocations using WDM on the fly in a commercially supportable commoditized box is game changing.  There have been several research projects in the past that have attempted to do this, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://dragon.maxgigapop.net/twiki/bin/view/DRAGON/WebHome&#34;&gt;DRAGON project&lt;/a&gt;, of which one of the sites I helped maintain was a member, attempted to do something like this using &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generalized_Multi-Protocol_Label_Switching&#34;&gt;GMPLS&lt;/a&gt;  on the WAN gear. Doing it in the data center?  That&amp;rsquo;s new. I look forward to seeing some of these boxes function up close and personal.  I&amp;rsquo;m especially interested in the longer distance pieces of these for remote data centers and DR locations. For a comprehensive write up, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://searchnetworking.techtarget.com/news/2240173858/Plexxi-SDN-includes-tiered-controller-data-center-based-WDM&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://searchnetworking.techtarget.com/contributor/Shamus-McGillicuddy&#34;&gt;Shamus McGillicuddy&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://searchnetworking.techtarget.com/news/2240173858/Plexxi-SDN-includes-tiered-controller-data-center-based-WDM&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brocade VDX First Impressions....</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/brocade-vdx-first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 17:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/brocade-vdx-first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had the opportinity to work with the much-anticipated &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brocade.com/launch/cloud-clarity/solutions-technology-innovation.html&#34;&gt;Brocade VDX &amp;ldquo;Ethernet Fabric&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; platform.  I do admit tha tI&amp;rsquo;m intrigued by this product.  I&amp;rsquo;d seen it work multiple times in demos and it worked so well and looked to easy that we actively tried to throw curve balls at the demo organizer to prove it wasn&amp;rsquo;t canned. &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.brocade.com/images/products/vdx-6720-dc-switches/VDX6720-24_front_large.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt; It succeeded. The hardware hashing across the VLAGs is very slick.  The VMware VSwitch integration worked well and was handy.  With the movement to virtualization, this is an important piece for most data center folks. That being said, some people have very specific data center requirements that aren&amp;rsquo;t really the same as an enterprise.  For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t firewall everything at the DC. That&amp;rsquo;s right. I said it.  Firewalls don&amp;rsquo;t solve all security problems.  Take that &amp;ldquo;defense in depth&amp;rdquo;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A potential need to do non-standard or experimental protocols.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of line rate 10G internally and to the rest of network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration with legacy, existing and or in-house written tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Need for GSLB/SLB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self Healing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ease of fabric upgrade (software upgrade doesn&amp;rsquo;t cause fabric isolation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ease of fabric upgrade (increase LAG numbers and capacity easily)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-Homed hosts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IPv4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IPv6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IPv4 Multicast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Future SDN support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NAT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Address space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All at the same time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I digress.  We can get into the Data Center design details later.  Below would be a theoretical data center reference design for a fabric deployment.  Please bear in mind that I mostly like to focus on the WAN and SP bits, so take my data center speculations and musings with a grain of salt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Flexible-DC.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Flexible-DC.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Flexible DC&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;   The Brocade VDX does most of what can be expected of a layer 2 fabric.  It really is the &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; part of a DC design.  If you can avoid STP, I would heavily recommend it.  I have an unnatural dislike for spanning tree. The unexpected things I ran into with my very brief hands-on with the VDX were just that, unexpected.  I could reliably crash ssh on the boxes by sending a public key at login, which is default behavior for a normal ssh client.  This was very annoying and implied that they don&amp;rsquo;t yet support ssh keys for authentication.  One can work around it by doing &lt;em&gt;ssh -o PubkeyAuthentication=no -l &lt;name&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and worked with the newest version of putty, which I don&amp;rsquo;t use.  The version of OpenSSH on my Mac running 10.8.2 had an issue with it, as did the linux jumphost I used. There is no way, in current software to manage this centrally like you can with qfabric.  Each device is an individual switch.  I suspect this will change since it&amp;rsquo;s pretty inconvenient and I know many folks have asked for it.  This was my biggest issue with it. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t run spanning tree.  It has a loop detection mechanism, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t spanning tree.  It&amp;rsquo;s not meant to have anything but end hosts or other VDX plugged into it from what I gather, other than uplinks. Unknown SDN roadmap.  Currently it&amp;rsquo;s unsupported but with the level of commitment that Brocade has given to SDN so far, I&amp;rsquo;m cautiously optimistic. Untested Layer 3 capabilities.  It&amp;rsquo;s a new platform and they&amp;rsquo;ve just added layer3 into it.  I have no intention of testing the layer3 capabilities since I doubt that I&amp;rsquo;d want to route on them. Unknown IPv6 RA guard status.  Tis is important and I&amp;rsquo;m fairly certain they&amp;rsquo;ll add it, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t in the code load that we had at SC12, at least that I could find. It is easily integrated into RANCID. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2012/11/vdxrancid-contrib-scripts/&#34;&gt;I hacked together a script to do this&lt;/a&gt; in about 10 minutes and I&amp;rsquo;m an awful programmer. It looks EXACTLY like IOS so folks familiar with Ciscos venerable IOS command line will have absolutely no issue picking this right up. Some of the things I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to do during this first run were to put a packet cannon like an IXIA on it and jam traffic up to, and ideally beyond the limits and see how it reacts and to point existing SNMP based tools at it (other than basic up/down status).  I&amp;rsquo;d also like to push the limits of the interconnect between geographic locations and see the latency and efficiency of the VLAG ports when moving traffic and virtual machines.  With luck these will happen at some point soon. Bear in mind that this is a relatively new product.  I would probably place the best competitor for this as the Juniper Qfabric or Microfabric, bith of which are a larger scale product and suffer from some of the same issues.  I&amp;rsquo;m excited to see more about it, it did its job pretty well.  Juniper and cisco take notice, these bits are important and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.plexxi.com&#34;&gt;more than just brocade are working on it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brocade VDX First Impressions....</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/brocade-vdx-first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 17:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/brocade-vdx-first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had the opportinity to work with the much-anticipated &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brocade.com/launch/cloud-clarity/solutions-technology-innovation.html&#34;&gt;Brocade VDX &amp;ldquo;Ethernet Fabric&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; platform.  I do admit tha tI&amp;rsquo;m intrigued by this product.  I&amp;rsquo;d seen it work multiple times in demos and it worked so well and looked to easy that we actively tried to throw curve balls at the demo organizer to prove it wasn&amp;rsquo;t canned. &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.brocade.com/images/products/vdx-6720-dc-switches/VDX6720-24_front_large.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt; It succeeded. The hardware hashing across the VLAGs is very slick.  The VMware VSwitch integration worked well and was handy.  With the movement to virtualization, this is an important piece for most data center folks. That being said, some people have very specific data center requirements that aren&amp;rsquo;t really the same as an enterprise.  For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t firewall everything at the DC. That&amp;rsquo;s right. I said it.  Firewalls don&amp;rsquo;t solve all security problems.  Take that &amp;ldquo;defense in depth&amp;rdquo;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A potential need to do non-standard or experimental protocols.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of line rate 10G internally and to the rest of network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration with legacy, existing and or in-house written tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Need for GSLB/SLB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self Healing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ease of fabric upgrade (software upgrade doesn&amp;rsquo;t cause fabric isolation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ease of fabric upgrade (increase LAG numbers and capacity easily)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-Homed hosts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IPv4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IPv6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IPv4 Multicast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Future SDN support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NAT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Address space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All at the same time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I digress.  We can get into the Data Center design details later.  Below would be a theoretical data center reference design for a fabric deployment.  Please bear in mind that I mostly like to focus on the WAN and SP bits, so take my data center speculations and musings with a grain of salt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Flexible-DC.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Flexible-DC.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Flexible DC&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;   The Brocade VDX does most of what can be expected of a layer 2 fabric.  It really is the &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; part of a DC design.  If you can avoid STP, I would heavily recommend it.  I have an unnatural dislike for spanning tree. The unexpected things I ran into with my very brief hands-on with the VDX were just that, unexpected.  I could reliably crash ssh on the boxes by sending a public key at login, which is default behavior for a normal ssh client.  This was very annoying and implied that they don&amp;rsquo;t yet support ssh keys for authentication.  One can work around it by doing &lt;em&gt;ssh -o PubkeyAuthentication=no -l &lt;name&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and worked with the newest version of putty, which I don&amp;rsquo;t use.  The version of OpenSSH on my Mac running 10.8.2 had an issue with it, as did the linux jumphost I used. There is no way, in current software to manage this centrally like you can with qfabric.  Each device is an individual switch.  I suspect this will change since it&amp;rsquo;s pretty inconvenient and I know many folks have asked for it.  This was my biggest issue with it. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t run spanning tree.  It has a loop detection mechanism, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t spanning tree.  It&amp;rsquo;s not meant to have anything but end hosts or other VDX plugged into it from what I gather, other than uplinks. Unknown SDN roadmap.  Currently it&amp;rsquo;s unsupported but with the level of commitment that Brocade has given to SDN so far, I&amp;rsquo;m cautiously optimistic. Untested Layer 3 capabilities.  It&amp;rsquo;s a new platform and they&amp;rsquo;ve just added layer3 into it.  I have no intention of testing the layer3 capabilities since I doubt that I&amp;rsquo;d want to route on them. Unknown IPv6 RA guard status.  Tis is important and I&amp;rsquo;m fairly certain they&amp;rsquo;ll add it, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t in the code load that we had at SC12, at least that I could find. It is easily integrated into RANCID. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2012/11/vdxrancid-contrib-scripts/&#34;&gt;I hacked together a script to do this&lt;/a&gt; in about 10 minutes and I&amp;rsquo;m an awful programmer. It looks EXACTLY like IOS so folks familiar with Ciscos venerable IOS command line will have absolutely no issue picking this right up. Some of the things I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to do during this first run were to put a packet cannon like an IXIA on it and jam traffic up to, and ideally beyond the limits and see how it reacts and to point existing SNMP based tools at it (other than basic up/down status).  I&amp;rsquo;d also like to push the limits of the interconnect between geographic locations and see the latency and efficiency of the VLAG ports when moving traffic and virtual machines.  With luck these will happen at some point soon. Bear in mind that this is a relatively new product.  I would probably place the best competitor for this as the Juniper Qfabric or Microfabric, bith of which are a larger scale product and suffer from some of the same issues.  I&amp;rsquo;m excited to see more about it, it did its job pretty well.  Juniper and cisco take notice, these bits are important and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.plexxi.com&#34;&gt;more than just brocade are working on it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Centers.....</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/data-centers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 09:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/data-centers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data centers are one of the hot things in networking tech right now.  Combine SDN, cloud, buzzword of the day, mix with data center and serve over ice.&lt;br /&gt;
I end up doing a lot with data centers for whatever reason.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stanford.edu/~alizade/Site/DCTCP.html&#34;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt;, however, is something I found interesting.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;DCTCP is an enhancement to the TCP congestion control algorithm for data center networks. It leverages Explicit Congestion Notification (ECN), a feature which is increasingly becoming available in modern data center switches. DCTCP sources extract multi-bit feedback on congestion from the single-bit stream of ECN marks by estimating the fraction of marked packets. In doing so, DCTCP sources react to the extent of congestion, not just the presence of congestion as in TCP.  This finer level of control allows DCTCP to operate with very low buffer occupancies while simultaneously achieving high throughput. &amp;ldquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[[ This is a content summary only. Visit my website for full links, other content, and more! ]]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
