<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Strategy Series on ForwardingPlane.net</title>
    <link>https://forwardingplane.net/tags/strategy-series/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Strategy Series on ForwardingPlane.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2019, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 01:21:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://forwardingplane.net/tags/strategy-series/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv6 Q&amp;A for ISPs</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/blog/ipv6-qa-for-isps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 01:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/blog/ipv6-qa-for-isps/</guid>
      <description>As a follow on to my post on why small to medium ISPs should deploy IPv6 and the associated APNIC blog post, I have begun to compile a list of commonly asked questions IPv6 and their answers in relation to how a small to medium sized ISP can (and should) deploy IPv6. Expect this list to change and grow over time. -&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;
Q: Is there DHCP in IPv6? 
-&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategy Series: Build vs. Buy (sorta)</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/blog/strategy-series-build-vs-buy-sorta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 22:53:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/blog/strategy-series-build-vs-buy-sorta/</guid>
      <description>Build vs. buy is an often lamented and always hotly debated question in all aspects of IT, however, if one is able to truly look at all angles the answer is typically straightforward and can be rooted in one simple strategy: don&amp;rsquo;t reinvent the wheel.
Don&amp;rsquo;t reinvent the wheel Too many times we as an industry don&amp;rsquo;t do our homework - we are all guilty of it - and we reinvent a wheel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategy Series: How do you view outside of your network?</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/blog/strategy-series-view-outside-network-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 16:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/blog/strategy-series-view-outside-network-comments/</guid>
      <description>Strategy Series: How do you view outside of your network? - Tech Field Day - Feb 1, 2018
[…] Strategy Series: How do you view outside of your network? […] </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategy Series: How do you view outside of your network?</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/blog/strategy-series-view-outside-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 16:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/blog/strategy-series-view-outside-network/</guid>
      <description>In the tradition of my NIX4NetEng series I&amp;rsquo;m going to dive deep into the world of strategy, and specifically into the strategy of how we look at and operate our networks, the data they generate and the analytics that are available (and often overlooked) in how networks are managed both long term and day-to-day. So, in the spirit of visibility, lets think about how typical networks are monitored. My guess is that you either already know, or will soon realize that visibility and testing across disparate networks is hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategy Series: What is your netflow strategy?</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/blog/what-is-your-netflow-strategy-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 11:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/blog/what-is-your-netflow-strategy-comments/</guid>
      <description>What is your netflow strategy? - Tech Field Day - Dec 2, 2017
[…] What is your netflow strategy? […] [Robert Cowart]( &amp;ldquo;robacj@gmail.com&amp;rdquo;) - Dec 4, 2017
Nick, thanks for the mention of ElastiFlow. Back when I created it I knew from my past experience that there was a lot of value in flow data. However, I must admit to being surprised with how popular the solution has become. Your criticism of the lacking documentation is fair, and will be addressed in the near future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategy Series: What is your netflow strategy?</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/blog/what-is-your-netflow-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 11:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/blog/what-is-your-netflow-strategy/</guid>
      <description>You have one, right? Even if your entire strategy is “collect some flow data”, there is absolutely NO reason not to have a netflow implementation, and frankly, it will save you time and money over time if you make the effort to do it. I love network data and analytics and I have waxed poetic about how important they are at every opportunity. There are a myriad of options for analytics and flow data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>