<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abouts on ForwardingPlane.net</title>
    <link>https://forwardingplane.net/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Abouts on ForwardingPlane.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2019, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 11:13:14 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://forwardingplane.net/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/about/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 11:13:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/about/publications/</guid>
      <description>Work Profile
Nick Buraglio, Anita Nikolich, Dale Carder, Securing the SDN WAN, October 30, 2014 Nick Buraglio,Vincent Stoffer, Adam Slagell, Jim Eyrich, Scott Campbell, Von Welch, Securing the Science DMZ: a discussion,October 28, 2014 Nick Buraglio, Best practices for securing an open perimeter network, August 18, 2014  &amp;nbsp;
Video 
&amp;nbsp;
Nick Buraglio, Securing the Science DMZ, June 14, 2014 Nick Buraglio, Real world IPv6 deployments, Westnet, June 9, 2014 Nick Buraglio, Tracy Smith, Mary Stevens, Paul Hixon:National Science Foundation CC-NIE award 1341025, 2013 Nick Buraglio, OpenFlow as a network control protocol, TechTarget, March 2014 Nick Buraglio, BGP still lacks security foundation, TechTarget, May, 2014 Nick Buraglio, Why monitoring will require a networking engineer, TechTarget, March, 2015 Nick Buraglio, Secure Layer 3 SDX (Interdomain SDN): A Concept, ChiNOG 05, May, 2015 Nick Buraglio, Network engineer qualifications trump coding hype, TechTarget, November, 2015 Nick Buraglio, SDN and OpenFlow improve broadband deployment, TechTarget, October, 2015 Share this:   Twitter  Email  Print  LinkedIn  Facebook  Reddit  Tumblr  Pinterest  Pocket       </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disclaimer</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/about/disclaimer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 18:00:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/about/disclaimer/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;#8217;t endorse or condemn products for free or for money [and if I did I would disclose it in bold lettering for the world to see].
I will strive to provide a fact based description, experience or assessment of any given technology or product based on my particular experience. I may provide opinions as to what I believe is the right or wrong $item, $idea, $process, or $procedure on any given subject again based on my personal experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/about/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 08:37:02 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/about/resume/</guid>
      <description>Share this:   Twitter  Email  Print  LinkedIn  Facebook  Reddit  Tumblr  Pinterest  Pocket       </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calendar</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/about/calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 10:16:36 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/about/calendar/</guid>
      <description>Free/Busy Calendar:
The best way to schedule time with me is via my Doodle MeetMe Page.
Share this:   Twitter  Email  Print  LinkedIn  Facebook  Reddit  Tumblr  Pinterest  Pocket       </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>