<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>
    Security on ForwardingPlane.net
    
    </title>
    <link>https://forwardingplane.net/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content 
    
    in Security on ForwardingPlane.net
    </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2019, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 18:17:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    
        <atom:link href="https://forwardingplane.net/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a dynamic security infrastructure [in a box - with SDN]</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/building-a-dynamic-security-infrastructure-in-a-box-with-sdn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 18:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/building-a-dynamic-security-infrastructure-in-a-box-with-sdn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Years ago I wrote about building a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forwardingplane.net/2013/07/building-a-secured-network-in-a-box/&#34;&gt;secure network in a box&lt;/a&gt;. Over a weekend I decided to revisit this concept thanks to a colleague at work wanting to do something similar. It got me thinking “a lot has changed since I last did this” and it felt like time to revisit it. Well, disappointment wasn’t in the cards because it’s easier, smarter, and more flexible now that it was back then. As I noted back in 2013 when I wrote that last post, OVS was a lot less well traveled and, frankly, there was not a reasonable controller that I could use in production for OpenFlow integration. I’ve since standardized on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.proxmox.com/en/&#34;&gt;ProxMox&lt;/a&gt; for my lab and production virtualization and have espoused on every available occasion the usefulness of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.faucet.nz&#34;&gt;Faucet SDN controller&lt;/a&gt;. Both play fundamental roles in this project. This is significantly easier than I expected - primarily due to the use of faucet for controlling the OVS switch. It’s fairly straightforward, so I won’t go into the step by step details here since the projects have good install and support docs. Proxmox has support for OVS, so just install it using apt and create an OVS switch in the GUI interface. Faucet has &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.faucet.nz/en/latest/&#34;&gt;amazingly complete documentation&lt;/a&gt; and even a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.faucet.nz/en/latest/installation.html#installing-on-raspberry-pi&#34;&gt;raspberry pi image&lt;/a&gt; (if you’re still thinking “OpenFlow is dead, isn’t it?”, have a listen to &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.ipspace.net/2019/04/using-faucet-to-build-sc18-network-with.html&#34;&gt;this podcast&lt;/a&gt; I did with Ivan Pepelnjak). From there, install a &lt;a href=&#34;https://securityonion.net/&#34;&gt;security option VM&lt;/a&gt; (or any other tool you want to capture data with). Once you have the OVS switch, the controller, and the VM up and running getting data to it is as simple as issuing the comments to configure a controller. I my case the command was:```
sudo ovs-vsctl set-controller vmbr4 tcp:10.16.9.12:6653 tcp:10.16.9.12:6654&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-In my lab design the architecture was as such ![Faucet OVS Proxmox Security](https://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Faucet-OVS-Proxmox-Security.jpg &#34;Faucet OVS Proxmox Security.jpg&#34;) The two switches on the right are physical and span all uplink data via two physical ports into my proxmox host. Everything else is done virtually in OVS. Once you have the controller setup, the data coming in, and the host listening, you can validate you have the correct controller, interfaces and ports in ovs.```&#34; data-lang=&#34;In my lab design the architecture was as such ![Faucet OVS Proxmox Security](https://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Faucet-OVS-Proxmox-Security.jpg &#34;Faucet OVS Proxmox Security.jpg&#34;) The two switches on the right are physical and span all uplink data via two physical ports into my proxmox host. Everything else is done virtually in OVS. Once you have the controller setup, the data coming in, and the host listening, you can validate you have the correct controller, interfaces and ports in ovs.```&#34;&gt;root@pve1:~# ovs-vsctl show
75b4bc7f-4e00-45c2-8919-b043cbaf509d
Bridge &amp;#34;vmbr4&amp;#34;
Controller &amp;#34;tcp:10.16.9.12:6654&amp;#34;
Controller &amp;#34;tcp:10.16.9.12:6653&amp;#34;
is\_connected: true
Port &amp;#34;enx00051ba65ece&amp;#34;
Interface &amp;#34;enx00051ba65ece&amp;#34;
Port &amp;#34;tap115i1&amp;#34;
Interface &amp;#34;tap115i1&amp;#34;
Port &amp;#34;vmbr4&amp;#34;
Interface &amp;#34;vmbr4&amp;#34;
type: internal
Port &amp;#34;eno2&amp;#34;
Interface &amp;#34;eno2&amp;#34;
ovs\_version: “2.7.0&amp;#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listing interfaces in OVS can be a helpful way to aid in building the faucet configuration```
root@pve1:~# ovs-vsctl &amp;ndash;columns=ofport,name list interface
ofport : 65534
name : &amp;ldquo;vmbr4&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ofport              : 1
name : &amp;ldquo;eno2&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ofport              : 4
name : &amp;ldquo;tap115i1&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ofport              : 2
name : &amp;ldquo;enx00051ba65ece&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-For spanning the data into the VM, the basic configuration within faucet looks like this and should reside in /etc/faucet/faucet.yaml. The real meat here is the mirror statement on port 4.```&#34; data-lang=&#34;For spanning the data into the VM, the basic configuration within faucet looks like this and should reside in /etc/faucet/faucet.yaml. The real meat here is the mirror statement on port 4.```&#34;&gt;dps:
    proxovs1:
        dp\_id: 0x51ba65ece
        hardware: &amp;#34;Open vSwitch&amp;#34;
        interfaces:
            65534:
                name: &amp;#34;vmbr4&amp;#34;
                description: &amp;#34;ProxMox OVS vmbr4&amp;#34;
                native\_vlan: servernet
            1:
                name: &amp;#34;eno2&amp;#34;
                description: &amp;#34;Span from sw1&amp;#34;
                native\_vlan: servernet
            2:
                name: &amp;#34;enx00051ba65ece&amp;#34;
                description: &amp;#34;Span from sw2&amp;#34;
                native\_vlan: servernet
            4:
                name: &amp;#34;tap115i1&amp;#34;
                description: &amp;#34;ProxMox OVS vmbr4&amp;#34;
                output\_only: True
                mirror: \[1,2\]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be fairly easily adjusted to mirror all internal, east-west traffic in a virtualization farm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNS - the treasure trove of information your ISP can see</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/dns-the-treasure-trove-of-information-your-isp-can-see/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 10:23:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/dns-the-treasure-trove-of-information-your-isp-can-see/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the nature of &lt;a href=&#34;http://fortune.com/2017/11/23/net-neutrality-explained-what-it-means-and-why-it-matters/&#34;&gt;privacy on the internet&lt;/a&gt; has become a very important topic amongst those concerned with the now lack of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/14/16776154/fcc-net-neutrality-vote-results-rules-repealed&#34;&gt;net neutrality&lt;/a&gt;. The de-facto mechanism for dealing with privacy has been to &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letsencrypt.org/&#34;&gt;SSL all the things&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;, which I am very much in favor of. What many do not realize, though, is that simply using SSL for the traffic that transits a given ISP still leaves a wealth of thick, rich, delicious personal data still easily available to your ISP to harvest, sell, and do with as they please. This data comes in the form of DNS queries. DNS is the nearly-always-forgotten, crucial aspect of how the internet functions. Without DNS, nothing works. Everything appears broken and manifest as what appears to be a networking problem. ISPs typically provide what is called a &lt;a href=&#34;https://umbrella.cisco.com/blog/2014/07/16/difference-authoritative-recursive-dns-nameservers/&#34;&gt;recursive resolver&lt;/a&gt;, which for most people is handed down by a local provider to the customer premise equipment (CPE; usually a modem or optical terminal of some kind) that they install at a residence. This CPE then hands that resolver to your clients that use it to - you guessed it - recursively resolve DNS queries. These queries can be logged and then mined for browsing habits, etc. Anyone that has ever done any network forensics will know straight away that the value of the information contained in DNS query logs is very, very high. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this means is that even though a privacy conscious individual is hiding the bulk of their content in SSL, meaning the bulk of what they’re reading, searching for, and doing, is encrypted, the requests for that content or activity is not. For example, an ISP can potentially see that a client is making many, many queries for $onlineshopping.com and begin selling that data to advertisers. If you think they’re not doing this now, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/story/can-verizon-build-a-strong-brand-from-the-bones-of-yahoo-and-aol/&#34;&gt;think again&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great, so $bigbadprovider can see your queries. There are a number of pretty good ways to work around this, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pi-hole.net/&#34;&gt;one of my favorite projects&lt;/a&gt; handily deals with one of them with great simplicity. What I am referring to is the newly popular &lt;a href=&#34;https://scotthelme.co.uk/securing-dns-across-all-of-my-devices-with-pihole-dns-over-https-1-1-1-1/&#34;&gt;DNS over HTTPS&lt;/a&gt;, which is supported by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://one.one.one.one/&#34;&gt;cloudflare 1.1.1.1 service&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as a thought experiment I decided to play Reeses Peanut butter and chocolate with two of my favorite technological creations: the aforementioned PiHole, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://zerotier.com/&#34;&gt;ZeroTier&lt;/a&gt;. Now anyone that isn’t familiar with ZeroTier, you should acquaint yourself - Packet Pushers did a good &lt;a href=&#34;https://packetpushers.net/podcast/pq-134-meet-zerotier-open-source-networking/&#34;&gt;podcast on it back in November of 2017&lt;/a&gt;. It’s functionally an encrypted overlay supporting dual stack networking with auto configuration and gateway capabilities, and it runs on almost everything. I love this overlay technology and have been using it for a while - highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to my peanut butter and chocolate experiment. So, given that I had an existing ZeroTier network and an existing PiHole setup at home, I went over to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vultr.com/?ref=7692870&#34;&gt;Vultr.com&lt;/a&gt; and spun up a small VM for $3.50/mo, integrated it into my fleet with my Ansible and Salt tools, and installed ZeroTier and Pihole. From there I set up this DNS hierarchy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/drawings/d/e/2PACX-1vS-DsmzNWvE335KZtNo6AHX3SySG-VQWhK7i9sNgT6mFMHC5VzRWtMuJg5JraU2dJTFQT4QIGnfaMFP/pub?w=960&amp;amp;h=720&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this buys me is a fully encrypted DNS path up through the Vultr.com VM host without modifying the underlying DNS transport. And it works surprisingly well. I ran SmokePing from two hosts - both leveraging ZeroTier to do their testing, one on my local network and one in the cloud - to measure latency for a few days before I did this and kept that running after the deployment. Now, it’s not perfect but my family and I have been using this for about a month with minimal issues. Once in a great while we’ll see some slow DNS resolution time, but overall it works fairly well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Resolver-Queries.png&#34; alt=&#34;Resolver Queries&#34; title=&#34;Resolver Queries.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My take &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of using a public resolver kinda bothers me, I realize it’s probably unfounded, but I know how to and have run resolvers for ISPs and organizations for like 20 years, so I have the burden of knowledge about what is in the logs and how to run my own. Using a secured recursive resolver is simply trading transit privacy for lack of query privacy somewhere else. Then there is the issue of content networks that use DNS queries to take you to the best / topologically closest cache of their content [NOTE: this, along with the forensics data for debugging potential security issues is a &lt;strong&gt;top&lt;/strong&gt; reason that all ISPs should run their own resolvers]. I fully realize that a normal end user running their own resolver is unlikely and that this deployment is a bit overkill. However, as I can demonstrably prove, it works. And it works pretty well. It also has the added bonus of allowing me to have internal DNS resolution of my own hosts and any mobile ZeroTier client. Is it for everyone? No way. Does it prove viability for low/medium traffic use? Sure. The point is really just to get folks thinking about information leaking that they may not have considered. The nature of the internet makes true privacy pretty much impossible, but there are a few ways to make your data a little harder to for companies to compile and capitalize on if you truly don’t want them to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faucet: Enterprise OpenFlow in production</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/faucet-enterprise-openflow-in-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 10:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/faucet-enterprise-openflow-in-production/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Remember OpenFlow? It was the media and marketing darling for the better part of 5 years as “the machine” conflated OpenFlow with SDN and SDN with - almost literally - everything. &amp;ldquo;Still Does Nothing&amp;rdquo; was a common phrase uttered around those of us that had run large scale, complex networks for a long time. Quietly, &lt;a href=&#34;https://faucet-sdn.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;and mostly&lt;/a&gt;, out of the fickle media and blogosphere eye, a scrappy little SDN project called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/faucetsdn/faucet&#34;&gt;faucet&lt;/a&gt; has been &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/faucetsdn/faucet&#34;&gt;diligently plugging away&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; making easy to use, production quality, well documented, and very stable code that runs OpenFlow networks quite happily in production and at scale. Oh, did I mention that it&amp;rsquo;s also got a very small footprint? Did I also mention that we&amp;rsquo;ve built a multi-terabit network that scales, transiting IPv4, IPv6, L2/L3 switching as well as routing? Or that faucet can control switches from multiple vendors, including P4 vendors who provide a P4-to-OF bridge, and interoperates with non-SDN networks? Or (and possibly most importantly) that faucet provides automated integration tests, allowing many bugs to be caught early (sometimes even by the switch vendor) before shipping new releases? Well, I should probably mention those things. I&amp;rsquo;ve been lucky enough to have been involved in SDN off and on since around 2009, and I can emphatically say that of the production SDN and OpenFlow networks that I have been intimately involved in, this combination of hardware, software and people has been, hands down, the most rewarding and most supportable. In fact, this has been so supportable and great to work with, we migrated our production branch office over to a set of faucet controlled SDN switches, and will soon migrate first hop routing over to our robust faucet system. &amp;ldquo;However did you do this?!?!&amp;rdquo; you might be inclined to say. Well, I&amp;rsquo;m glad you asked, because I am going to tell you.    First, though, there should be some design goals. As many of the naysayers of SDN will happy point out, &amp;ldquo;what problem are you trying to solve?&amp;rdquo; to that end, here is what our design goals were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run all layer 2 in via faucet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove need to log into any network elements after deployment (other than firmware updates)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Centralize management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stretch goal to NFV BGP, do first hop L3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy enough, right? It really is. For our deployment we leveraged Aruba 2930F switches giving us a wealth of 1G copper ports and a handful of 10G SFP+ ports. Luckily, we already had this gear because as so many that have tried to deploy openflow in the past have seen, all hardware is not created equally. Luckily, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.faucet.org.nz/&#34;&gt;faucet foundation&lt;/a&gt; has published a list of requirements for support, and there are a reasonable number of vendors that actually conform. The real key that I learned in this process is that without proper vendor support (which had been several lacking in the past), and without multi-table, OpenFlow is not positioned for success. It comes down to using the right tools for the job, and OpenFlow (as well as SDN) is no different. Originally this post was to detail the process of building this network, much like posts in the past where there has been a “do this, then do that” how-to, it’s more or less unnecessary here. Why? The faucet project is serious, well documented and generally here to work. The expectation is that this is not an enclave, or a science experiment, or a lab. It’s a production network with real people and real traffic. Read that again. The expectation is that this is stable, supportable, and can do in ready to use day-to-day. And it doesn’t disappoint. Installing is a snap, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.faucet.nz/en/latest/tutorials/first_time.html&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; for faucet is fantastic and complete. If there is something missing or a question, the developers are incredibly responsive and very quick to answer and address any issues that may arise. It’s extremely low footprint - it runs very well on a raspberry pi and does not tax a raspberry pi series 2, even with the gauge telemetry interface (there is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.faucet.nz/en/latest/installation.html#installing-on-raspberry-pi&#34;&gt;pre-built pi OS&lt;/a&gt; for anyone that would prefer a more turnkey option). You may be thinking “_But Nick, I need my CLI!!!_” You’re covered - and here is why: the developers use this system. They run real networks with it. Every day. They know what is necessary to manage and maintain a real production network and sometimes that means troubleshooting. Like many engineers that learned on traditional network equipment, most of us prefer a CLI to troubleshoot, so the inclusion of this feature from the controller is not really a surprise. The fctl command provides a reasonable visibility into the operations of the controller and can be augmented and scripted.```
buraglio@faucet:~ $ /usr/bin/fctl &amp;ndash;help&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;usage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MACs learned on a DP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/usr/bin/fctl -n &amp;ndash;endpoints=&lt;a href=&#34;http://172.17.0.1:9302&#34;&gt;http://172.17.0.1:9302&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash;metrics=learned_macs &amp;ndash;labels=dp_id:0xb827eb608918&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status of all DPs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/usr/bin/fctl -n &amp;ndash;endpoints=&lt;a href=&#34;http://172.17.0.1:9302&#34;&gt;http://172.17.0.1:9302&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash;metrics=dp_status&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retrieve FAUCET/Gauge state using Prometheus variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;optional arguments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-h, &amp;ndash;help            show this help message and exit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-n, &amp;ndash;nonzero         nonzero results only&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-e ENDPOINTS, &amp;ndash;endpoints ENDPOINTS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;list of endpoint URLs to query&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-m METRICS, &amp;ndash;metrics METRICS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;list of metrics to query&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-l LABELS, &amp;ndash;labels LABELS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;list of labels that must be present&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;display-labels DISPLAY_LABELS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;list of labels to filter display by (default all)
```Monitoring is also taken into account in the form of the gauge interface, which provides a nearly-real-time telemetry stream of important and useful information. Leveraging both the wealth of topological information that the controller has at its disposal and a familiar &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/prometheus&#34;&gt;prometheus&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://grafana.com/&#34;&gt;grafana&lt;/a&gt; back / front end interface, the oft-touted notion of streaming telemetry is fully - and quite capably - realized. From the perspective of a networking monitoring and statistics geek, this is the cat’s meow. Very, very data rich. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/grafana-screencap.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/grafana-screencap-1024x275.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A simple diagram of our office network pretty well explains the decoupled control plane architecture. Keep it simple, architect for success. Fundamentally SDN networks should be designed like other networks, redundant systems, good monitoring, out of band access. A good design principle is that if you wouldn’t do it on a traditional network, you probably shouldn’t do it for an SDN based network.   &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/faunet-office.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/faunet-office.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;   Don’t trust me? Fair enough, check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.waikato.ac.nz/research/units/wand.shtml&#34;&gt;University of Waikato&lt;/a&gt; interface &lt;a href=&#34;https://grafana.redcables.wand.nz/d/000000003/redcables-bgp?orgId=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. For more interface on the deployment at &lt;a href=&#34;https://wand.net.nz/&#34;&gt;WAND&lt;/a&gt;, check &lt;a href=&#34;https://redcables.wand.nz/&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;. You won’t be disappointed.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-take&#34;&gt;My take&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;building-and-running-it&#34;&gt;Building and running it&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.faucet.nz/en/latest/&#34;&gt;documentation for faucet&lt;/a&gt; is indescribably better than any other SDN project I have worked with over the span of nearly 10 years. &lt;strong&gt;It’s also supportable.&lt;/strong&gt; My office has been running the enterprise network off of faucet for a while now, without issue, and it meets our design goals [stretch goal of BGP NFV is still in process - testing is successful]). It is easy to manage and very information rich. I can see security minded folks being very interested in the ACLs and other such options available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;telemetry-and-analytics&#34;&gt;Telemetry and analytics    &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;   Where so many others in this space are talking about their Telemetry solution, this one is already here, complete, and usable. Frankly, I am fully comfortable running a production network on this technology, operationally it is truly easier. From a security perspective, the options added scale well and deliver on their promise. Where OpenFlow was once touted as the networking silver bullet (without a lot of real stick time to prove or disprove it), it has now fallen comfortable into a nice, supportable model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;up-next&#34;&gt;Up next….    &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think this is cool, wait until &lt;a href=&#34;https://sc18.supercomputing.org/&#34;&gt;SuperComputing 18&lt;/a&gt;, where we’re deploying a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:6461072411969363968/&#34;&gt;first-of-it’s kind network&lt;/a&gt;, all controlled by FAUCET.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDoS mitigation podcast, black hole routing</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ddos-mitigation-podcast-black-hole-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 10:53:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ddos-mitigation-podcast-black-hole-routing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an often-security-engineer and an individual that has been working on large networks for quite a while, dealing with DDoS, or the threat of DDoS is a well traveled path. Recently I was invited to discuss some of the basics of DDoS mitigation on the Network Collective Podcast. This was a really fun and insightful chat with a wealth of great information for engineers and operators of any skill level.   &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/298146825&#34;&gt;Ep38 - DDoS Mitigation&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/networkcollective&#34;&gt;Network Collective&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.   As mentioned in the cast, there are some good, free resources out there for black hole routing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://fod.grnet.gr/welcome?next=/&#34;&gt;GRnet firewall on Demand&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2011/10/black-hole-routing/&#34;&gt;BlackHole Routing Basics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nanog.org/sites/default/files/tuesday_general_ddos_ryburn_63.16.pdf&#34;&gt;Using BGP FlowSpec slides from NANOG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trouble with Tribbles .....errr NAT</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/trouble-with-tribbles-errr-nat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 10:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/trouble-with-tribbles-errr-nat/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;As a follow up to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forwardingplane.net/2018/06/nat-discussions/&#34;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted to dive a little deeper into the world of address translation and to suss out some of the more compelling details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve said on many occasions, it pains me to see NAT referenced as a security mechanism. That said, where PNAT can be beneficial is in an overall privacy strategy, however, even that is comparatively low value and given the current state of global IPv4 allocations, arguably a detriment to usability - we’ll get to that - before we do, it is important to understand what ’NAT” as we call it today actually is, and to do that we need to explain all of the types of address translation (yes, there are several). When what was designed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Static, or one-to-one NAT&lt;/strong&gt; This is the original and most simple. It is comprised of an internal and corresponding external IP address. Every machine on the network still needs a public IP address for external mapping with this model. It was originally designed to solve the problem NAT was built to address: address translation between two networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic NAT&lt;/strong&gt; This is a bit of a hybrid of static and the next type, NAPT. In this model, a NAT router maintains a set of external IPv4 address and cynically allocates one to internal addressed for outbound communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network Address port translation (NAPT)&lt;/strong&gt; This is what most folks will mean when they say “NAT”. Really, this is address masquerading with port translation. This is what is often confused with a security tool, given that it provides a low level of obfuscation from external scanning and “hides” the hosts behind an externally facing address. This mechanism is typically conflated with stateful firewall implementation, which is not inclusive of this implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the enterprise expectation of a modern UTM, NAPT is unfortunately used interchangeably by many security professionals. What NAPT actually buys is a mechanism for obfuscating many hosts to a smaller number of addresses, typically on the same device. By removing a single data reconnaissance vector (scanning of ipv4) you’re actually providing a new one that’s much easier to exploit (state table exhaustion). While it does work to prevent inbound scanning, that’s really all it does other than allow for network and port translation, it should not be expected to provide anything more than simple obscuring of the internal data. NAPT as security is primarily predicated on the notion that your source address is critically important and should be obscured. While this is true to a certain extent, this believe is somewhat antiquated and should be treated as such. Tracking via source address is still completely doable with simple tools, and geolocation is completely available (assuming it is correctly registered) based on the NAPT address. This is true of IPv4 and IPv6. What NAT does accomplish is prevention of scanning and external recon of potentially sensitive systems. That’s it. I would also assert that this over-stated sense of usefulness users a false sense of protection and encourages a relaxed diligence on hardening end hosts. The same level of protection can very easily be accomplished on a public IPv4 or IPv6 prefix with a simple stateful firewall or host based firewall. What NAPT buys is two fold:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Extension of IPv4 resources&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A poor shortcut to resource protection&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If sized appropriately, the expense of this is a very under-stated price tag&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A sizable cost for right-sized UTM&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Acceptance of the risk of a state table exhaustion DoS event&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Insecure internal resources, IoT devices, or BYOD nodes that are compromised or vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without proper east-west filtering and a tight egress policy, this sheen of protection becomes significantly less useful. Add in the likelihood of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carrier-grade_NAT&#34;&gt;carrier grade NAT (CGNAT)&lt;/a&gt; due to extreme &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPv4_address_exhaustion&#34;&gt;exhaustion of IPv4 resource&lt;/a&gt;, and you compound the limits with additional operational and troubleshooting overhead. IPv6, while the correct next step, does solve a large part of the issues, but not without it’s own [mostly one-time] costs, and given the large uptake in IPv6 from both the client and content perspectives, it would behoove every organization to get their IPv6 strategy sorted and underway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-take&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My take&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the olden times of winnuke, providing a layer of confusion between the delicious caramel center of your network resource and the dragons of the internet was pretty important. The tracking mechanisms and scanning was mostly thwarted by the thin candy shell of the NAPT device. While this is still a very important aspect in your network architecture and defense in depth strategy, understanding the real risks and true value is important. The belief that NAPT provides your security (or that it is even a security tool at all) is somewhat misguided. With regard to privacy, the real threats lie in the metadata collection, and unless you are high profile or have a highly targeted business or personal footprint, the security incidents are far more nuanced and often happen at higher layers. In addition, lets not forget that a very, very real threat is not from random poking at our externally facing network resources, but in the social engineering attacks that are readily let right in the door. In addition, there are a number of significant risks that NAPT beings to bear based on it’s use of a state table to track IP to port mappings. All of these details need to be considered and continually revisited for relevance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;further-study&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Further study&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding that this is a very high profile, sensitive, and polarizing subject, additional reading and research is important. A few good white papers detailing shortcomings and misconceptions surrounding NAPT can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/amp/s/www.calyptix.com/top-threats/ddos-attacks-101-types-targets-motivations/amp/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://f5.com/resources/white-papers/the-myth-of-network-address-translation-as-security&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. In addition, &lt;a href=&#34;https://thenetworkcollective.com/&#34;&gt;The Network Collective&lt;/a&gt; invited me back to discuss privacy in networking. What resulted was a very spicy podcasts that really highlights the complexity of privacy as a concept in today&amp;rsquo;s internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/272381393&#34;&gt;Ep28 - For The Love Of NAT&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/networkcollective&#34;&gt;Network Collective&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAT discussions, fact checking, and debate</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nat-discussions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 09:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nat-discussions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been very vocal about the misinterpretation of NAT for many, many years. Since it&amp;rsquo;s inception, NAT has been slowly perverted into what many now believe to be a security mechanism. While I do see a reasonable use of IP masquerading in a larger security strategy, this is not the original intent (or implementation) of NAT. What mosts network engineers call &amp;ldquo;NAT&amp;rdquo; is actually &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tldp.org/HOWTO/IP-Masquerade-HOWTO/ipmasq-background2.1.html&#34;&gt;one to many network port address translation&lt;/a&gt; - or taking one public address and &amp;ldquo;hiding&amp;rdquo; a number of private (likely &lt;a href=&#34;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc1918&#34;&gt;RFC1918&lt;/a&gt;) addresses &amp;ldquo;behind&amp;rdquo; it, using ports to translate traffic and keeping the state of those connections. Given my&amp;hellip;.vigor for debating the details of NAT, I was invited to discuss this on &lt;a href=&#34;https://thenetworkcollective.com/2018/05/ep28-for-the-love-of-nat/&#34;&gt;an episode of The Network Collective Podcast.&lt;/a&gt; We get to some of the grimy details with some technical heavy hitters, so if you&amp;rsquo;re into the debate, it is certainly worth a watch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategy Series: What is your netflow strategy?</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/what-is-your-netflow-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 11:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/what-is-your-netflow-strategy/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;You have one, right? Even if your entire strategy is “collect some flow data”, there is absolutely NO reason not to have a netflow implementation, and frankly, it will save you time and money over time if you make the effort to do it. I love network data and analytics and I have waxed poetic about how important they are at every opportunity. There are a myriad of options for analytics and flow data. If you’re not doing something, you’re doing it wrong. I can go on and on about the importance of network data for budgeting, security, capacity planing, and general knowledge of what your network is actually doing, but that’s for another day (contact me directly if you really want to chat details on that subject). Today is about network flow data - the foundational bits and pieces of what the heck your network, big or small, is actually doing. I’ve been having a breakdance fight with flow data packages for almost two decades, and I’ve jotted down a few of my more notable experiences. Regardless of your needs, budget, abilities, or time, there is a solution for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com/gifs/breakin-boogaloo-shrimp-11FirB7GcukiwU&#34;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;arbor-https-www-arbornetworks-com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arbornetworks.com/&#34;&gt;Arbor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arbor is the Rolls Royce of flow analytics (and DDoS mitigation) solutions. It does almost everything, has options for managed objects, DDoS scrubbing and alerting capabilities, a magnificent interface, role based access, rainbows and gumdrop houses with lollipop trees. This system is pretty darned amazing - it truly is, and that likely comes from the fact that they were one of the first, and had/have one of the largest install bases for this kind of system. They have turnkey solutions and have the unique position of being in roughly 90% of the worlds legacy tier 1 ISPs, so their DDoS and other security options are strong, fast to update, and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; good. I’ve had great experience with this platform and its API. I like to think of arbor as the commercial ISP brass ring for flow data analytics. They have other solutions for enterprise and campus, but their roots are in strong ISP solutions. They’re pricey, but very, very good. Expect to need at least an FTE to really take full advantage of their very capable ecosystem, but if you dedicated the money and manpower to it, you won’t be sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;splunk-https-www-splunk-com&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.splunk.com/&#34;&gt;Splunk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know spunk as a really nice log and analytic system but what many may not realize is that Splunk is really, really good at network data and analytics as well. It’s pricey, but it’s as close as you’ll get to a turkey solution for a SIEM that can actually scale. It has the notion of customizable dashboards and visualization, as a huge amount of plugins and add on’s, but they come with a legendarily steep price tag. The saying I have always heard is “if you can afford spunk, buy spunk. If you can’t use an ELK stack (noe elastic stack)”. My experience backs this up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;elk-elastic-stack-https-www-elastic-co&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elastic.co/&#34;&gt;ELK /Elastic Stack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a big fan of this not only because it’s essentially free, but because it’s so extremely flexible and has so many existing projects built around it. I’ve moved my go-to for net flow collection from nfdump to Elastic Stack built around the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.manitonetworks.com/about-flow-analyzer/&#34;&gt;Manito Networks flowanalyzer&lt;/a&gt; install.   This platform takes a bit more command line jockeying and isn’t entirely turnkey, but it’s crazy flexible, had great eye candy and building the visualizations and dashboards is easy. Notable mention is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robcowart/elastiflow&#34;&gt;Elastiflow&lt;/a&gt;, which is similar but has a bit more eye candy and leverages log stash. Elastiflow doesn’t have nearly as turnkey of an install (and really has almost no “newbie” install instructions at all - but it’s a strong offering if you already know how to spin up an ELK stack and tune it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nfdump-http-nfdump-sourceforge-net&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nfdump.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Nfdump&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The venerable nfdump. This is what so many large networks were using (and probably still are) for their raw flow collections. This package scales exceptionally well to huge networks and has so many tools available for the CLI that it’s the de facto standard for raw flow analytics and forensics. I love this system and ran it for many, many, MANY years. It takes a but of time to learn, and may not be the right tool for you if you want a modern GUI, lots of eye candy, or are inexperienced with the UNIX/LINIX command line, but it’s got it where it counts, supports IPFix, Netflow v5, v9 and IPFIX and you can’t dog wrong with it. I have a handy how-to getting it up and running Under CentOS &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forwardingplane.net/2014/01/install-nfsen-and-nfdump-on-centos-6-5-for-netflow-and-or-sflow-collection/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. When you couple this with something like &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/JustinAzoff/flow-indexer&#34;&gt;Justin Azoff’s flow indexer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourceforge.net/projects/nfsen/&#34;&gt;nfsen&lt;/a&gt; on the front end, you’ve got an enviable power user setup ripe for both forensics, tactical work as well as baseline generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;solarwinds-https-www-solarwinds-com&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.solarwinds.com/&#34;&gt;SolarWinds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solarwinds Orion is the go-to for windows based monitoring. It’s not cheap, but if you’re running a windows based monitoring system, you’re likely an enterprise and have budget for it. I have been impressed with the visualizations of this system and like that it does all of the monitoring in one package - once installed I never have to see windows (and since I can’t efficiently support windows, that’s probably a good thing - someone else will handle the OS work). The price tag can be a bit steep depending on number of nodes monitored, but it does what it claims and commercial support is decent. My one complaint is that I can’t seem to find a way to do raw data queries in a straightforward way. This may be possible and I have just not had the time or mental power to workout out. Overall it’s a worthy monitoring platform if you need your system to run on windows and can afford it. There are some older but still good videos from several Network Field Day events &lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/companies/solarwinds/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and I wrote about it from a UNIX users perspective &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forwardingplane.net/2015/07/solarwinds-orion-from-a-unix-user-point-of-view/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;live-action-networks-live-ux-https-www-liveaction-com-products-live-ux&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.liveaction.com/products/live-ux/&#34;&gt;Live Action Networks Live UX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another commercial option that has good support and a lot of eye candy. This was born out of work with the US Government and is a really interesting system. I’ve met with these guys several times and their team is super open to taking and feature requests and they have a good product. I first heard about them at &lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/appearance/liveaction-presents-at-networking-field-day-7/&#34;&gt;Network Field day 7&lt;/a&gt;, their product was intriguing there and they’ve come a long way since then. Worth looking at for a turnkey solution for things like network analytics, IP-SLA,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-take&#34;&gt;My take&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the power that an indexed set of data provides and I am willing and capable of plowing through the install of a linux based system. I’m also frugal, and for a product to really warrant my money it needs to do something that nothing else does [translated: I am willing and able to support open source solutions].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Screenshot-2017-12-15-20.32.57.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, the Manito Networks install of Elk + Kibana (no logstash in this default install) is where I typically land due to the fact that I can get indexed flow data, nice, configurable graphs and trending statistics, and can integrate things like syslog into another index on the same system giving me the tools to do forensics on a number of topics on that system. &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/thart/flowanalyzer/blob/master/Install/README.md&#34;&gt;The setup is crazy easy&lt;/a&gt; and really well documented, too. Someone linux-inclined can have it up and collecting flow data (sflow, netflow v5/9 or IPFIX) in an order of about 30 minutes - probably less. The take aways really, though, is that there are options available no matter your skill level or budget, so there is really no reason not to have something.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No privacy may be the new privacy.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/no-privacy-may-new-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 18:06:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/no-privacy-may-new-privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Taking politics and putting them aside, what the new administration has &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/03/23/technology/congress-moves-to-strike-internet-privacy-rules-from-obama-era.html?_r=0&#34;&gt;been attempting to change&lt;/a&gt; with regard to internet privacy is something we should &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; be informed about. Wether you have a tin foil hat or don&amp;rsquo;t care, &amp;ldquo;knowing is half the battle&amp;rdquo;. The other half is doing - which I will also lend some brief insight to (sorta). What&amp;rsquo;s changing? Nothing yet (as of the time of this writing). What will likely change? The ability of your internet (mobile or not) to sell your browsing habits and personal usage data. What does this mean? Well, it means that if you visit facebook, amazon, JC Penny, or buy-adult-toys.com a lot, that information can be sold to advertisers, private companies, etc., etc. &amp;ldquo;But I use SSL, I&amp;rsquo;m safe&amp;rdquo;. Nope. DNS query data - the requests made for a domain name like google.com, used to map a name to an IPvX address - that can be sold too. The content of the browsing is great, but the knowledge that a site was visited is just as useful&amp;hellip;and this data is generated not just by traditional &amp;ldquo;browsing&amp;rdquo;, everything that touches the internet uses it. Apps, Games, everything. Removing these rules also means that there is no oversight into how this collection can be done, what kind of data - sensitive or not - can be collected and sold and to whom. That&amp;rsquo;s what deregulation looks like, folks.&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/personal.info_.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/personal.info_.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; What does this mean for the average internet user like, say, my Mom or Dad? It means that when they look at ANYTHING online, it&amp;rsquo;s likely going to be collected, indexed, data mined, and then sold to be further data mined and then these users will get targeted for a barrage of advertising. Worse yet, this data is ripe for misuse. What if the data is compromised? Sorry. That&amp;rsquo;ll suck for sure. Even worse that than, what if that data is used by nation states? What if it&amp;rsquo;s misinterpreted? It&amp;rsquo;s a mess. Has this data been used in this manner in the past? Sure. All of the providers use it internally. &lt;a href=&#34;http://money.cnn.com/2016/07/25/technology/yahoo-verizon-deal-sale/&#34;&gt;Verizon bought yahoo&lt;/a&gt; for this reason.  The real issue is that most people do not understand what all of this means. Since the internet is a completely traceable environment in 99.999% of cases, unlike really anything prior, this is paramount. What can you do? Well, if you&amp;rsquo;re not technical, good luck. Perhaps if this happens it will spark a new industry of private overlays like Tor to be commercialized and widely adopted. Wait with the FCC leaning toward rolling back net neutrality those services could likely be slowed or blocked completely. Sorry. On the fringes are the mom-and-pop ISPs - they still exist. WISPs, small and rural providers. These are less likely to be the safest bet in the future should this come to pass. Mobile metadata - what will generate the majority of the controversy - is likely to be the most often sold because there will be such a diverse and deep pool of data. Another of the side effects is this could potentially be an even higher adoption of SSL, which is good, but may also lead to a higher adoption of the vile SSL decryption practice. Lets hope not. What will I do? Not sure. I have extensive experience running DNS servers and VPNs. I may just start connecting to one of my VPS devices and run everything over OpenVPN from both mobile and traditional connections. There are some super simple &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kylemanna/docker-openvpn&#34;&gt;docker how-tos&lt;/a&gt; out there that Ive used in the past. VPS service are cheap, I have a few but my &lt;a href=&#34;https://prgmr.com/xen/&#34;&gt;prgmr.com&lt;/a&gt; VPS is my favorite. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to tunnel IPv6 too. Welcome to 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an internal span port inside proxmox OVS</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/creating-internal-span-port-inside-proxmox-ovs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 03:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/creating-internal-span-port-inside-proxmox-ovs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last few years I have moved all of my virtualization to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.proxmox.com/en/&#34;&gt;proxmox&lt;/a&gt; and docker. Seeing as I like to look at packets because I am a closet security guy, and being as I have been working off-and-on on a security project in recent times, I wanted to be able to span a port not only from a hardware switch, but also within my software switches. I had been using linux bridge, which I am not a fan of, so when I started down this path I did not look hard to find a way to do so under that platform. Instead I used it as an opportunity to move some of the internal bridges to &lt;a href=&#34;http://openvswitch.org/&#34;&gt;OpenVSwitch&lt;/a&gt;. I wanted to create an OVS span port internally. I had experience with OVS in the past for SDN work that I was doing, but I had never created a mirror port. I briefly thought about using OpenFlow to do it, but the unnecessary complexity was off putting. Instead I chose to create a simple mirror of a span port from my switch. So, traffic flow goes as such: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/OVS-SPAN-1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/OVS-SPAN-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;     This was fairly trivial, and I was seeing packets in no time. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go through creating an OVS bridge in proxmox, there are lots of &lt;a href=&#34;https://pve.proxmox.com/wiki/Open_vSwitch&#34;&gt;documents&lt;/a&gt; on how to do that. Once you have your switch port SPAN up and running, and the physical interface in the OVS bridge, you essentially just need to add the following: Create the mirror```
ovs-vsctl &amp;ndash; &amp;ndash;id=@m create mirror name=span &amp;ndash; add bridge vmbr1 mirrors @m&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Find your ports that you want to mirror - you&#39;ll need the physical port if consuming from a real switch like I am, and the software port of the virtualized analyzer.  Remember, in OVS anything you want to mess with is going to have a UUID. You need to match the interfaces with the UUID to verify. ovs-vsctl list port \_uuid : 42dbd5a9-27c6-4f1b-958b-943f67b6801b bond\_downdelay : 0 bond\_fake\_iface : false bond\_mode : \[\] bond\_updelay : 0 external\_ids : {} fake\_bridge : false interfaces : \[b155454d-db6e-4bb8-af88-7cd6b544c303\] lacp : \[\] mac : \[\] name : &#34;eth1&#34; other\_config : {} qos : \[\] statistics : {} status : {} tag : \[\] trunks : \[\] vlan\_mode : \[\] \_uuid : 85c932b2-4f98-4650-8298-ae9e9ca72796 bond\_downdelay : 0 bond\_fake\_iface : false bond\_mode : \[\] bond\_updelay : 0 external\_ids : {} fake\_bridge : false interfaces : \[5219306f-96ec-440a-ac8b-d949ea18d752\] lacp : \[\] mac : \[\] name : &#34;vmbr1&#34; other\_config : {} qos : \[\] statistics : {} status : {} tag : \[\] trunks : \[\] vlan\_mode : \[\] \_uuid : d53c7323-517f-48a2-9235-4505e654d4b1 bond\_downdelay : 0 bond\_fake\_iface : false bond\_mode : \[\] bond\_updelay : 0 external\_ids : {} fake\_bridge : false interfaces : \[91d52d05-d881-4693-ab5c-fc64b5d87518\] lacp : \[\] mac : \[\] name : &#34;veth100i9&#34; other\_config : {} qos : \[\] statistics : {} status : {} tag : \[\] trunks : \[\] vlan\_mode : \[\] In red we have the interfaces I want to to use. the veth interface is the software port on the VM. Eth1 is the hardware interfce that my switch is spanning traffic to. Pro tip: In OVS, the commands are a little unintuitive to me when talking about mirrors.  &#34;select\_src\_port&#34; and &#34;select\_dst\_port=&#34; is the destination of the traffic flow from an interface and not source and destination of the traffic you are mirroring from the point of view of the in and out ports. Confusing, right? For instance I can monitor the input from one interface and the output of another in the mirror. What we want is the input and output of the same interface to get both directions of traffic. This is not unlike how span ports are configured on your hardware switch, the nomenclature just threw me off.```&#34; data-lang=&#34;Find your ports that you want to mirror - you&#39;ll need the physical port if consuming from a real switch like I am, and the software port of the virtualized analyzer.  Remember, in OVS anything you want to mess with is going to have a UUID. You need to match the interfaces with the UUID to verify. ovs-vsctl list port \_uuid : 42dbd5a9-27c6-4f1b-958b-943f67b6801b bond\_downdelay : 0 bond\_fake\_iface : false bond\_mode : \[\] bond\_updelay : 0 external\_ids : {} fake\_bridge : false interfaces : \[b155454d-db6e-4bb8-af88-7cd6b544c303\] lacp : \[\] mac : \[\] name : &#34;eth1&#34; other\_config : {} qos : \[\] statistics : {} status : {} tag : \[\] trunks : \[\] vlan\_mode : \[\] \_uuid : 85c932b2-4f98-4650-8298-ae9e9ca72796 bond\_downdelay : 0 bond\_fake\_iface : false bond\_mode : \[\] bond\_updelay : 0 external\_ids : {} fake\_bridge : false interfaces : \[5219306f-96ec-440a-ac8b-d949ea18d752\] lacp : \[\] mac : \[\] name : &#34;vmbr1&#34; other\_config : {} qos : \[\] statistics : {} status : {} tag : \[\] trunks : \[\] vlan\_mode : \[\] \_uuid : d53c7323-517f-48a2-9235-4505e654d4b1 bond\_downdelay : 0 bond\_fake\_iface : false bond\_mode : \[\] bond\_updelay : 0 external\_ids : {} fake\_bridge : false interfaces : \[91d52d05-d881-4693-ab5c-fc64b5d87518\] lacp : \[\] mac : \[\] name : &#34;veth100i9&#34; other\_config : {} qos : \[\] statistics : {} status : {} tag : \[\] trunks : \[\] vlan\_mode : \[\] In red we have the interfaces I want to to use. the veth interface is the software port on the VM. Eth1 is the hardware interfce that my switch is spanning traffic to. Pro tip: In OVS, the commands are a little unintuitive to me when talking about mirrors.  &#34;select\_src\_port&#34; and &#34;select\_dst\_port=&#34; is the destination of the traffic flow from an interface and not source and destination of the traffic you are mirroring from the point of view of the in and out ports. Confusing, right? For instance I can monitor the input from one interface and the output of another in the mirror. What we want is the input and output of the same interface to get both directions of traffic. This is not unlike how span ports are configured on your hardware switch, the nomenclature just threw me off.```&#34;&gt;ovs-vsctl set mirror span select\_src\_port=@eth1 select\_dst\_port=@eth1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also do this with the UUID```
ovs-vsctl set mirror span select_src_port=42dbd5a9-27c6-4f1b-958b-943f67b6801b select_dst_port=42dbd5a9-27c6-4f1b-958b-943f67b6801b&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Now that we have the source of our mirror we just need to send it somewhere. I wanted mine to go to an internal host running some analytics software (on interface veth100i9)```&#34; data-lang=&#34;Now that we have the source of our mirror we just need to send it somewhere. I wanted mine to go to an internal host running some analytics software (on interface veth100i9)```&#34;&gt;ovs-vsctl -- --id=@veth100i9 get port veth100i9 -- set mirror span output-port=@veth100i9&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s it. Log into your host and do a tcpdump on whatever interface is mapped to veth100i9 and you should see packets flowing. A few tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify your span from the hardware switch is working before diving into the software stack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re doing this is proxmox, be aware that proxmox networking stack can be unforgiving when you much around outside of their environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This will not persist across reboots. Add it to /etc/network/interfaces manually to keep it after a restart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BGP RPKI - why aren&#39;t we using it more?</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/bgp-rpki-why-arent-we-using-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 16:33:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/bgp-rpki-why-arent-we-using-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;nav&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#image-created-from-surfnet-rpki-page&#34;&gt;Image created from SURFNet RPKI page.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;

&lt;p&gt;     I was recently at a meeting where BGP RPKI was the topic de jour. While this has been a topic that I have visited on occasion of the last few years and something I wanted to spend significant time on, I have found that setting aside the time has been difficult and sparse, much like the deployment of BGP RPKI. In order to better understand the options available, it&amp;rsquo;s important to break down the pieces and terminology involved; BGP is daunting enough to those unfamiliar with it and adding PKI on top of that can be even more so. So, what are these bits and pieces and why have we not done more to adopt it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BGP&lt;/strong&gt; - the venerable and foundational protocol that quite literally runs the internet. BGP allows an organization to announce and exchange it’s IPv4 and IPv6 resources with other organizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arin.net/resources/rpki/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resource Public Key Infrastructure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arin.net/resources/rpki/&#34;&gt;ARIN&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Using cryptographically verifiable certificates, RPKI allows IP address holders to specify which Autonomous Systems (AS&amp;rsquo;s) are authorized to originate their IP address prefixes. These statements, known as Route Origin Authorizations (ROAs), allow network operators to make informed routing decisions, and help secure Internet routing in general. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROA&lt;/strong&gt; - Route Origin Authorizations - Who is authorized to originate or source these prefixes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROV&lt;/strong&gt; - Route Origin Validation - Can we validate, cryptographically, that the origin of this resource (for example, 8.8.8.8) is authorized to originate or source these prefixes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;     Many of the details of RPKI are actually not even technical, both with ARIN and with vendors, there exists complications that make the technical pieces look like child’s play. Legality of the licensing and housing of authoritative certificates are complicated, shrouded in legalese due to the nature of what they represent. This proves to be a show stopper for a lot of older organizations that have grandfathered address space and may not have gone through the ARIN agreement process any time in the recent past [note: supposedly this process is required for ARIN IPv6 space, so most of that _should_ be covered. Other regions may have easier, lower hurdles - I’ve heard good things about RIPE’s process - but I have no experience with it. The legal issues with contracts and signing certificates may also prove to be troublesome to enterprises, most of which are very conservative and slow to adopt anything new ::cough:: IPv6 ::cough::.  Certificate generation and maintenance is also considered difficult in many cases, the details can be confusing and the documentation overwhelming or difficult to find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of those non-technical issues, platforms with large install bases are sparsely supported - although this is changing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;     There have been a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bgpmon.net/large-scale-bgp-hijack-out-of-india/&#34;&gt;number&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bgpmon.net/large-hijack-affects-reachability-of-high-traffic-destinations/&#34;&gt;recent&lt;/a&gt;, high profile route hijacks. If you’re ever curious to see what they were, BGPMon typically has a post-mortem shortly after they occur. This is a big deal. There are a number of ways they could have been prevented, too one of which is BGP RPKI. Is that worth the overhead? I think anyone that has had to scramble to figure out what was going on during one of these events would argue yes. But even with that, we have minimal adoption. With the significant movement to cloud based work, enterprises, service providers, academic institutions and even savvy end users should ask themselves a few important questions before doing your risk analysis:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do your cloud providers do RPKI?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does your upstream service provider or peering partner honor invalid routes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does your upstream service provider or peering partner even support prefix or AS-Path filtering?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does the effect BGP blackhole routing for security filtering?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you deal with invalid routes? (alert, set preference, drop, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you handle invalid routes that may be more specific?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why have I not deployed BGP RPKI yet?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My perspective:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    Unfortunately, the feeling I get is very similar to that of things [that we actually need] such as IPv6 and DNSSec. Tools that make our resources safer,  but are often overlooked due to increased operational complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is really about risk analysis: Is the risk of not having this worth the effort of maintaining it?  Since we [as an internetworking ecosystem] been clear in our actions that necessary things as obvious and straightforward as appropriate prefix filtering and IPv6 deployment are in many cases above and beyond, it should come as no surprise that adding complexity on top of “stuff that just works” is’t happening on a large scale. Even with repeated proof that changes would alleviate risk, we don’t do it because what we have has been deemed “good enough”* and change is scary and hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do we need? We need tools. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://rpki.surfnet.nl/&#34;&gt;RPKI dashboard&lt;/a&gt; that SURFnet has available is a fantastic example of an easy to use tool that makes a ton of information available. We need a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;very easy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; way to deploy this. BGP is actually a pretty simple protocol to make work, which is why is hasn’t changed much in the  extremely long tenure it has had as foundation of the internet. We need a very, very straightforward way to get the non-technical pieces done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; This is just the tip of the iceberg and I am but a novice with this tech - but my gut feelings are typically right about this type of thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* &amp;ldquo;Good enough” is almost never good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&#34;image-created-from-surfnet-rpki-page&#34;&gt;Image created from SURFNet RPKI page.&lt;/h6&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenDNS acquires BGPMon and the future of route monitoring</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/opendns-acquires-bgpmon-and-the-future-of-route-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 05:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/opendns-acquires-bgpmon-and-the-future-of-route-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For those that run BGP networks, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bgpmon.net&#34;&gt;BGPmon&lt;/a&gt; is often a tool they turn to for some really unique and hard to find information. Remember back in February 2008 when Pakistan Telecom &amp;ldquo;blocked&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/buraglio&#34;&gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt;? That one was a really, really public example of something that BGPMon caught. BGPmon has been around for a long, long time. Quietly watching prefixes. Silently noting changes and reporting them to the ones lucky enough to know of its existence. For those that don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;a href=&#34;http://searchtelecom.techtarget.com/feature/BGP-essentials-The-protocol-that-makes-the-Internet-work&#34;&gt;know how BGP works&lt;/a&gt;, I am not going to go into it too much other than to say that it is both the foundation that the internet is built upon, and one of the most antiquated trust models that exists in a world where most of the pundits are going on and on about SDN and network engineers being out of a job in 10 years. See, the problem with BGP is not that it is a terrible protocol. Quite the opposite, it is elegant in its simplicity and ability to be extended.It is lightweight and arguably the easiest of the routing protocols with the exception of RIPv2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Many have argued that it is not a routing protocol, per se, but a policy enforcement framework for paths, but that is a completely different discussion. I happen to agree&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue with BGP is that its install base is so vast that changing it is not unlike parting the red sea or holding the earth on ones shoulders, because that is what BGP does. It holds the internet on its shoulders every bit as much as things like fiber in the ground does. Lets get back to BGPmon. BGPmon does something that nothing else really does. It watches the global routing table from points all over the globe and keeps track of prefixes. For a network operation that provides transit, financial services or any sensitive data, notification of a ROA violation, prefix hijack or more specific route announcement is a critical service. BGPmon provides that among other equally distinct services. In fact, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forwardingplane.net/2014/03/bgp-tools-troubleshooting-and-monitoring-external-routing-in-a-nutshell/&#34;&gt;I have it listed as one of my critical tools for maintaining, monitoring and troubleshooting external routing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does the acquisition of BGPmon by OpenDNS mean? I honestly can not say, but I am fairly confident that it means good things and &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.opendns.com/2015/03/12/opendns-acquires-bgpmon/&#34;&gt;OpenDNS has a very, very encouraging position&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moving forward, our integration plan for BGPmon is straightforward. We’ll invest in building out the service and making it more complete—but we also are committed to keeping the free features free. We’ll continue to use BGPmon data and innovate to augment our predictive intelligence and provide better threat protection to OpenDNS customers. So basically status quo for current customers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strong backing from a forward thinking company with a solid track record of good products likely means a bright future for an invaluable service. I am optimistic and encouraged, this was the next logical step and they have taken it with elegance and thought.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIX4NetEng 5 - GeoIP tools</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nix4neteng-5-geoip-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 18:22:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nix4neteng-5-geoip-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes in networking and security it becomes necessary to do lookups of location data on IP addresses and prefixes. On my Mac I use &lt;a href=&#34;http://brew.sh/&#34;&gt;homebrew&lt;/a&gt; to manage packages, but most of these tools are available with thetypocal apt, yum and port package management systems. For this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to shift gears and show the install on my mac:```
sliver:~ buraglio$ brew install geoip
==&amp;gt; Downloading &lt;a href=&#34;https://downloads.sf.net/project/machomebrew/Bottles/geoip-1.6.3.mavericks.bottle.tar.gz&#34;&gt;https://downloads.sf.net/project/machomebrew/Bottles/geoip-1.6.3.mavericks.bottle.tar.gz&lt;/a&gt;
######################################################################## 100.0%
==&amp;gt; Pouring geoip-1.6.3.mavericks.bottle.tar.gz
sliver:~ buraglio$ brew install geoipupdate
==&amp;gt; Downloading &lt;a href=&#34;https://downloads.sf.net/project/machomebrew/Bottles/geoipupdate-2.0.2.mavericks.bottle.tar.gz&#34;&gt;https://downloads.sf.net/project/machomebrew/Bottles/geoipupdate-2.0.2.mavericks.bottle.tar.gz&lt;/a&gt;
######################################################################## 100.0%
==&amp;gt; Pouring geoipupdate-2.0.2.mavericks.bottle.tar.gz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Once this installed we need to do a simple update:```&#34; data-lang=&#34;Once this installed we need to do a simple update:```&#34;&gt;sliver:~ buraglio$ geoipupdate
sliver:~ buraglio$&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This really doesn&amp;rsquo;t yield any output, but I tend to do it pretty much every time I am using the tool so I know I have up to date information. So lets say that you are a service provider and your customers are calling complaining that they&amp;rsquo;re seeing www.weather.co.uk when going to weather.com or more realistically, they can&amp;rsquo;t get to netflix or amazon video, which tells them they don&amp;rsquo;t support srtreaming to the UK.```
sliver:~ buraglio$ geoiplookup 141.142.2.2
GeoIP Country Edition: US, United States
GeoIP City Edition, Rev 1: US, IL, Illinois, Urbana, 61801, 40.109501, -88.212303, 648, 217&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Nope, that looks ok, it must be something else \[I have actually seen this problem in the past, it&#39;s really no fun to run to ground\]. As you can see, there is a good deal of information there, lat/long, area code, city, state, zip, etc. This data, specifically the lat/long, can be used to do really cool visualization stuff with things like google maps or google earth. As a sanity check, here is a view of bbc.com:```&#34; data-lang=&#34;Nope, that looks ok, it must be something else \[I have actually seen this problem in the past, it&#39;s really no fun to run to ground\]. As you can see, there is a good deal of information there, lat/long, area code, city, state, zip, etc. This data, specifically the lat/long, can be used to do really cool visualization stuff with things like google maps or google earth. As a sanity check, here is a view of bbc.com:```&#34;&gt;sliver:~ buraglio$ geoiplookup 212.58.244.71
GeoIP Country Edition: GB, United Kingdom
GeoIP City Edition, Rev 1: GB, N7, Surrey, Tadworth, N/A, 51.283298, -0.233300, 0, 0&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yup, that looks right. The nice thing about this tool is that it can be automated to do all kinds of things with logs from syslog, Bro-IDS, Snort, whatever, and then act on the data or like I mentioned above, plot it out for visualization. The one drawback I&amp;rsquo;ve found is that the IPv6 lookups are sparsely correct, for example:&lt;code&gt;
sliver:~ buraglio$ geoiplookup6 2400:cb00:2048:1::681c:194f
sliver:~ buraglio$
&lt;/code&gt;Looking up 2400:cb00:2048:1::681c:194f which belongs to cloudflare yields me nothink, so there is some work to do there on the IPv6 front. Overall this is a useful tool for quick troubleshooting but it really shines when used in scripts and for visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIX4Neteng 4: POODLE and SSLv3, scanning and updating</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nix4neteng-4-poodle-and-sslv3-scanning-and-updating/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 17:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nix4neteng-4-poodle-and-sslv3-scanning-and-updating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the recent release of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openssl.org/~bodo/ssl-poodle.pdf&#34;&gt;POODLE SSLv3 vulnerability&lt;/a&gt;, folks are scrambling around trying to figure out what runs what and where.  Running a handful of things that do SSL, I was obligated, both personally and professionally, to figure out an easy way to drill down and figure out what does what and then fix the vulnerable services.  When there are a lot of devices, this can seem like a daunting task, and it is if you&amp;rsquo;re trying to do it manually.  This is where &lt;a href=&#34;http://nmap.org/&#34;&gt;NMAP&lt;/a&gt; comes into play.  NMAP is an extremely powerful tool for scanning and enumerating your own network, not just a tool for the script kiddies to port scan. Since there is no SSL patch at the time of this writing, and since SSLv3 is old and depricated, it is a good idea to see what services support it and then squish them in favor of TLS 1+.  Thankfully, smarter folks than myself have done most of the legwork for accomplishing this task and written most of it down &lt;a href=&#34;http://nmap.org/nsedoc/scripts/ssl-enum-ciphers.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. NMAP has a wealth of cool scripts and bolt ons that extend it in amazing ways.  To accomplish our tasks we&amp;rsquo;ll ned to do a few things. Install nmap. I ran into issues with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://nmap.org/book/nse-library.html&#34;&gt;nselibs&lt;/a&gt; being incomplete, so I grabbed the source and built it that way as opposed to using yum.```
git clone git@github.com:nmap/nmap.git&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-We then need to build it from source which requires the dev tools:```&#34; data-lang=&#34;We then need to build it from source which requires the dev tools:```&#34;&gt;sudo yum -y groupinstall &amp;#39;Development Tools&amp;#39;
cd nmap
./configure
sudo make&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and alternatively```
sudo make install&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-I like to just run it from my directory since there are path considerations.```&#34; data-lang=&#34;I like to just run it from my directory since there are path considerations.```&#34;&gt;(~/nmap) v-chimera $ ./nmap --script ssl-enum-ciphers -p 443 10.14.14.0/27

Starting Nmap 6.46 ( http://nmap.org ) at 2014-10-15 12:21 CDT
Nmap scan report for gw.test (10.14.14.1)
Host is up (0.0028s latency).
PORT    STATE  SERVICE
443/tcp closed https

Nmap scan report for ssldevice.test (10.14.14.2)
Host is up (0.0042s latency).
PORT    STATE SERVICE
443/tcp open  https
| ssl-enum-ciphers:
|   SSLv3:
|     ciphers:
|       TLS\_RSA\_WITH\_RC4\_128\_MD5 - strong
|       TLS\_RSA\_WITH\_RC4\_128\_SHA - strong
|     compressors:
|       NULL
|   TLSv1.0:
|     ciphers:
|       TLS\_RSA\_WITH\_RC4\_128\_MD5 - strong
|       TLS\_RSA\_WITH\_RC4\_128\_SHA - strong
|     compressors:
|       NULL
|\_  least strength: strong

Nmap scan report for nossl.test (10.14.14.3)
Host is up (0.00049s latency).
PORT    STATE  SERVICE
443/tcp closed https&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here we can see that there is a host that needs to be updated. There are a wealth of docs out there for changing out the supported version. Most of my stuff is apache so I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://zmap.io/sslv3/&#34;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt;. For embedded devices, the best option is to filter access [which you should probably be doing anyway] until there is a patched firmware version.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sonrancid: A [very] basic RANCID module for sonicwall</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/sonrancid-a-very-basic-rancid-module-for-sonicwall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 09:05:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/sonrancid-a-very-basic-rancid-module-for-sonicwall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I know, I know, I&amp;rsquo;m always saying that you don&amp;rsquo;t need a firewall. That&amp;rsquo;s mostly to get your attention to push my agenda of sane security architecture, I do actually believe that firewalls are appropriate in a great many use cases and I&amp;rsquo;ve managed them big and small ranging from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2010/08/juniper-srx-cluster/&#34; title=&#34;Juniper SRX Cluster&#34;&gt;Juniper SRX 5800 clusters&lt;/a&gt; to tiny purpose built BSD distros on custom hardware. I even managed &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.checkpoint.com/&#34;&gt;Checkpoint&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kulichki.com/moshkow/SECURITY/gauntlet.txt&#34;&gt;gauntlet firewall&lt;/a&gt; back in the 1990s. And &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.novell.com/products/bordermanager/&#34;&gt;Novell Border manager&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;.good gravy&amp;hellip;.border manager. I just had a chill, that thing is still around.  They work well when spec&amp;rsquo;d, designed, maintained correctly and placed in an appropriate location in a network architecture.  That said, I have a few SonicWall devices that I work on occasionally and it has always irritated me that there was not a usable &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shrubbery.net/rancid/&#34;&gt;RANCID&lt;/a&gt; module for it.  To that end, I hacked up the Cisco RANCID script to support very rudimentary config backups. &lt;em&gt;&lt;Insert comment about having some DevOps skills is useful, even if they are very basic like mine.&gt;&lt;/em&gt; The script will log in and pull the config and version using the following commands:&lt;code&gt;
show current-config
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;code&gt;
show version
&lt;/code&gt;I am really hoping that someone else will pick it up and massage it a bit because it is very chatty and will produce a diff every time due to the way SonicOS presents some of its configuration parameters. It also needs tested against larger SonicWall devices as I only have smaller boxes to run against.  I know it works against a TZ210, YMMV. Please post comments on github if you use it with anything else.   The password hash is particularly annoying, it always changes when the configuration is displayed. Some of the framework is there to remove it so I may hack at it a bit more but it&amp;rsquo;s usable in the loosest sense for the short term.  It&amp;rsquo;s available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/buraglio/sonrancid&#34;&gt;my github site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you don&#39;t need a firewall [how to secure an open perimeter network]</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/why-you-dont-need-a-firewall-how-to-secure-an-open-perimeter-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 07:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/why-you-dont-need-a-firewall-how-to-secure-an-open-perimeter-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I admit that the title was meant to be inflammatory.  However, there are use cases that aren&amp;rsquo;t terribly uncommon where an in-line security appliance is just not the correct tool for the job.  Someone once told me &amp;ldquo;a firewall protects a network like a fuse protects an electrical circuit&amp;rdquo;, and it&amp;rsquo;s mostly a correct statement. Firewall vendors will probably argue this and enterprise folks may discount this as heresy and call for burning me at the stake.  I can say, though, that the use of a firewall, IPS or other inline security appliance has presented many problems in many environments in my years as a network and security engineer and architect.    To that end, there are mechanisms for replacing the functions of a firewall and IPS with other options, which in many cases have a lower capital expense [although they may have a higher &lt;em&gt;initial&lt;/em&gt; operational expense].  I&amp;rsquo;ll outline them here, but before I do I want to re-iterate that NAT (PAT) is not a security tool, it&amp;rsquo;s a translation tool.  Nothing more.  So, I will leave that out.  If you don&amp;rsquo;t have appropriate IPv4 or IPv6 address space some of these things may need adjustments although they are still accomplishable by doing NAT on a border Layer 3 device.     Below is a talk that I gave at BroCon14 that is a rough outline of how to do this, if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend 30 minutes listening to me talk about it, the clifs notes are bulleted below, but the context is all in the video so I encourage you to watch it before responding to my post. For those that want to take a look, here is the talk. Here are the bullets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Announce only necessary resources &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One can utilize routing to only expose the pieces of the network that need to be exposed.  If you have a /16 and on;y a /24 needs to be exposed, only announce that prefix.  This is not that different than a typical DMZ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Filter access to network, storage and management hardware&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Utilize best practice ingress filtering.  Follow &lt;a href=&#34;http://tools.ietf.org/html/bcp38&#34;&gt;BCP38&lt;/a&gt;. You should be doing this anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Utilize host based firewalls&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a no-brainer.  Firewall as close to the resource as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Employ central host management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make your life easy.  Cloud providers do it and it&amp;rsquo;s well documented nowadays.  There are &lt;a href=&#34;http://cfengine.com/&#34;&gt;many&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://puppetlabs.com/&#34;&gt;options&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Centralize logging and flow data collection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another no brainer, you should be doing this anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create baselines for traffic and activity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data is good.  Knowledge is power.  Baselines are useful for both anomaly detection and forecasting and it&amp;rsquo;s not that hard to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deploy and tune IDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passive IDS system[s] off of a TAP or SPAN are key to this kind of architecture.  See video for more details but there are a bunch of good options. I prefer &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bro.org&#34;&gt;Bro IDS&lt;/a&gt; but there are many players both commercial and FOSS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Filter with black hole routing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2011/10/black-hole-routing/&#34; title=&#34;Black Hole routing&#34;&gt;talked about this before&lt;/a&gt;.  Automating this is key to making it function efficiently and it is a fantastic tool.  This can be done with BGP (traditionally) or with something innovative like OpenFlow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make use of regularly scheduled external vulnerability scanning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a great way to verify your exposure and works for any sized network.  Highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;  Clearly this isn&amp;rsquo;t for everyone, and that&amp;rsquo;s ok.  For anyone that has struggled with issues involving security appliances either based on protocol, horsepower or interface speeds, there are options.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
