<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud on ForwardingPlane.net</title>
    <link>https://forwardingplane.net/tags/cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud on ForwardingPlane.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2019, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 06:52:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://forwardingplane.net/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The NEC surprise</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/the-nec-surprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 06:52:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/the-nec-surprise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href=&#34;http://necam.com/&#34;&gt;NEC&lt;/a&gt; began talking about SDN at &lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/event/nfd9/&#34;&gt;Network Field Day 9&lt;/a&gt;, I was not sure what to expect. I knew they had been heavily involved with openflow since the early days, and many years ago I was able to get my hands on their early OpenFlow controller and was immediately frustrated by its cryptic nature and frankly, poor documentation. Their switches were fine and were heavily utilized in early OpenFlow deployments. I knew they had decent support and were squarely on board the SDN train. Their controller, in 2010, was not terribly fun to work with. It was (if memory serves) prohibitively expensive and the support manual was nearly as cryptic as the controller. Because it&amp;rsquo;s my personality type, I went in with a very open mind, hoping to be surprised. After all, it&amp;rsquo;d been 4+ years since I&amp;rsquo;d seen that controller. Well, I am here to report that I will happily eat some crow. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Eat-Crow.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Eat-Crow.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Eat Crow&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;   A few things became very apparent to me as I sat and watched the presentation from NEC, which you can view in its entirety below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NEC is not messing around with their SDN offering. They&amp;rsquo;ve been in the openflow game since the beginning and the polish on their controller shows it. The topology is quite nice and they&amp;rsquo;ve got a finished looking product that would find itself at home in a decent sized NOC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NEC is playing well with others. Their demo consisted of both NEC and DELL whitebox switches. To me this is an indication of both great forward thinking and a clear message that the controller is a product that can stand on its own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NEC is setting the barrier of entry low. Very low. They&amp;rsquo;ve got an entry level &amp;ldquo;SDN in a box&amp;rdquo; that consists of their controller and a few switches for like 3k. They&amp;rsquo;re also offering a 90 day free trial on their controller that is bundled with &lt;a href=&#34;http://mininet.org/&#34;&gt;mininet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Like most other controllers, the NEC controller is topology aware and using openflow 1.3 for it&amp;rsquo;s communication. Unlike any other demo I&amp;rsquo;ve seen, NEC used CLI to make changes and displayed the updates in near realtime on the controller.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;ve got a tap product aimed at security tap aggregators a la &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gigamon.com/&#34;&gt;gigamon&lt;/a&gt;, so they&amp;rsquo;re seeing the value of SDN and openflow from a security lens as well as a network operations perspective, a good play in my opinion. SDN and openflow in particular have a great deal to offer the security community (think of all of the wacky stuff your security team has asked for and then map that into an openflow network. You&amp;rsquo;ll probably hit 80% match). NEC has done some tight integration with &lt;a href=&#34;https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/windowsserver/dd448604.aspx&#34;&gt;microsoft hyper-v&lt;/a&gt; too, so environments leveraging hyper-v as a virtualization technology can drop this in to take advantage of the network programmability on top of their virtualization environment. This is something that I&amp;rsquo;d not seen before [although it may exist and I just don&amp;rsquo;t know it]. In addition, NEC has spun up an &amp;ldquo;app store&amp;rdquo; for SDN apps and allowed for some cross pollination, with a handful of caveats, with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opendaylight.org/&#34;&gt;opendaylight&lt;/a&gt; for testing. &lt;speculation&gt; There are a few things I find interesting about the NEC offering and about NEC in general. Being in a service provider environment off and on for most of my career, the fact that NEC is getting involved so heavily is intriguing. Unlike most of the other DC focused companies, NEC plays in the carrier market. While this particular briefing did not include any carrier updates, it would surprise me if this wasn&amp;rsquo;t being investigated behind some big doors. It makes sense to me and it would be a surprise if it did not occur to someone else. The SP market is fickle and slow to change, but ripe for fresh ideas. I see a lot of potential both there and in the DC / campus / enterprise. &lt;/speculation&gt;   &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/119508255&#34;&gt;Introduction to NEC Networking&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/sfoskett&#34;&gt;Stephen Foskett&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/119508725&#34;&gt;NEC ProgrammableFlow vCOps Solution&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/sfoskett&#34;&gt;Stephen Foskett&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/119510207&#34;&gt;ProgrammableFlow SCVMM Demo&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/sfoskett&#34;&gt;Stephen Foskett&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Field Day 9</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/network-field-day-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 15:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/network-field-day-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ll have the opportunity to participate in another &lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/event/nfd9/&#34;&gt;Network Field Day&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve been lucky enough to have the opportunity to attend&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2014/02/network-field-day-7/&#34; title=&#34;Network Field Day 7&#34;&gt; in the past&lt;/a&gt; and have done some &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2013/03/network-field-day-5/&#34; title=&#34;Network Field Day 5 – Participate Remotely&#34;&gt;remote participation&lt;/a&gt; when possible, but like some of the other rare &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2012/11/scinet-a-privileged-few/&#34; title=&#34;SCinet, a privileged few&#34;&gt;opportunities&lt;/a&gt; I have had in my career, NFD is fairly unique in that it is constantly evolving in both the information provided and the individuals involved. As the saying goes, variety is the spice of life. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly excited about the presentations and have been looking forward to talking to a few of the participant companies for a while. There is a tight line up for NFD9, but I am very intrigued as I am either unfamiliar or have been looking for more information about several of them for quite some time now. &lt;a href=&#34;http://netbeez.net/&#34;&gt;NetBeez&lt;/a&gt; is  an interesting one, they provide a service not unlike a project I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with for years called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.perfsonar.net/&#34;&gt;perfSonar&lt;/a&gt;. The data that these kind of projects provide is absolutely invaluable, so I&amp;rsquo;m very interested in NetBeez and how they&amp;rsquo;re accomplishing their tasks and presenting their data. I met with and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2014/04/blending-the-network-pluribus-serverswitch/&#34;&gt;wrote about&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pluribusnetworks.com/&#34;&gt;Pluribus Networks&lt;/a&gt; at (and around the time of) &lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/event/nfd7/&#34;&gt;NFD7&lt;/a&gt;. I was impressed then and I&amp;rsquo;m impressed now. I see a great value in what they&amp;rsquo;re doing for so many practical applications and am very anxious to see what they&amp;rsquo;ve added, changed or tweaked since our last meeting roughly a year ago. &lt;a href=&#34;http://cumulusnetworks.com/&#34;&gt;Cumulus networks&lt;/a&gt; is another one I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to get lab time with since they came out. I am looking forward to having them in a room, they&amp;rsquo;re doing something to networking that, like Pluribus, is pretty unique and arguably game changing. At then end of the day, though, the best part of this is not that there are a few interesting topics, it is the fact that all of the topics and players are unique, top shelf and potentially game changing. It&amp;rsquo;s essentially an all star lineup (again) with the likes of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brocade.com&#34;&gt;Brocade&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.solarwinds.com/&#34;&gt;Solarwinds&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nec.com&#34;&gt;NEC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.velocloud.com/&#34;&gt;VeloCloud&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cloudgenix.com/&#34;&gt;Cloudgenix&lt;/a&gt;. This entire line up is right up my alley, as a large number of them are WAN or SDN oriented, which is where I spend the majority of my normal working days. In addition to all of that, I&amp;rsquo;ll finally get to meet &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/networkingnerd&#34;&gt;NetworkingNerd&lt;/a&gt; in real life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Tech Predictions for 2013</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/random-tech-predictions-for-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 19:39:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/random-tech-predictions-for-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a love-hate feeling about &amp;ldquo;predictions&amp;rdquo; about the upcoming year, especially tech predictions.  I don&amp;rsquo;t like media sensationalism of any kind, and a lot of the tech predctions are just that, sensational, extreme talk to draw in readers or viewers.  I&amp;rsquo;m choosing to go down a more subtle path, these are things I&amp;rsquo;ve thought about lately but will likely forget in the upcoming year, unless they actually happen, in which case I&amp;rsquo;d likely do an &amp;ldquo;ah, I remember thinking that may happen&amp;rdquo; gesture.  Additionally, many of these things are well underway already, but I have a mind like a FIFO pipe, so I&amp;rsquo;m gonna write them down here to remember to go back and look at them in a few months.  They&amp;rsquo;re sort of a mixed bag of stuff, in no particular order. Lets call these, &amp;ldquo;plausible but not necessarily inevitable; possibly already happening&amp;rdquo;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/crystal-ball.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/crystal-ball.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;crystal-ball&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 1. Google buys or invests in a mobile carrier.  I was thinking Sprint, but T-Mobile makes more sense because of their GSM network and more global compatibility.  Thins kind of thing has been proposed many times over the last few years and it still makes sense. 2.  Apple buys or invests in Twitter.  This makes a lot of sense to me and would solidify their place in the social networking arena. 3. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aristanetworks.com&#34;&gt;Arista Networks &lt;/a&gt; moves into a larger data center and cloud computing role.  I see big things for this company. they have a very solid pedigree, have an innovative business model and a &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; compelling product.   Which leads me to #4. 4. Talks of larger companies (Cisco, Juniper, Dell, Google) purchasing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aristanetworks.com&#34;&gt;Arista Networks&lt;/a&gt;.  This hapens to many of the very innnovative companies.  Remember &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Procket_Networks&#34;&gt;Procket&lt;/a&gt;?  Yeah, most folks don&amp;rsquo;t.  I had the same thoughts about them.  cisco purchased, absorbed and buried them.  I believe their routing pieces were shoved into the nexus. 5. SDN controllers become more mainstream.  BigSwitch stands more or less unchallenged in the commercial controller space and has done it right.  Seed the opensource community and make a commercial product for those that want it (i.e. businesses that need support, don&amp;rsquo;t want to deal with code).  It makes sense to me that this become a big market in the next few years, and next year will likely be the mad dash.  I expect to see SDN controllers from big names and hopefully some start ups. 6. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.plexxi.com&#34;&gt;Plexxi&lt;/a&gt; starts to become a more well known name.  They&amp;rsquo;ve got a really cool product and a unique and innovative feature set.  I also wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised if a big name tried to buy them. 7. More and more &amp;ldquo;Ethernet Fabric&amp;rdquo; products emerge.  This is the new marketing favorite son and there are &lt;a href=&#34;http://gnodal.com&#34;&gt;many&lt;/a&gt; new players here.  Sprinkle in SDN and &amp;ldquo;Cloud&amp;rdquo;, shake with &amp;ldquo;data center&amp;rdquo; and you&amp;rsquo;ve got a buzzword cocktail worthy of a king. 8. Productized optical (WDM) SDN starts to mature and become available. This is already happening in he background and on the periphery. 9. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crn.com/news/networking/240007827/microsoft-confirms-more-details-of-lync-skype-integration.htm&#34;&gt;Skype is integrated into MS Lync&lt;/a&gt;.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think this is really unexpected or a surprise at all since it&amp;rsquo;s been announced.  I think it&amp;rsquo;ll happen in 2013, though. 10.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openstack.org&#34;&gt;OpenStack&lt;/a&gt; starts taking a more publicized role in production cloud computing.  This is sort of inevitable and obvious, I think, and it&amp;rsquo;s already starting to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
