<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ForwardingPlane.net</title>
    <link>https://forwardingplane.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ForwardingPlane.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2019, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 18:11:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://forwardingplane.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Packet Pushers Weekend Edition Number 1</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/packet-pushers-weekend-edition-no1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 18:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/packet-pushers-weekend-edition-no1/</guid>
      <description>We all know the Packet Pushers. Recently, I had the pleasure of sitting in on the inagural &amp;ldquo;Packet Pushers Weekend Edition&amp;rdquo; - an informal, video round table where we discuss fun and relevant topics in the space of networking and other related IT topics. Much discussion was had on SR-MPLS, Service providers, SD-WAN, and Cloud. I hope to participate again, as I found the experience both entertaining and informative, I hope you will too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ElastiFlow Template VM</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/elastiflow-template-vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 18:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/elastiflow-template-vm/</guid>
      <description>Flow data is a critical piece of understanding how your network works what what it is actively doing. It also provides a great baseline and capacity planning tool. However, some of the more feature rich NetFlow and/or sFlow collectors can be quite daunting in their cost and/or complexity to install. ElastiFlow is a great alternative for flow analytics and is built on the well traveled and robust ElasticStack, meaning, its back end is well documented, well supported, and scales exceptionally well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic automation for WISPs and small to medium ISPs</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/basic-automation-for-wisps-and-small-to-medium-isps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 09:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/basic-automation-for-wisps-and-small-to-medium-isps/</guid>
      <description>Small to medium ISPs are an interesting phenomenon. Early in my career I was pretty heavily involved in that space, so much of my current thought processes and methodologies are heavily informed by that experience. Something that never ceases to amaze me today is that the practice of scripting and “automating” things seems to have become somewhat of a lost art, or at the very least it is not part of an initial deployment plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The BGP conundrum</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/the-bgp-conundrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 02:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/the-bgp-conundrum/</guid>
      <description>BGP. It’s that magical protocol that runs the internet. For for as much as BGP is a fundamental, critical, irreplaceable part of the core functioning of the internet, it is a protocol that has not aged well as far as security is concerned. See, BGP was born when the internet was really still an academic experiment. Handshakes and loose agreements were totally fine for connecting a new site. Then came the awakening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a dynamic security infrastructure [in a box - with SDN]</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/building-a-dynamic-security-infrastructure-in-a-box-with-sdn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 18:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/building-a-dynamic-security-infrastructure-in-a-box-with-sdn/</guid>
      <description>Years ago I wrote about building a secure network in a box. Over a weekend I decided to revisit this concept thanks to a colleague at work wanting to do something similar. It got me thinking “a lot has changed since I last did this” and it felt like time to revisit it. Well, disappointment wasn’t in the cards because it’s easier, smarter, and more flexible now that it was back then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renaming interfaces under linux</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/renaming-interfaces-under-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 07:23:50 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/renaming-interfaces-under-linux/</guid>
      <description>There are many of us that learned Linux in the very early days, and with that history comes habits. One habit I have is to look for spec interface names. In particular, I prefer to have my interfaces named eth* (with some notables exceptions here). Modern linux systems seem to have adopted the BSD methodology of naming the interfaces based on what it is &amp;#8211; and while I did do a fair amount of work in BSD, I still prefer the eth naming scheme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renaming interfaces under linux</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/renaming-interfaces-under-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 13:23:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/renaming-interfaces-under-linux/</guid>
      <description>There are many of us that learned Linux in the very early days, and with that history comes habits. One habit I have is to look for spec interface names. In particular, I prefer to have my interfaces named eth* (with some notables exceptions here). Modern linux systems seem to have adopted the BSD methodology of naming the interfaces based on what it is - and while I did do a fair amount of work in BSD, I still prefer the eth naming scheme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rant: toolexplodeaphobia</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1672/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 13:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1672/</guid>
      <description>It’s kinda like having RouteExplorer and Arbor Peakflow. They have a decent overlap but *just* enough difference to want both</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The value of measurements: Network Latency</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/the-value-of-measurements-network-latency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 10:23:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/the-value-of-measurements-network-latency/</guid>
      <description>There is no shortage of network telemetry data that can be collected, recorded, graphed, and stored for cross reference and triage. Not one to be underestimated, latency at a can be incredibly powerful when leveraged for baseline and deviation notification. As I have eluded to in the past, there are many tools in this space. I have written about a few of them in detail and touched on others in passing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soap Box: Mikrotik &#34;IPv6 Apocalypse&#34;, or maybe not.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/soap-box-mikrotik-ipv6-apocalypse-or-maybe-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 17:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/soap-box-mikrotik-ipv6-apocalypse-or-maybe-not/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few days there has been a huge amount of FUD and panic surrounding two as-yet-to-be-published CVEs (found here and here) related to Mikrotik&amp;rsquo;s IPv6 implementation.It is my opinion that this entire process has been poorly handled, and that the community involved tends to be fairly sensitive to issues such as, and the cloak and dagger nature of the two issues has only exacerbated it. Mikrotik, as a company, is well known for being terse in their responses and tight lipped with their internal workings and dealings with these kinds of issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISC dhcp and dhcpv6 relay</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/dhcp-and-dhcpv6-relay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 10:00:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/dhcp-and-dhcpv6-relay/</guid>
      <description>When deploying dual stack, dhcpv6 is a crucial piece of the puzzle. I personally prefer to run the dhcp process on a linux system and relay it for both v4 and v6. Assuming you are installing isc-dhcpd, the following configurations can be used to delegate host addresses for both IPv4 and IPv6
 #
# Sample configuration file for ISC dhcpd for Debian / Ubuntu
# Examples provided without support by buraglio@forwardingplane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISC dhcp and dhcpv6 relay</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/dhcp-and-dhcpv6-relay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 16:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/dhcp-and-dhcpv6-relay/</guid>
      <description>When deploying dual stack, dhcpv6 is a crucial piece of the puzzle. I personally prefer to run the dhcp process on a linux system and relay it for both v4 and v6. Assuming you are installing isc-dhcpd, the following configurations can be used to delegate host addresses for both IPv4 and IPv6
# \# Sample configuration file for ISC dhcpd for Debian / Ubuntu \# Examples provided without support by buraglio@forwardingplane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling LLDP</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/enabling-lldp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 20:00:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/enabling-lldp/</guid>
      <description>Enabling LLDP can aid in understanding network and system topologies, I am very much in favor of running it and largely dismiss the perceived security issues surrounding it, when done correctly and with full knowledge of what it is being enabled.
Enable LLDP on a SROS based Nokia (formerly Alcatel-Lucent). It is per physical port, so replace 1/1/1 with your physical port and replicate on every port you want it to run on</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling LLDP</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/enabling-lldp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 02:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/enabling-lldp/</guid>
      <description>Enabling LLDP can aid in understanding network and system topologies, I am very much in favor of running it and largely dismiss the perceived security issues surrounding it, when done correctly and with full knowledge of what it is being enabled.
Enable LLDP on a SROS based Nokia (formerly Alcatel-Lucent). It is per physical port, so replace 1/1/1 with your physical port and replicate on every port you want it to run on</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FreeRouter as a test environment</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/freertr-as-a-lab-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 17:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/freertr-as-a-lab-environment/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago Kevin Myers of IP Architechs introduced me to a really interesting project called FreeRouter. Being that I absolutely love alternative routing platforms and feature complete simulation environments, this really got me going. I tend to define &amp;ldquo;feature complete&amp;rdquo; in a routing platform as something that can do both IS-IS and MPLS. Given that there aren&amp;rsquo;t many platforms that do both correctly or within a reasonable budget, and offer simulation options, I was pretty excited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FreeRTR basic configurations</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/freertr-basic-configurations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 11:00:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/freertr-basic-configurations/</guid>
      <description>From the freertr website:
freeRouter is a free, open source router os process
it speaks routing protocols, and (re)encapsulates packets on interfaces (a huge list of encapsulation and routing test cases can be found under self-test page)since it handles packets itself, it is independent of underlaying os capabilities(optionally, it can export forwarding tables through openflow to external switch)since it is an unprivilegized process, it receives and sends packets through socketsthere are external, privileged processes that place traffic to these sockets(it means that internet can be used as backplane for router processes) the command line tries to mimic the industry standards with one exception: no global routing table: every routedinterface must be in a virtual routing table positive side effect: there are no vrf-awareness questions As notes in my FreeRTR post, FreeRTR is a wonderful alternative to labbing up protocols and provides an incredible array of protocol support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FreeRTR basic configurations</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/freertr-basic-configurations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 17:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/freertr-basic-configurations/</guid>
      <description>From the freertr website:
freeRouter is a free, open source router os process it speaks routing protocols, and (re)encapsulates packets on interfaces (a huge list of encapsulation and routing test cases can be found under self-test page)since it handles packets itself, it is independent of underlaying os capabilities(optionally, it can export forwarding tables through openflow to external switch)since it is an unprivilegized process, it receives and sends packets through socketsthere are external, privileged processes that place traffic to these sockets(it means that internet can be used as backplane for router processes) the command line tries to mimic the industry standards with one exception: no global routing table: every routedinterface must be in a virtual routing table positive side effect: there are no vrf-awareness questions  As notes in my FreeRTR post, FreeRTR is a wonderful alternative to labbing up protocols and provides an incredible array of protocol support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable Telnet access on MacOS High Sierra</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/enable-telnet-access-on-macos-high-sierra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 10:11:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/enable-telnet-access-on-macos-high-sierra/</guid>
      <description>Lots of things changed under the hood in MacOS high sierra. One of those was to enable a sandbox like environment and to remove insecure communication protocols. This breaks things like console communication to the network modeling and virtualization platform Eve-NG. It&amp;#8217;s fairly trivial to re-enable it, however. This can be accomplished by doing the following steps.
Install Homebrew. Open your favorite terminal application (I like to use iTerm2 (also installable via homebrew), but Terminal works fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable Telnet access on MacOS High Sierra</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/enable-telnet-access-on-macos-high-sierra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 16:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/enable-telnet-access-on-macos-high-sierra/</guid>
      <description>Lots of things changed under the hood in MacOS high sierra. One of those was to enable a sandbox like environment and to remove insecure communication protocols. This breaks things like console communication to the network modeling and virtualization platform Eve-NG. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly trivial to re-enable it, however. This can be accomplished by doing the following steps.
Install Homebrew. Open your favorite terminal application (I like to use iTerm2 (also installable via homebrew), but Terminal works fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic IOS-XR command cheat sheet</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/basic-ios-xr-command-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 14:05:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/basic-ios-xr-command-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>Some basic commands that I have found useful in managing an ASR9K / IOS-XR device. This page is likely to grow and change over time.
Clear ARP
clear arp-cache &amp;lt;interface&amp;gt; &amp;lt;IPv4 addr&amp;gt; location all  BGP
show bgp all unicast summary  BGP Routes
show bgp ipv[4/6] unicast neighbors &amp;lt;neighbor&amp;gt; received route
show bgp ipv[4/6] unicast advertised neighbor &amp;lt;neighbor&amp;gt; show bgp ipv[4/6] unicast summary
show bgp ipv[4/6] unicast summary
clear bgp ipv[4/6] unicast &amp;lt;neighbor&amp;gt; soft in</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic IOS-XR command cheat sheet</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/basic-ios-xr-command-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 20:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/basic-ios-xr-command-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>Some basic commands that I have found useful in managing an ASR9K / IOS-XR device. This page is likely to grow and change over time.
Clear ARP
clear arp-cache &amp;lt;interface&amp;gt; &amp;lt;IPv4 addr&amp;gt; location all  BGP
show bgp all unicast summary  BGP Routes
 show bgp ipv\[4/6\] unicast neighbors &amp;lt;neighbor&amp;gt; received route show bgp ipv\[4/6\] unicast advertised neighbor &amp;lt;neighbor&amp;gt; show bgp ipv\[4/6\] unicast summary show bgp ipv\[4/6\] unicast summary clear bgp ipv\[4/6\] unicast &amp;lt;neighbor&amp;gt; soft in show bgp all unicast summary show bgp ipv\[4/6\] unicast bestpath-compare  NetFlow</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade Single ASR9k hw-module</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/upgrade-an-asr9k-hardware-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 13:58:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/upgrade-an-asr9k-hardware-module/</guid>
      <description>ASR9k is a powerful device but management may be daunting to anyone not familiar with IOS-XR. Inserting new line cards in may require a manual upgrade of the module to match the current running code on the chassis
Show all slow and firmware details:
show hw-module fpd location rack/slot/subslot In the admin prompt:
upgrade hw-module fpd all location 0/RSP1/CPU0 During the upgrade, this is the output, it will take a bit of time to perform the update.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade Single ASR9k hw-module</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/upgrade-an-asr9k-hardware-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 19:58:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/upgrade-an-asr9k-hardware-module/</guid>
      <description>ASR9k is a powerful device but management may be daunting to anyone not familiar with IOS-XR. Inserting new line cards in may require a manual upgrade of the module to match the current running code on the chassis
Show all slow and firmware details:
show hw-module fpd location _rack/slot/subslot_  In the admin prompt:
upgrade hw-module fpd all location 0/RSP1/CPU0  During the upgrade, this is the output, it will take a bit of time to perform the update.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nokia SROS useful commands</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/nokia-sros-useful-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 08:30:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/nokia-sros-useful-commands/</guid>
      <description>Nokia (formerly Alcatel-Lucent, formerly Timetra) have an extremely robust routing platform, but it has some notable differences if you&amp;#8217;re coming from a vendor such as Cisco or Juniper (or any vendor platform in the enterprise space, really). Things like &amp;#8220;VLANs&amp;#8221; don&amp;#8217;t really exist, as this is more of a metro / carrier / customer provisioning style device, so modular concepts are expected and baked into the OS at the deepest layers, unlike many of the other vendor platforms that support it but it feels like an add-in or addendum to the base routing instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nokia SROS useful commands</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nokia-sros-useful-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 14:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nokia-sros-useful-commands/</guid>
      <description>Nokia (formerly Alcatel-Lucent, formerly Timetra) have an extremely robust routing platform, but it has some notable differences if you&amp;rsquo;re coming from a vendor such as Cisco or Juniper (or any vendor platform in the enterprise space, really). Things like &amp;ldquo;VLANs&amp;rdquo; don&amp;rsquo;t really exist, as this is more of a metro / carrier / customer provisioning style device, so modular concepts are expected and baked into the OS at the deepest layers, unlike many of the other vendor platforms that support it but it feels like an add-in or addendum to the base routing instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mikrotik OpenVPN server</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/mikrotik-openvpn-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 14:14:40 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/mikrotik-openvpn-example/</guid>
      <description>Mikrotik is one of my favorite routing and MPLS platforms for doing lab and small ISP work. This one is pretty darned easy if you&amp;#8217;re willing to use self-signed certificates, and pretty trivial to add legitimate certificates if you are so inclined.
/certificate add name=ca common-name=ca key-usage=key-cert-sign,crl-sign
/certificate sign ca ca-crl-host=10.255.255.4 name=ca
/certificate export-certificate ca
/certificate add name=gw-dsl common-name=gw.yourcompany.com
/certificate add name=vpnclient1 common-name=client1
/certificate sign gw-dsl ca=ca name=gw.yourcompany.com
/certificate sign vpnclient1 ca=ca name=client1 /ip pool add name=ovpn-pool range=10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mikrotik OpenVPN server</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/mikrotik-openvpn-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 20:14:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/mikrotik-openvpn-example/</guid>
      <description>Mikrotik is one of my favorite routing and MPLS platforms for doing lab and small ISP work. This one is pretty darned easy if you&amp;rsquo;re willing to use self-signed certificates, and pretty trivial to add legitimate certificates if you are so inclined.
/certificate add name=ca common-name=ca key-usage=key-cert-sign,crl-sign /certificate sign ca ca-crl-host=10.255.255.4 name=ca /certificate export-certificate ca /certificate add name=gw-dsl common-name=gw.yourcompany.com /certificate add name=vpnclient1 common-name=client1 /certificate sign gw-dsl ca=ca name=gw.yourcompany.com /certificate sign vpnclient1 ca=ca name=client1 /ip pool add name=ovpn-pool range=10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EdgeOS OpenVPN</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/edgeos-openvpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 14:05:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/edgeos-openvpn/</guid>
      <description>OpenVPN is a great technology but can be a bit of a bear to configure. A large part of the complexity with OpenVPN is the certificates, many are put off my them and for good reason. They can be confusing and hard to follow. The certificates can be generated off box pretty easily and that&amp;#8217;s how I tend to do it. This configuration should work on both EdgeMAX and Unifi USG devices, although the latter will require some additional work to make it persist across provisioning events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EdgeOS OpenVPN</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/edgeos-openvpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 20:05:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/edgeos-openvpn/</guid>
      <description>OpenVPN is a great technology but can be a bit of a bear to configure. A large part of the complexity with OpenVPN is the certificates, many are put off my them and for good reason. They can be confusing and hard to follow. The certificates can be generated off box pretty easily and that&amp;rsquo;s how I tend to do it. This configuration should work on both EdgeMAX and Unifi USG devices, although the latter will require some additional work to make it persist across provisioning events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mikrotik IPv6 DHCPv6-PD configuration</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/mikrotik-ipv6-dhcpv6-pd-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 13:26:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/mikrotik-ipv6-dhcpv6-pd-configuration/</guid>
      <description>For a small to medium ISPs (especially WISPs) looking to move to IPv6 dual-stack, the right way to deploy is to use DHCPv6 prefix delegation. Here is an example of how to do this in-skin (i.e. on the mikrotik itself rather than a relay).
/ipv6 dhcp-server
add address-pool=vl100-v6-pd-pool interface=ether5.100 name=vl100-v6-pd
add address-pool=vl101-v6-pd-pool interface=ether3.101 name=vl101-v6-pd
add address-pool=vl102-v6-pd-pool interface=ether2.102 name=vl102-v6-pd
add address-pool=vl106-v6-pd-pool interface=ether1.106 name=vl106-v6-pd
add address-pool=vl108-v6-pd-pool interface=ether4.108 name=vl108-v6-pd /ipv6 pool
add comment=&#34;VLAN103 IPv6 prefix delegation pool&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mikrotik IPv6 DHCPv6-PD configuration</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/mikrotik-ipv6-dhcpv6-pd-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 19:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/mikrotik-ipv6-dhcpv6-pd-configuration/</guid>
      <description>For a small to medium ISPs (especially WISPs) looking to move to IPv6 dual-stack, the right way to deploy is to use DHCPv6 prefix delegation. Here is an example of how to do this in-skin (i.e. on the mikrotik itself rather than a relay).
/ipv6 dhcp-server add address-pool=vl100-v6-pd-pool interface=ether5.100 name=vl100-v6-pd add address-pool=vl101-v6-pd-pool interface=ether3.101 name=vl101-v6-pd add address-pool=vl102-v6-pd-pool interface=ether2.102 name=vl102-v6-pd add address-pool=vl106-v6-pd-pool interface=ether1.106 name=vl106-v6-pd add address-pool=vl108-v6-pd-pool interface=ether4.108 name=vl108-v6-pd `````` /ipv6 pool add comment=&amp;quot;VLAN103 IPv6 prefix delegation pool&amp;quot; name=vl103-v6-pd-pool prefix=2001:db8:1a:b000::/48 prefix-length=59 add comment=&amp;quot;VLAN100 IPv6 prefix delegation pool&amp;quot; name=vl100-v6-pd-pool prefix=2001:db8:1a:8800::/48 prefix-length=59 add comment=&amp;quot;VLAN101 IPv6 prefix delegation pool&amp;quot; name=vl101-v6-pd-pool prefix=2001:db8:1a:9000::/48 prefix-length=59 add comment=&amp;quot;VLAN106 IPv6 prefix delegation pool&amp;quot; name=vl106-v6-pd-pool prefix=2001:db8:1a:9800::/48 prefix-length=59 add comment=&amp;quot;VLAN108 IPv6 prefix delegation pool&amp;quot; name=vl108-v6-pd-pool prefix=2001:db8:1a:a000::/48 prefix-length=59 add comment=&amp;quot;VLAN102 IPv6 prefix delegation pool&amp;quot; name=vl102-v6-pd-pool prefix=2001:db8:1a:a800::/48 prefix-length=59 `````` /ipv6 address add address=2001:db8:1a:103::1 disabled=yes interface=bridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comcast Business IPv6 Prefix Delegation</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/comcast-business-ipv6-prefix-delegation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:58:29 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/comcast-business-ipv6-prefix-delegation/</guid>
      <description>Comcast Business class service has some quirks when using the Cisco branded business gateway. Essentially, the prefix delegation will not work without very specific configuration options on the client. In order to run your own network border (i.e. not using their device as the first hop router for your LAN(s)), the following is required. In addition, with static IP addresses also comes with a static IPv6 prefix delegation.
For Ubiquity EdgeOS (or a derivative like a Unifi USG) the following needs to be set (eth2 is the port facing the comcast router)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comcast Business IPv6 Prefix Delegation</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/comcast-business-ipv6-prefix-delegation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 18:58:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/comcast-business-ipv6-prefix-delegation/</guid>
      <description>Comcast Business class service has some quirks when using the Cisco branded business gateway. Essentially, the prefix delegation will not work without very specific configuration options on the client. In order to run your own network border (i.e. not using their device as the first hop router for your LAN(s)), the following is required. In addition, with static IP addresses also comes with a static IPv6 prefix delegation.
For Ubiquity EdgeOS (or a derivative like a Unifi USG) the following needs to be set (eth2 is the port facing the comcast router)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mikrotik Routed VLANs (non-CRS)</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/mikrotik-routed-vlans-non-crs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 11:57:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/mikrotik-routed-vlans-non-crs/</guid>
      <description>Add a simple set of VLANs to a CCR or other non-CRS RouterBoard.
/interface vlan add interface=sfpplus1 name=sfpplus1.4 vlan-id=4 comment=&#34;VLAN ID 4&#34;
add interface=sfpplus1 name=sfpplus1.5 vlan-id=5 comment=&#34;VLAN ID 5&#34;
add interface=sfpplus1 name=sfpplus1.6 vlan-id=6 comment=&#34;VLAN ID 6&#34;
add interface=sfpplus1 name=sfpplus1.7 vlan-id=7 comment=&#34;VLAN ID 7&#34;
add interface=sfpplus1 name=sfpplus1.8 vlan-id=8 comment=&#34;VLAN ID 8&#34;
add interface=sfpplus1 name=sfpplus1.9 vlan-id=9 comment=&#34;VLAN ID 9&#34; Add IP addressing to each VLAN
/ipv6 address add address=2001:db8:c33e:f0::1/64 advertise=no
add address=2001:db8:c:f4::1/64 advertise=yes interface=sfpplus1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mikrotik Routed VLANs (non-CRS)</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/mikrotik-routed-vlans-non-crs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 17:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/mikrotik-routed-vlans-non-crs/</guid>
      <description>Add a simple set of VLANs to a CCR or other non-CRS RouterBoard.
/interface vlan add interface=sfpplus1 name=sfpplus1.4 vlan-id=4 comment=&amp;quot;VLAN ID 4&amp;quot; add interface=sfpplus1 name=sfpplus1.5 vlan-id=5 comment=&amp;quot;VLAN ID 5&amp;quot; add interface=sfpplus1 name=sfpplus1.6 vlan-id=6 comment=&amp;quot;VLAN ID 6&amp;quot; add interface=sfpplus1 name=sfpplus1.7 vlan-id=7 comment=&amp;quot;VLAN ID 7&amp;quot; add interface=sfpplus1 name=sfpplus1.8 vlan-id=8 comment=&amp;quot;VLAN ID 8&amp;quot; add interface=sfpplus1 name=sfpplus1.9 vlan-id=9 comment=&amp;quot;VLAN ID 9&amp;quot;  Add IP addressing to each VLAN
/ipv6 address add address=2001:db8:c33e:f0::1/64 advertise=no add address=2001:db8:c:f4::1/64 advertise=yes interface=sfpplus1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EdgeOS weighted load balance</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/edgeos-weighted-load-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 11:37:39 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/edgeos-weighted-load-balance/</guid>
      <description>set load-balance group LoadBalance_WAN interface route-test initial-delay 15
set load-balance group LoadBalance_WAN interface route-test interval 5
set load-balance group LoadBalance_WAN interface route-test type ping target set load-balance group LoadBalance_WAN interface weight 95 # weight based on more bandwidth set load-balance group LoadBalance_WAN interface route-test initial-delay 15
set load-balance group LoadBalance_WAN interface route-test interval 5
set load-balance group LoadBalance_WAN interface route-test type ping target set load-balance group LoadBalance_WAN interface weight 5 # weight based on less bandwidth Share this:   Twitter  Email  Print  LinkedIn  Facebook  Reddit  Tumblr  Pinterest  Pocket       </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EdgeOS weighted load balance</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/edgeos-weighted-load-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 17:37:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/edgeos-weighted-load-balance/</guid>
      <description>set load-balance group LoadBalance\_WAN interface route-test initial-delay 15 set load-balance group LoadBalance\_WAN interface route-test interval 5 set load-balance group LoadBalance\_WAN interface route-test type ping target set load-balance group LoadBalance\_WAN interface weight 95 # weight based on more bandwidth set load-balance group LoadBalance\_WAN interface route-test initial-delay 15 set load-balance group LoadBalance\_WAN interface route-test interval 5 set load-balance group LoadBalance\_WAN interface route-test type ping target set load-balance group LoadBalance\_WAN interface weight 5 # weight based on less bandwidth  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration Archive</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/configuration-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 16:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/configuration-archive/</guid>
      <description>This section contains various configuration examples that I have built or found otherwise useful.
[child_pages]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eve-NG on proxmox for network virtualization</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1575/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 15:03:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1575/</guid>
      <description>CPU type “host” for proper nested virtualization
https://pve.proxmox.com/wiki/Nested_Virtualization
Converting images
qemu-img convert -f vmdk -O qcow2 vmx-nested-18.2R1.9-4.vmdk vmx-18.2R1.9-4/hda.qcow2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal Faucet Graphs</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/home-openflow-faucet-graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 21:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/home-openflow-faucet-graphs/</guid>
      <description>OpenFlow statistics from my home installation powered by a 48 port, PoE Allied Telesis x930 and a minimal linux container running Faucet. This installation runs my home, my home office, and my rack of lab gear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv6 Q&amp;A for ISPs</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ipv6-qa-for-isps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 01:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ipv6-qa-for-isps/</guid>
      <description>As a follow on to my post on why small to medium ISPs should deploy IPv6 and the associated APNIC blog post, I have begun to compile a list of commonly asked questions IPv6 and their answers in relation to how a small to medium sized ISP can (and should) deploy IPv6. Expect this list to change and grow over time. -&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;
Q: Is there DHCP in IPv6? 
-&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNS - the treasure trove of information your ISP can see</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/dns-the-treasure-trove-of-information-your-isp-can-see/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 10:23:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/dns-the-treasure-trove-of-information-your-isp-can-see/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, the nature of privacy on the internet has become a very important topic amongst those concerned with the now lack of net neutrality. The de-facto mechanism for dealing with privacy has been to &amp;ldquo;SSL all the things&amp;rdquo;, which I am very much in favor of. What many do not realize, though, is that simply using SSL for the traffic that transits a given ISP still leaves a wealth of thick, rich, delicious personal data still easily available to your ISP to harvest, sell, and do with as they please.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faucet: Enterprise OpenFlow in production</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/faucet-enterprise-openflow-in-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 10:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/faucet-enterprise-openflow-in-production/</guid>
      <description>Remember OpenFlow? It was the media and marketing darling for the better part of 5 years as “the machine” conflated OpenFlow with SDN and SDN with - almost literally - everything. &amp;ldquo;Still Does Nothing&amp;rdquo; was a common phrase uttered around those of us that had run large scale, complex networks for a long time. Quietly, and mostly, out of the fickle media and blogosphere eye, a scrappy little SDN project called faucet has been diligently plugging away &amp;ndash; making easy to use, production quality, well documented, and very stable code that runs OpenFlow networks quite happily in production and at scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDoS mitigation podcast, black hole routing</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ddos-mitigation-podcast-black-hole-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 10:53:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ddos-mitigation-podcast-black-hole-routing/</guid>
      <description>As an often-security-engineer and an individual that has been working on large networks for quite a while, dealing with DDoS, or the threat of DDoS is a well traveled path. Recently I was invited to discuss some of the basics of DDoS mitigation on the Network Collective Podcast. This was a really fun and insightful chat with a wealth of great information for engineers and operators of any skill level. Ep38 - DDoS Mitigation from Network Collective on Vimeo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The rush to automation and the IT pendulum</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/the-rush-to-automation-and-the-it-pendulum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 14:20:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/the-rush-to-automation-and-the-it-pendulum/</guid>
      <description>Recently, the venerable Ivan Pepelnjak published a very insightful article about automation becoming such a popular topic that was spawned by an email from one of his readers. I found this article to be spot on, and wanted to add a bit of my own opinion into the automation pie, as I have been spending a lot of time on automation as it related to existing networks as well as into SDN based environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As a small to medium ISP, why you should deploy IPv6</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/as-a-small-to-medium-isp-why-you-should-deploy-ipv6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 16:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/as-a-small-to-medium-isp-why-you-should-deploy-ipv6/</guid>
      <description>IPv6 has been a crusade of mine for well over a decade. Wether it is teaching IPv6 workshops, offering advice to new users, answering questions, or evangelizing it ad nauseam, it is an important topic to me. The ISP world holds a special place in my heart since a good deal of my early experience came from building or assisting regional ISPs. Recently I had a fun opportunity to talk about deploying IPv6 on The Brothers WISP podcast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trouble with Tribbles .....errr NAT</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/trouble-with-tribbles-errr-nat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 10:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/trouble-with-tribbles-errr-nat/</guid>
      <description>As a follow up to my last post, I wanted to dive a little deeper into the world of address translation and to suss out some of the more compelling details.
As I&amp;rsquo;ve said on many occasions, it pains me to see NAT referenced as a security mechanism. That said, where PNAT can be beneficial is in an overall privacy strategy, however, even that is comparatively low value and given the current state of global IPv4 allocations, arguably a detriment to usability - we’ll get to that - before we do, it is important to understand what ’NAT” as we call it today actually is, and to do that we need to explain all of the types of address translation (yes, there are several).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAT discussions, fact checking, and debate</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nat-discussions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 09:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nat-discussions/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been very vocal about the misinterpretation of NAT for many, many years. Since it&amp;rsquo;s inception, NAT has been slowly perverted into what many now believe to be a security mechanism. While I do see a reasonable use of IP masquerading in a larger security strategy, this is not the original intent (or implementation) of NAT. What mosts network engineers call &amp;ldquo;NAT&amp;rdquo; is actually one to many network port address translation - or taking one public address and &amp;ldquo;hiding&amp;rdquo; a number of private (likely RFC1918) addresses &amp;ldquo;behind&amp;rdquo; it, using ports to translate traffic and keeping the state of those connections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Field Area Networking</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/field-area-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 13:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/field-area-networking/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that RF technologies and what like to call &amp;ldquo;specialty networking&amp;rdquo; are two of my favorite things in the networking space. Put them together and it is like chocolate and peanut butter! Now, some may not consider Field Area Networking (FAN) to be &amp;ldquo;unconventional&amp;rdquo;, but it certainly falls well outside of the space of what is typically traditional enterprise networking. That said, Cisco&amp;rsquo;s FAN briefing at Network Field Day 17 really got me excited and thinking about the alternatives for the IoT space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategy Series: Build vs. Buy (sorta)</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/strategy-series-build-vs-buy-sorta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 22:53:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/strategy-series-build-vs-buy-sorta/</guid>
      <description>Build vs. buy is an often lamented and always hotly debated question in all aspects of IT, however, if one is able to truly look at all angles the answer is typically straightforward and can be rooted in one simple strategy: don&amp;rsquo;t reinvent the wheel.
Don&amp;rsquo;t reinvent the wheel Too many times we as an industry don&amp;rsquo;t do our homework - we are all guilty of it - and we reinvent a wheel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategy Series: How do you view outside of your network?</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/strategy-series-view-outside-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 16:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/strategy-series-view-outside-network/</guid>
      <description>In the tradition of my NIX4NetEng series I&amp;rsquo;m going to dive deep into the world of strategy, and specifically into the strategy of how we look at and operate our networks, the data they generate and the analytics that are available (and often overlooked) in how networks are managed both long term and day-to-day. So, in the spirit of visibility, lets think about how typical networks are monitored. My guess is that you either already know, or will soon realize that visibility and testing across disparate networks is hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategy Series: What is your netflow strategy?</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/what-is-your-netflow-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 11:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/what-is-your-netflow-strategy/</guid>
      <description>You have one, right? Even if your entire strategy is “collect some flow data”, there is absolutely NO reason not to have a netflow implementation, and frankly, it will save you time and money over time if you make the effort to do it. I love network data and analytics and I have waxed poetic about how important they are at every opportunity. There are a myriad of options for analytics and flow data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speculation on the obvious: stuff changes, why freak out?</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/speculation-obvious-stuff-changes-freak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/speculation-obvious-stuff-changes-freak/</guid>
      <description>I have my +100 hat of irreverence on today so it&amp;rsquo;s time for a soapbox post. Having recently read a several posts and articles on what seems to be the never-ending cavalcade of assertions that &amp;ldquo;networking people will be out of jobs and you&amp;rsquo;d better learn to be a programmer&amp;rdquo; - or more succinctly put: the &amp;ldquo;dramatic changes in IT networking&amp;rdquo;. To this I respond simply:
via GIPHY The scorched earth, &amp;ldquo;there&amp;rsquo;s a hole in the boat, we&amp;rsquo;re all going to die!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration backups and an opportunity for automation and management</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/configuration-backups-opportunity-automation-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 17:19:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/configuration-backups-opportunity-automation-management/</guid>
      <description>Configuration management is a critical part of successfully and efficiently run any network. From the early days of networking there have been options for doing configuration backup. Several projects have been around for literally decades, enabling the backup of a myriad of critical network devices and providing historical archives. Many of these projects and platforms require a reasonable amount of unix experience and perhaps some development skills. I’m going to give a quick synopsis of my three favorites, these a all very different in execution but provide the same types of services - configuration backup, diff, and archive (and not much else).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates, podcasts, and videos</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/updates-podcasts-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 01:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/updates-podcasts-videos/</guid>
      <description>Anyone that looks at this site with any regularity may have noticed that I have been pretty remiss in adding posts - for that I apologize, things have been busy. However, I have not been absent in the tech world&amp;hellip;quite the opposite, in fact. I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending more and more time on podcasts and other forms of tech media which I have not provided links for here. So, to help expose that, here are a few of the other media resources I&amp;rsquo;ve been popping up in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No privacy may be the new privacy.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/no-privacy-may-new-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 18:06:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/no-privacy-may-new-privacy/</guid>
      <description>Taking politics and putting them aside, what the new administration has been attempting to change with regard to internet privacy is something we should all be informed about. Wether you have a tin foil hat or don&amp;rsquo;t care, &amp;ldquo;knowing is half the battle&amp;rdquo;. The other half is doing - which I will also lend some brief insight to (sorta). What&amp;rsquo;s changing? Nothing yet (as of the time of this writing). What will likely change?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an internal span port inside proxmox OVS</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/creating-internal-span-port-inside-proxmox-ovs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 03:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/creating-internal-span-port-inside-proxmox-ovs/</guid>
      <description>In the last few years I have moved all of my virtualization to proxmox and docker. Seeing as I like to look at packets because I am a closet security guy, and being as I have been working off-and-on on a security project in recent times, I wanted to be able to span a port not only from a hardware switch, but also within my software switches. I had been using linux bridge, which I am not a fan of, so when I started down this path I did not look hard to find a way to do so under that platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I care about Segment Routing</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/care-segment-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:54:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/care-segment-routing/</guid>
      <description>Edit: Going against my normal “just get the content out there” methodology, I’ve been mulling over this blog post since July of 2016. Segment routing is such a beautifully elegant solution I have had trouble articulating that fact. WAN technologies are squarely within my wheelhouse, and this one fits in so well I was going over and over the post never really satisfied with it, continuing to find mistakes and decided to just get it out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BGP RPKI - why aren&#39;t we using it more?</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/bgp-rpki-why-arent-we-using-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 16:33:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/bgp-rpki-why-arent-we-using-it/</guid>
      <description>Image created from SURFNet RPKI page.         I was recently at a meeting where BGP RPKI was the topic de jour. While this has been a topic that I have visited on occasion of the last few years and something I wanted to spend significant time on, I have found that setting aside the time has been difficult and sparse, much like the deployment of BGP RPKI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIX4NetEng 6 DNS, ad-blocking, and quality of experience</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nix4neteng-6-dns-ad-blocking-and-quality-of-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 16:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nix4neteng-6-dns-ad-blocking-and-quality-of-experience/</guid>
      <description>The sixth [and arguably very overdue] installment of my NIX4NetEng series, this began as an overly complex diatribe about DNS. As it evolved, I realized that DNS is so complex and far reaching that it could never be contained in one meager post. DNS is a powerful tool. It has existed for so long that many that have never had the responsibility of running an authoritative or recursive resolver may take for granted the extensive reach of a tool so engrained in the fabric of the internet that it is frequently overlooked, much like a utility such as electricity or running water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1342/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 22:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1342/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 16:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/podcasts/</guid>
      <description>Podcasts Podcasts on Security and Networking that I have hosted or participated in. The series hosted by myself for ForwardingPlane.net are &amp;ldquo;Default Deny&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Non-Blocking&amp;rdquo;, which focus on data networking and security, respectively. [soundcloud url=&amp;ldquo;https://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/242625484&amp;quot; params=&amp;ldquo;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;100%&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; iframe=&amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; /]
Other Podcasts Software Gone Wild OpenSource Network Management Tools on Software Gone wild Running OpenDayLight in production  Network Field Day 9 Wrap Up
Packet Pushers Golf cart in my fiber tunnel Open Source Perfsonar for finding network issues</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buzzwords, technology, terminology, and the interconnection of modern networking</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/buzzwords-technology-terminology-interconnection-modern-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 16:33:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/buzzwords-technology-terminology-interconnection-modern-networking/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m way overdue for a soapbox session &amp;ndash; I found this one in my drafts and thought it was something I needed to put out there. It&amp;rsquo;s already dated in terminology but that actually helps make the point - it&amp;rsquo;s hard to keep up. 
Lets throw this out there: social media can be exhausting. Do not misunderstand me, it’s a great tool for communication, obtaining and disseminating information as well as standard goofing around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Interdomain SDN part 3</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/building-interdomain-sdn-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 04:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/building-interdomain-sdn-part-3/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago I wrote some text on interdomain SDN. Years later, work is being done, smart people are thinking about it and building ways to make it a reality. Not being one to give up on an idea, I gave this presentation in may at ChiNOG on what my take on what that architecture should be. I (we) propose that the use of existing protocols such as BGP FlowSpec will make this realistically deployable and maintainable given some simple, pluggable middleware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solarwinds Orion from a UNIX user perspective</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/solarwinds-orion-from-a-unix-user-point-of-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 04:08:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/solarwinds-orion-from-a-unix-user-point-of-view/</guid>
      <description>Back in February of this year (2015) I was introduced to Solarwinds when they presented to us at Networking Field day 9. Until then I knew of SolarWinds products but only at a cursory level; I had never really seen or used their stuff since it was mostly focused on environments that were either smaller or outside of the networking world that I generally operate in. However, I am a[n insufferable] network monitoring &amp;ldquo;aficionado&amp;rdquo; so when the opportunity to play around with it arose, I happily took it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brocade Vyatta Install and OpenFlow 1.3 on ICX 7450</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/brocade-vyatta-install-and-openflow-1-3-on-icx-7450/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 16:06:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/brocade-vyatta-install-and-openflow-1-3-on-icx-7450/</guid>
      <description>I recently had a need to test OpenFlow on the brocade ICX 7450 for a fairly good sized, high visibility project. The basic goal is pretty simple, Layer2 path provisioning. Straightforward and fairly well supported in OpenFlow, even from the early days. To do this, the idea was to use a turnkey platform, that way there is one throat to choke if there are issues. I landed on the Brocade Vyatta controller (which is essentially ODL), and the ICX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ravello Systems review and use case study</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ravello-systems-review-and-use-case-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 16:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ravello-systems-review-and-use-case-study/</guid>
      <description>There are a vast number of entities that offer the seemingly ubiquitous “cloud”. “SaaS”, “IaaS”, “BLAHaaS”, buzzword compliance is truly a sought after thing by marketing folks. With the proliferation of virtualization, containers and other “time slicing” of hardware by software the chatter can quickly become noise. As technical professionals and the warm bodies with the responsibility for actually making things work and keeping them running, the onus is on us to be able to decipher the useful from the fluff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brocade does a double down on SDN</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/brocade-does-a-double-down-on-sdn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 16:09:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/brocade-does-a-double-down-on-sdn/</guid>
      <description>Since Network Field Day 9, I have spent more and more time mentally grinding on what Brocade is doing. I have been a pretty vocal critic of the foundry hardware and software platform since my first experience with it years and years ago. I found it to be lacking in completed features, Layer 3 functionality and general stability.
This is one reason that anyone reading this should take pause and think about the background this post is sourcing from and how much of a shift it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1247/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 17:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1247/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1248/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 17:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1248/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1250/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 17:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1250/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1252/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 17:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1252/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1262/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 17:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1262/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 17:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/home/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenDNS acquires BGPMon and the future of route monitoring</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/opendns-acquires-bgpmon-and-the-future-of-route-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 05:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/opendns-acquires-bgpmon-and-the-future-of-route-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>For those that run BGP networks, BGPmon is often a tool they turn to for some really unique and hard to find information. Remember back in February 2008 when Pakistan Telecom &amp;ldquo;blocked&amp;rdquo; Youtube? That one was a really, really public example of something that BGPMon caught. BGPmon has been around for a long, long time. Quietly watching prefixes. Silently noting changes and reporting them to the ones lucky enough to know of its existence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networking</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 03:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/networking/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetBeez, performance monitoring and the network.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/netbeez-performance-monitoring-and-the-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 05:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/netbeez-performance-monitoring-and-the-network/</guid>
      <description>At Networking Field day 9 there was a great deal of discussion regarding monitoring, modeling, and maintaining networks, as would be expected at an event with such a focus. Luckily for us, an interesting product that comes from a company that I was unfamiliar with called NetBeez gave an inspired presentation. Now, NetBeez got my attention for a few reasons. First off, NetBeez is doing some really great things in the field of network monitoring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The NEC surprise</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/the-nec-surprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 06:52:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/the-nec-surprise/</guid>
      <description>When NEC began talking about SDN at Network Field Day 9, I was not sure what to expect. I knew they had been heavily involved with openflow since the early days, and many years ago I was able to get my hands on their early OpenFlow controller and was immediately frustrated by its cryptic nature and frankly, poor documentation. Their switches were fine and were heavily utilized in early OpenFlow deployments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BigSwitch Networks BigCloud Fabric 2.5</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/bigswitch-networks-bigcloud-fabric-2-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 01:04:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/bigswitch-networks-bigcloud-fabric-2-5/</guid>
      <description>BigSwitch is making waves again, this time with its Big Cloud Fabric product update. I was lucky enough to get a bit of a preview of what was coming and was pleasantly surprised by the new features, finding them functionally useful for both operators, security folks and management alike.
Not only is the fabric fit to operate at hyper scale proportions, they&amp;rsquo;ve paid close attention to making such operations even easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Field Day 9</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/network-field-day-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 15:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/network-field-day-9/</guid>
      <description>In a few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ll have the opportunity to participate in another Network Field Day. I&amp;rsquo;ve been lucky enough to have the opportunity to attendin the past and have done some remote participation when possible, but like some of the other rare opportunities I have had in my career, NFD is fairly unique in that it is constantly evolving in both the information provided and the individuals involved. As the saying goes, variety is the spice of life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 17:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/publications/</guid>
      <description>Work Profile
Nick Buraglio, Anita Nikolich, Dale Carder, Securing the SDN WAN, October 30, 2014
Nick Buraglio,Vincent Stoffer, Adam Slagell, Jim Eyrich, Scott Campbell, Von Welch, Securing the Science DMZ: a discussion,October 28, 2014
Nick Buraglio, Best practices for securing an open perimeter network, August 18, 2014   Video   Nick Buraglio, Securing the Science DMZ, June 14, 2014
Nick Buraglio, Real world IPv6 deployments, Westnet, June 9, 2014</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/publications/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 17:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/publications/publications/</guid>
      <description>Work Profile
Nick Buraglio, Anita Nikolich, Dale Carder, Securing the SDN WAN, October 30, 2014
Nick Buraglio,Vincent Stoffer, Adam Slagell, Jim Eyrich, Scott Campbell, Von Welch, Securing the Science DMZ: a discussion,October 28, 2014
Nick Buraglio, Best practices for securing an open perimeter network, August 18, 2014   Video   Nick Buraglio, Securing the Science DMZ, June 14, 2014
Nick Buraglio, Real world IPv6 deployments, Westnet, June 9, 2014</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring VMware ESXi with SNMP and Cacti</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/monitoring-vmware-esxi-with-snmp-and-cacti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 10:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/monitoring-vmware-esxi-with-snmp-and-cacti/</guid>
      <description>VMWare is a powerful tool, and monitoring is a critical service. How does one monitor such an integral piece of infrastructure, and what do they monitor it with? There are powerful commercial ways of monitoring VMware, however, for those with existing SNMP based systems in place, specifically cacti, there are options. To that end, I&amp;rsquo;ll set aside my strong distaste for SNMP [yet again], because those are for a larger, less useful series of posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIX4NetEng 5 - GeoIP tools</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nix4neteng-5-geoip-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 18:22:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nix4neteng-5-geoip-tools/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes in networking and security it becomes necessary to do lookups of location data on IP addresses and prefixes. On my Mac I use homebrew to manage packages, but most of these tools are available with thetypocal apt, yum and port package management systems. For this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to shift gears and show the install on my mac:``` sliver:~ buraglio$ brew install geoip ==&amp;gt; Downloading https://downloads.sf.net/project/machomebrew/Bottles/geoip-1.6.3.mavericks.bottle.tar.gz ######################################################################## 100.0% ==&amp;gt; Pouring geoip-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIX4Neteng 4: POODLE and SSLv3, scanning and updating</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nix4neteng-4-poodle-and-sslv3-scanning-and-updating/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 17:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nix4neteng-4-poodle-and-sslv3-scanning-and-updating/</guid>
      <description>With the recent release of the POODLE SSLv3 vulnerability, folks are scrambling around trying to figure out what runs what and where. Running a handful of things that do SSL, I was obligated, both personally and professionally, to figure out an easy way to drill down and figure out what does what and then fix the vulnerable services. When there are a lot of devices, this can seem like a daunting task, and it is if you&amp;rsquo;re trying to do it manually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenVswitch 2.3.0 RPMs</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/openvswitch-2-3-0-rpms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 21:06:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/openvswitch-2-3-0-rpms/</guid>
      <description>I was wanting to do a few quick mock-ups with OpenvSwitch and OpenDayLight and wanted to use CentOS since I have templates for it that I replicate. Just like with the debian stuff I had been doing, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to find any in some quick searches. I stumbled upon This site, which had a great how to for building them, so I just used that. Seeing as that the debian packages actually got downloaded a lot, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d post these RPMs as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BigSwitch Labs for SDN learning: a sneak peek!</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/bigswitch-labs-for-sdn-learning-a-sneak-peek/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 10:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/bigswitch-labs-for-sdn-learning-a-sneak-peek/</guid>
      <description>I was recently granted access to the beta BigSwitch Networks lab site, a purpose built classroom in the cloud focused on teaching the BigSwitch SDN environment. I had seen some of the BSN offerings in the past and always held them in high regard, but I was thoroughly impressed with both the completeness of the lab and how polished the controller environment was.At the time of this writing, the lab consists of 3 modules: Building cloud fabric, monitoring fabric and dynamic provisioning of monitoring fabric.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sonrancid: A [very] basic RANCID module for sonicwall</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/sonrancid-a-very-basic-rancid-module-for-sonicwall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 09:05:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/sonrancid-a-very-basic-rancid-module-for-sonicwall/</guid>
      <description>I know, I know, I&amp;rsquo;m always saying that you don&amp;rsquo;t need a firewall. That&amp;rsquo;s mostly to get your attention to push my agenda of sane security architecture, I do actually believe that firewalls are appropriate in a great many use cases and I&amp;rsquo;ve managed them big and small ranging from Juniper SRX 5800 clusters to tiny purpose built BSD distros on custom hardware. I even managed Checkpoint and gauntlet firewall back in the 1990s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you don&#39;t need a firewall [how to secure an open perimeter network]</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/why-you-dont-need-a-firewall-how-to-secure-an-open-perimeter-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 07:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/why-you-dont-need-a-firewall-how-to-secure-an-open-perimeter-network/</guid>
      <description>I admit that the title was meant to be inflammatory. However, there are use cases that aren&amp;rsquo;t terribly uncommon where an in-line security appliance is just not the correct tool for the job. Someone once told me &amp;ldquo;a firewall protects a network like a fuse protects an electrical circuit&amp;rdquo;, and it&amp;rsquo;s mostly a correct statement. Firewall vendors will probably argue this and enterprise folks may discount this as heresy and call for burning me at the stake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aging hardware, IPv6 and the growing route table</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/aging-hardware-ipv6-and-the-growing-route-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 05:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/aging-hardware-ipv6-and-the-growing-route-table/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve blathered on about BGP forever. Say what you will about the venerable protocol, it runs the interwebs, is reliable, extendable and well documented. I&amp;rsquo;ve also espoused&amp;rdquo;) ad nauseam about IPv6, so none of this [admitted] rant should really be a surprise coming from me. As of 8/12/2014, according to the CIRD report (and many mailing lists), the default free global ipv4 routing table has reached 512k routes. This is a milestone from many perspectives, but more importantly, it solidifies the fact that there is a great deal of equipment in critical points in the internet that is out of date and cannot perform as intended in its current configuration or function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIX4NetEng 3: IP Addressing and Subnet Tools</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nix4neteng-3-ip-addressing-and-subnet-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 16:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nix4neteng-3-ip-addressing-and-subnet-tools/</guid>
      <description>IP addressing and subnetting is a common interview subject. I assert that memorizing these things is useful for learning the concepts but ultimately futile in that it is time consuming and inefficient use of engineering time when tools can be utilized to accomplish the same goals in less time with fewer errors. Honestly, I gave up doing this kind of work manually around 10 years ago and have never regretted it, and in actuality, I&amp;rsquo;d probably struggle to do it at this point because it&amp;rsquo;s a repetitive process better suited by code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crystal Ball: Cisco buying tail-f.  What does it mean?</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/crystal-ball-cisco-buying-tail-f-what-does-it-mean/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 16:24:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/crystal-ball-cisco-buying-tail-f-what-does-it-mean/</guid>
      <description>With the recent announcement of Cisco Systems intent to purchase tail-f, proponents of a multi-vendor environment are waiting with baited breath to see how the networking giant will deal with support of competitor hardware and CLIs. Yang is here to stay, there is no doubt about that. As is netconf. Both of these are good things for the industry as a whole, having a standard way to communicate with network hardware [that isn&amp;rsquo;t openflow] is necessary and immeasurably useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIX4NetEng 2 IPv4/6 address investigation tools - whois &#43; dig</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nix4neteng-2-ipv46-address-investigation-tools-whois-dig/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2014 19:54:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nix4neteng-2-ipv46-address-investigation-tools-whois-dig/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t care what your vendor alignment of choice is, Cisco, Juniper, Brocade, Alcatel&amp;hellip;.it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. At one point or another you&amp;rsquo;re going to need to bird dog an address to see where it&amp;rsquo;s coming from, who owns it, what it&amp;rsquo;s DNS name is or what path you&amp;rsquo;re taking to get to it. We&amp;rsquo;ve already talked about BGP tools, they&amp;rsquo;re a great choice for checking routes across the internet. Hunting down addresses is an interesting one, though, as address management and lookups can bleed into other aspects of networking like path selection, latency, jitter and many other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Net Neutrality changes could force better fiber networks</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/net-neutrality-changes-could-force-better-fiber-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2014 18:40:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/net-neutrality-changes-could-force-better-fiber-networks/</guid>
      <description>Many regular internet users are extremely upset about the recent proposed changes the FCC has opened for comments about the delivery and provisioning of internet services. Watch this video if you&amp;rsquo;re unaware of the high emotions it has evoked: While these are proposed rules and are not in any way finalized, there is real concern that they may become law. Where this is problematic is that it opens up the possibility of some real misuse, abuse or simple misunderstanding of needs and services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIX4NetEng 1 Managing dotfiles; pwn the unspoken pain of UNIX administration</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nix4neteng-1-managing-dotfiles-pwn-the-unspoken-pain-of-unix-administration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 02:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nix4neteng-1-managing-dotfiles-pwn-the-unspoken-pain-of-unix-administration/</guid>
      <description>Many network engineers are also tasked with maintaining systems that provide network services, those things that make the network easier to use such as DNS and DHCP or management systems that perform useful things like monitor the network, collect flow data or bestow access to the equipment by acting as bastion or jump hosts. In many instances, robust and high availability services run on UNIX, Linux or BSD systems for stability and reliability, so those that manage these systems need to be well versed system admins as well as whatever their other job functions are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blending the Network; Pluribus ServerSwitch</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/blending-the-network-pluribus-serverswitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 04:44:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/blending-the-network-pluribus-serverswitch/</guid>
      <description>I firmly believe that blending disciplines is the way of the future in IT. I&amp;rsquo;ve rambled about it here at other venues and I&amp;rsquo;m vocal (some would probably say brash) about it on the twitters. Be it Networking and System, Systems and Security, Programming and Networking, most of us that have been around any length of time already do it but now it&amp;rsquo;s happening out in the open and &amp;ldquo;DevOps&amp;rdquo;, a form of the hybrid IT worker, has seemingly become the BOTD (Buzzword of the day).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BGP tools; troubleshooting and monitoring external routing in a nutshell</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/bgp-tools-troubleshooting-and-monitoring-external-routing-in-a-nutshell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 04:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/bgp-tools-troubleshooting-and-monitoring-external-routing-in-a-nutshell/</guid>
      <description>Time to rewind from the new and shiny and get back to roots of networking. BGP is one of those odd protocols that is foundational to the functioning of the internet but yet somewhat hard to get experience with. Say what you will about this venerable protocol, it&amp;rsquo;s been here a while and it is not going anywhere any time soon. I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing BGP since around late 1999, and I completely fell into it by accident, having only the Cisco Internet Routing Architectures book (which I literally read cover to cover) and the Ulysses Black Routing Protocols Book and whatever I could find on a random search engine to guide me, and that was only after having to learn on the CLI for the first 6-7 months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disclaimer</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/disclaimer/disclaimer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 00:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/disclaimer/disclaimer/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t endorse or condemn products for free or for money [and if I did I would disclose it in bold lettering for the world to see]. I will strive to provide a fact based description, experience or assessment of any given technology or product based on my particular experience. I may provide opinions as to what I believe is the right or wrong $item, $idea, $process, or $procedure on any given subject again based on my personal experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disclaimer</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/disclaimer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 00:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/disclaimer/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t endorse or condemn products for free or for money [and if I did I would disclose it in bold lettering for the world to see]. I will strive to provide a fact based description, experience or assessment of any given technology or product based on my particular experience. I may provide opinions as to what I believe is the right or wrong $item, $idea, $process, or $procedure on any given subject again based on my personal experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 14:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/resume/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/resume/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 14:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/resume/resume/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replace ZFS RAIDZ1 disk</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/replace-zfs-raidz1-disk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 01:01:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/replace-zfs-raidz1-disk/</guid>
      <description>I recently had the displeasure of dealing with a series of failed disks in my newly created ZFS based NAS. I had cobbled together roughly 12TB of disk space and jammed them into an old PC, stretching the limits of the platform when I decided to go with ZFS. I broke all of the rules, underpowered, single core PC, only a handful of GIG of non-ECC RAM, etc. I&amp;rsquo;m sure storage guys are having a coronary after reading that, but it works for me and has minimal issues since I just relatively redundant need bulk storage and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be fast (the ethernet connection is only 100M).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tail-F NCS: upsetting network management...in a good way.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/tail-f-ncs-upsetting-network-management-in-a-good-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 04:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/tail-f-ncs-upsetting-network-management-in-a-good-way/</guid>
      <description>“Hopefully there are some things here that will make you really upset in a very good way” is how Carl Moberg of Swedish based company tail-f opened up to the crowd at Networking Field Day 7 on Feb 19, 2014. Tail-f is a sleeper, I had actually never heard of them before NFD7, but they&amp;rsquo;ve got a very unique product in NCS and in my opinion it can change the way existing and future networks are managed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cold Locals</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/cold-locals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 02:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/cold-locals/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Site</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/personal-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 02:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/personal-site/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFD7 Live stream available</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nfd7-live-stream-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 18:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nfd7-live-stream-available/</guid>
      <description>Tune in!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Field Day 7</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/network-field-day-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 02:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/network-field-day-7/</guid>
      <description>A while ago I got an email asking me to participate in Network Field Day 7. I was very happy and humbled to get asked again since I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to attend NFD5 or NFD6 for various reasons outside of my control (although I did try to participate with NFD5 remotely). If you&amp;rsquo;re unfamiliar with the tech field day series, you should spend a little time and learn about the value it brings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install nfsen and nfdump on CentOS 6.5 for netflow and or sflow collection</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/install-nfsen-and-nfdump-on-centos-6-5-for-netflow-and-or-sflow-collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 21:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/install-nfsen-and-nfdump-on-centos-6-5-for-netflow-and-or-sflow-collection/</guid>
      <description>I am an absolutely huge fan of statistical and instrumentation data, especially when it comes to traffic analysis, visualization and baselining. I&amp;rsquo;ve rambled on about the importance of it at every opportunity. As a result of that, I have been doing work with netflow and netflow-like data for a fairly long time. My first collector was the OSU Flow tools based stuff back around 13 years ago. From there I played with all kinds of netflow tools, both commercial and open source, finally settling most of my focus on nfdump and nfsen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speculation and soapboxing about the leaked NSA spy catalog.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/speculation-and-soapboxing-about-the-leaked-nsa-spy-catalog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 17:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/speculation-and-soapboxing-about-the-leaked-nsa-spy-catalog/</guid>
      <description>The buzz as of late around the security and networking communities has been about the NSA and their catalog or spy toolkit. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent time in my career thinking about and doing infosec and I did a brief stint working for the FBI in a project called NCDIR. I like to think that I can provide at least a peripherally competent commentary about it [take it with a grain of salt].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sonicwall revisited - Now with IPv6 - and way too much licensing cruft.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/sonicwall-revisited-now-with-ipv6-and-way-too-much-licensing-cruft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 15:45:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/sonicwall-revisited-now-with-ipv6-and-way-too-much-licensing-cruft/</guid>
      <description>About a year ago I did a brief review of the &amp;ldquo;new Sonicwall&amp;rdquo;, specifically a smaller branch office device that was said should have had all of the features of the larger devices. I proposed that it had some significant limitations (much to the disagreement of a great deal of folks). However, I stand by my statements. If you ignore the fact that firewalls often cause more problems than they solve, that NAT is a nightmarish kludge (and not a security mechanism), and will likely be phased out for better options eventually, the SonicOS I tested was pretty limited as far as what I believe should be features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calendar</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/calendar/calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 16:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/calendar/calendar/</guid>
      <description>Free/Busy Calendar: The best way to schedule time with me is via my Doodle MeetMe Page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calendar</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 16:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/calendar/</guid>
      <description>Free/Busy Calendar: The best way to schedule time with me is via my Doodle MeetMe Page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenvSwitch 2.0 Debian packages</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/openvswitch-2-0-debian-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 20:15:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/openvswitch-2-0-debian-packages/</guid>
      <description>As part of a larger fun project I&amp;rsquo;m working on (OVS for the ALIX platform; more to come on that once I have it 100% working), I have been playing a lot with OVS. It&amp;rsquo;s a great platform, and as others have mentioned, it&amp;rsquo;s as close to an SDN reference data plane implementation as we have. I&amp;rsquo;d be surprised if many if not all commercial implementations of OpenFlow aren&amp;rsquo;t based on OVS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to be a [good] Network Engineer (and network engineer appreciation day)</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/how-to-be-a-good-network-engineer-and-network-appreciation-engineer-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 04:02:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/how-to-be-a-good-network-engineer-and-network-appreciation-engineer-day/</guid>
      <description>My personal background in computing (specifically networking) is atypical. I have a bachelors in visual arts and only took a handful of computing classes in my relatively long tenure in college. However, I did learn one valuable lesson that has served me pretty well over the 15 or so years I have been doing networking and I&amp;rsquo;d bet money any good network engineer that has more than 10 years of experience will nod their head at this and agree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being single vendor does your brain a disservice.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/being-single-vendor-does-your-brain-a-disservice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2013 15:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/being-single-vendor-does-your-brain-a-disservice/</guid>
      <description>Let me be clear, when I say &amp;ldquo;single vendor&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m talking about being &amp;ldquo;single vendor&amp;rdquo; in what you work on, not necessarily what you install (although one basically forces the other) and what I really mean is multilingual. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain after a brief history of why I am the way I am. I&amp;rsquo;m idealistic but I&amp;rsquo;m also realistic. I generally propose solutions that I think are best even if it is non-standard or out of current comfort level along with an alternative or two.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inline-jflow on MX series Juniper</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/inline-jflow-on-mx-series-juniper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 15:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/inline-jflow-on-mx-series-juniper/</guid>
      <description>One of the things that I&amp;rsquo;ve always lamented about using non-Cisco hardware is the lack of true 1:1 netflow support. Say what you will about jflow, cflow, sflow&amp;hellip;.there is no substitute for netflow, with sflow being the exception to that since it is a protocol that inherently supports ipv6 and can transport far more than simple network information if configured in certain ways on certain devices. On newer MX series Juniper routers the game has changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing the dreaded &#34;error: could not open configuration database (juniper.data&#43;)&#34; problem.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/fixing-the-dreaded-error-could-not-open-configuration-database-juniper-data-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 16:52:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/fixing-the-dreaded-error-could-not-open-configuration-database-juniper-data-problem/</guid>
      <description>Working on some MX series routers recently I encountered a problem I&amp;rsquo;d never seen before, essentially preventing the configuration from being committed:``` buraglio@rtr# commit check re0: error: could not open configuration database (juniper.data+)
buraglio@rtr&amp;gt;start shell From there I wanted to see the file system and check out the stats of what it thinks we have.``` buraglio@rtr% df -h Filesystem Size Used Avail Capacity Mounted on /dev/ad0s1a 3.5G 313M 2.9G 10% / devfs 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The sad state of IPv6 and why you need to learn it.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/the-sad-state-of-ipv6-and-why-you-need-to-learn-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 11:18:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/the-sad-state-of-ipv6-and-why-you-need-to-learn-it/</guid>
      <description>I have been learning and using IPv6 for a quite a while, even before I worked in research and education, back in the ISP days. I thought I should learn it because, frankly, I figured we&amp;rsquo;d all be converted to it by now, already whole hog using it like it was the layer 3 addressing mechanism that it is. Flashback: My first IPv6 access was via a tunnel to HE a long, long time ago and before that I was reading what I could about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a secured network in a box</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/building-a-secured-network-in-a-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 05:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/building-a-secured-network-in-a-box/</guid>
      <description>In many environments, the move to virtualization is a path well traveled. My home and lab networks are no exception to this and I&amp;rsquo;m sure nearly everyone who reads these pages has at least been exposed to it in one way or another. I have played with nearly all of the virtualization platforms and am firmly in the camp that there will be a large segment of networking that will move to a virtualized platform especially in the data center and campus segments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building FlowVisor on Centos 6 - quick and dirty</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/building-flowvisor-on-centos-6-quick-and-dirty/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 10:22:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/building-flowvisor-on-centos-6-quick-and-dirty/</guid>
      <description>I had the need to build a FlowVisor instance under CentOS. Since nearly all of the docs I could find were for debian, I threw this together. I utilized this GENI doc and the github docs as a simple reference. This is the quick and dirty method I used: Install the prerequisites:``` sudo yum -y install ant eclipse java-1.6.0-openjdk.x86_64 git sudo yum -y groupinstall &amp;ldquo;Development Tools&amp;rdquo;
mkdir /services cd /services git clone git://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I want to love cumulus networks.....</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/i-want-to-love-cumulus-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 22:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/i-want-to-love-cumulus-networks/</guid>
      <description>I want to preface this by saying that I have not seen or worked on the cumulus networks system yet. This is a stream of consciousness post on my thoughts and opinions based on what I&amp;rsquo;ve read publicly. Recently a new network player has emerged on the scene with a very simple, straightforward idea. Take linux and put it on a switch. While this isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly new (see Juniper and FreeBSD, Arista with Linux, Force10 with NetBSD or the plethora of other vendors using an opensource OS as the underpinnings of their NOS), the angle that cumulus networks is taking is a bit more&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMWare ESXi CLI reference</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/vmware-esxi-cli-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 14:24:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/vmware-esxi-cli-reference/</guid>
      <description>One of my biggest complaints about VMware is that it is an enterprise application. It has historically catered to the masses, which I completely understand, but those of us that aren&amp;rsquo;t a fortune 500 company are figuratively and operationally shoved into a corner and forced to find hackish ways of doing things to work around the enterprise nature. One really, really good example of this is OS dependency. I hated architecture dependencies back in the old days (x86, SPARC, PPC) and I absolutely despise things that are OS platform dependent now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMWare ESXi CLI reference</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/vmware-esxi-cli-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 08:08:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/vmware-esxi-cli-reference/</guid>
      <description>All of these commands require ssh to be enabled on the VMware host and were tested on 5.1.
Power off a VM
vim-cmd vmsvc/power.getstate List power state of VM:
vim-cmd vmsvc/power.of Power on VM
vim-cmd vmsvc/power.on List all VMs:
vim-cmd vmsvc/getallvms Other important commands under vmsvc:
acquiremksticket get.snapshotinfo
acquireticket get.spaceNeededForConsolidation
connect get.summary
convert.toTemplate get.tasklist
convert.toVm getallvms
createdummyvm gethostconstraints
destroy login
device.connection logout
device.connusbdev message
device.disconnusbdev power.getstate
device.diskadd power.hibernate
device.diskaddexisting power.off</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broadcast input with iTerm</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/broadcast-input-with-iterm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 15:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/broadcast-input-with-iterm/</guid>
      <description>As much as I like to think I automate everything, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty bad at writing code to make my life easier since it tends to take me longer to write the code and it tends to make be a bit grumpy (this is eomthing I&amp;rsquo;m fixing by learning as much code dev as I can during my limited spare time). However, I like to think I can be fairly smart about working around my limited programming skills (think boba fett rather than jedi) by using the tools available to common folk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating flow data without Cisco</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/677/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 14:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/677/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging Brocade MLX/XMR ip_rx CPU issues</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/debugging-brocade-mlxxmr-ip_rx-cpu-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 00:35:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/debugging-brocade-mlxxmr-ip_rx-cpu-issues/</guid>
      <description>I recently had the need to debug a run away ip_rx process on an older Brocade MLX. For anyone that has had to do any type of low level debugging on the Brocade (Foundry) platform, you know that there many somewhat deep level diagnostics that are possible. The debug (like cisco debug) is a bit lacking, but the dm, LP and MP commands are very useful (and a tad scary). Regardless, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to utilize them a lot in the last few years so my aversion to using them has been pretty much completely callused over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPLS Bootstrap</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/mpls-bootstrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 13:04:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/mpls-bootstrap/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot of MPLS in the last 45 or so days (which is one of the reasons I have been absentee in the OpenFlow world lately). Having had almost no real world MPLS experience aside from a handful of pseudo-wires and a very small LDP signaled network, I had to spend some time reading, hacking at routers and essentially learning. In doing so, I found a few things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPLS PseudoWire (VLL) between JunOS and Brocade MLX/XMR</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/mpls-pseudowire-vll-between-junos-and-brocade-mlxxmr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2013 16:24:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/mpls-pseudowire-vll-between-junos-and-brocade-mlxxmr/</guid>
      <description>I love to be the &amp;ldquo;uncola&amp;rdquo; of networking sites. I like interop and I don&amp;rsquo;t do a lot with Cisco because I don&amp;rsquo;t have access to much of their gear anymore. So, that being the case, I had a need to bring up a l2circuit (in JunOS speak), or VLL (in Brocade speak) between an MX480 and an MLX. Since they are very different platforms, I had to do some digging and playing around to get it to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv6 Feature Matrix (Again)</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ipv6-feature-matrix-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 22:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ipv6-feature-matrix-again/</guid>
      <description>There has been some recent chatter on the IPv6 Ops mailing list about the feature matrix. Sadly, I&amp;rsquo;ve let this sort of wither on the vine for a while in favor of OpenFlow and SDN. At the end of the day, though, as a whole we actually need IPv6 more than SDN and OpenFlow at this moment in time, so I&amp;rsquo;m resurrecting it. It is available here. A few additions have been made and there is now a &amp;ldquo;last edited&amp;rdquo; cell so folks can tell if the data is stale or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scripting the build of OpenDayight Controller under CentOS</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/scripting-the-build-of-opendayight-controller-under-centos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 21:45:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/scripting-the-build-of-opendayight-controller-under-centos/</guid>
      <description>Jon Langemak has a great write up on building the OpenDaylight controller under CentOS. Since I&amp;rsquo;ll have to do this a bunch of times, I though tI&amp;rsquo;d take what he so generously put online and build a very rudimentary script for deploying ODC under CentOS. The prerequisites are that you already have an account and ssh key at the OpenDaylight GIT repo and that you disable SELinux. Here is the script:``` #!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VNC Console on VMware ESXi</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/vnc-console-on-vmware-esxi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 03:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/vnc-console-on-vmware-esxi/</guid>
      <description>Let me preface this post by saying that I am absolutely not an enterprise IT or systems guy, take everything that I write here on out with that as a side dish. I&amp;rsquo;m also very, very cheap. That said, one of the things I really like about KVM is the ability to easily view the console of a guest system using free, non-windows software like VNC. However, much like everything in life, there are reasons to do one thing or another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic reference openflow controller VMs running in CentOS 6 for KVM.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/basic-reference-openflow-controller-vms-running-in-centos-6-for-kvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 04:56:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/basic-reference-openflow-controller-vms-running-in-centos-6-for-kvm/</guid>
      <description>I had been working, off and on, on a how-to for building the daylight openflow controller under CentOS. Most openflow docs and dev are done under ubuntu or debian, and while those are both fantastic alternatives, there are a huge number of folks that will want or need to use RHEL or CentOS. So, seeing as that is the case, having someone be mindful of that is important. When I saw the write up by Jon Langemak, I scrapped my attempt at a how-to since his was so much better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenFlow Hybrid.  It&#39;s a must, not an option.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/openflow-hybrid-its-a-must-not-an-option/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 16:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/openflow-hybrid-its-a-must-not-an-option/</guid>
      <description>OpenFlow is, of course, a hot buzzword. It&amp;rsquo;s the newest, and in my opinion, the most innovative thing to hit data networking since dynamic routing. The ability to programmatically, systematically and potentially dynamically control traffic at the flow level through a network is innovative, exciting and terrifying [to many network engineers and architects] at the same time. Allowing applications to touch the network change behavior is something that many engineers are not terribly comfortable with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daylight, a new dawn is approaching.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/daylight-a-new-dawn-is-approaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 04:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/daylight-a-new-dawn-is-approaching/</guid>
      <description>The SDN world is abuzz with the announcement that the OpenDaylight controller came from stealth mode today. Why is this important? Well, SDN and OpenFlow are fractured. It is Mac vs. PC, Beta vs VHS, Coke vs. Pepsi all over again&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;multiplied by 100x and with a handful of players.  Vendor zealots and brand loyalists will nearly always side with their camp. Heck, even I have some biases of personal preference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A missing link in small MPLS, 10G devices.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/a-missing-link/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 04:43:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/a-missing-link/</guid>
      <description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been lamenting the fact that there seems to be a lack of options in a very specific product level. Lets say you have a network that looks like this: Right Away you&amp;rsquo;re limited since you need MPLS and more than 2 10G interfaces. Even more so if you require full support for IPv6 and ISIS. If budget is of any concern, you&amp;rsquo;re in real trouble. For many, Cisco pricing and smartnet is potentially going to exclude anything reasonable from them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My SDN soapbox (now with IPv6!)</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/my-sdn-soapbox-now-with-ipv6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 21:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/my-sdn-soapbox-now-with-ipv6/</guid>
      <description>This week there was a lot of buzz about SDN (as usual). There was alightreading thread that I commented on and a fantastic read by Brent Salisbury about being the steamroller and not the road that got me thinking about OpenFlow and SDN in a way I had not before.   All that is old is new again. I remember when internal networks were small and routing protocols were taboo in many internal environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why hardware firewalls are the walking dead</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/why-hardware-firewalls-are-the-walking-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 11:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/why-hardware-firewalls-are-the-walking-dead/</guid>
      <description>OK, maybe they&amp;rsquo;re not totally dead, but they&amp;rsquo;re being demoted. To the mail room. During the course of my career I&amp;rsquo;ve always had at least some responsibility for firewall and security devices. In those ~15 years, how these boxes are built and function has shifted. From the perspective of my career, there were IOS ACLs (yes, I know, not a firewall), there was the IOS firewall versions and there were software packages such as gauntlet, checkpoint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Bridge Domain on MX series JunOS</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/building-a-bridge-domain-on-mx-series-junos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 16:48:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/building-a-bridge-domain-on-mx-series-junos/</guid>
      <description>I started working on Juniper equipment around 2002. At my employer, we had an M40 with the serial number 256. We did Layer3 only. I had no idea if the Juniper even did layer2. It certainly wasn&amp;rsquo;t a layer3 switch like a 6500 like I was used to. It was like a deliciously robust version of any Layer 3 router I&amp;rsquo;d worked on previously. Over the years Juniper has added a switching line utilizing their FreeBSD based OS, JunOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Field Day 5 - Participate Remotely</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/network-field-day-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 14:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/network-field-day-5/</guid>
      <description>Last year, Networking Field Day was something that I&amp;rsquo;d heard of but wasn&amp;rsquo;t really aware of what is really was. I occasionally looked at Twitter and saw the hash tags but did not know much about how it was set up or what it was about. In fact, I actually thought it was supposed to be like the HAM radio field day stuff where you go out and build out an emergency network on the fly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuning BGP installed IPv6 routes</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/tuning-bgp-installed-ipv6-routes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 13:15:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/tuning-bgp-installed-ipv6-routes/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently run into a situation where there was no longer enough space in the FIB to handle both the full IPv4 global table and the full IPv6 global table. We prefer to run a default-free network within this particular SP network, but in this case, until a hardware refresh can happen, we&amp;rsquo;ll need to adjust that. Given what we knew about the size of both tables, it made more sense to take a default IPv6 route from one transit provider and filter the rest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CentOS KVM Install - Quick Start to a VM</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/centos-kvm-install-quick-start-to-a-vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 01:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/centos-kvm-install-quick-start-to-a-vm/</guid>
      <description>I am a network engineer by profession, but with the proliferation of SDN and OpenFlow, I have had to spend a lot of time re-learning a lot of system admin skills that I&amp;rsquo;d shelved years ago. Now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been a virtualization user forever. From VMware (Fusion, ESX), VirtualBox, to Parallels, I&amp;rsquo;ve used them at least in testing if not in production environments. I&amp;rsquo;d not really spent any mentionable amount of time with XEN, qEMU or KVM, but some projects I was working on suggested it for the virtualization mechanism, so I figured I&amp;rsquo;d try to pick it up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KVM virsh command reference</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/kvm-virsh-command-referenc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 14:28:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/configuration-archive/kvm-virsh-command-referenc/</guid>
      <description>From the help command, here is a reference sheet for the virsh command:
virsh [options]... [&amp;lt;command_string&amp;gt;] virsh [options]... &amp;lt;command&amp;lt;/command [args...] options: -c | --connect=URI hypervisor connection URI -r | --readonly connect readonly -d | --debug=NUM debug level [0-4] -h | --help this help -q | --quiet quiet mode -t | --timing print timing information -l | --log=FILE output logging to file -v short version -V long version --version[=TYPE] version, TYPE is short or long (default short) -e | --escape set escape sequence for console commands (non interactive mode): Domain Management (help keyword &#39;domain&#39;) attach-device attach device from an XML file attach-disk attach disk device attach-interface attach network interface autostart autostart a domain blkdeviotune Set or query a block device I/O tuning parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KVM virsh command reference</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/kvm-virsh-command-referenc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 20:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/kvm-virsh-command-referenc/</guid>
      <description>From the help command, here is a reference sheet for the virsh command:``` virsh [options]&amp;hellip; [] virsh [options]&amp;hellip; [args&amp;hellip;]
options: -c | &amp;ndash;connect=URI hypervisor connection URI -r | &amp;ndash;readonly connect readonly -d | &amp;ndash;debug=NUM debug level [0-4] -h | &amp;ndash;help this help -q | &amp;ndash;quiet quiet mode -t | &amp;ndash;timing print timing information -l | &amp;ndash;log=FILE output logging to file -v short version -V long version &amp;ndash;version[=TYPE] version, TYPE is short or long (default short) -e | &amp;ndash;escape set escape sequence for console</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv6 Toolkit 1.3 fun - scan6</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ipv6-toolkit-1-3-fun-scan6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 10:53:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ipv6-toolkit-1-3-fun-scan6/</guid>
      <description>Recently SI6 released the IPv6 Toolkit 1.3  This release is on the heels of this IETF draft  on IPv6 host scanning. It was long thought that scanning an IPv6 network was impossible. The address space was too large and reliably ascertaining the hosts from it would be too time consuming to even attempt. However, as Dr. Hans Zarkov says in the 1980 classic cult film of my youth, Flash Gordon, &amp;ldquo;You can&amp;rsquo;t beat the human spirit!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watch out, Gigamon (and others), Arista is bringing their A game</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/watch-out-gigamon-and-others-arista-is-bringing-their-a-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 03:11:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/watch-out-gigamon-and-others-arista-is-bringing-their-a-game/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of the model Arista Networks is using to make gear and provide innovative services and products. In my opinion, they&amp;rsquo;re changing the landscape of campus and data center networking gear. I&amp;rsquo;m always a fan of the little guy trying to change the world and this falls under that category. For those that don&amp;rsquo;t know, Arista Networks is a &amp;ldquo;hardware&amp;rdquo; networking company that is using merchant silicon wrapped in their custom linux based operating system (which is very much like IOS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optical SDN and the future of DWDM</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/437/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 16:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/437/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Floodlight OpenFlow controller on CentOS 6</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/building-a-floodlight-openflow-controller-on-centos-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 13:10:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/building-a-floodlight-openflow-controller-on-centos-6/</guid>
      <description>A bit of back history: I came from BSD land. I was a FreeBSD user from way back in the 1990s. BSD land is a land of secure boxes and very high uptimes. It&amp;rsquo;s also a land of arguably clunky package support, a lot of compiling by hand and these days, not nearly as encompassing package and network tuning support. I decided to move to Linux&amp;rdquo;) a while ago, reluctantly, and chose Debian as my flavor of choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identify and remedy problem IKE and eventd processes on Juniper SRX</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/identify-and-remedy-problem-ike-and-eventd-processes-on-juniper-srx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 12:45:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/identify-and-remedy-problem-ike-and-eventd-processes-on-juniper-srx/</guid>
      <description>Recently we encountered a very strange behavior on an SRX 5800 cluster. The cluster, which is in active/active mode, started dropping OSPF adjacencies to it&amp;rsquo;s neighboring routing equipment, in this case, Juniper MX480 and Brocade/Foundry MLX8. Strange behavior indeed, since for us, these had been rock solid for around 2 years and we&amp;rsquo;d never seen this odd behavior before. Honestly, we started looking at the routers first since this was something the SRX has never done before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open source or open standards?</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/427/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 19:39:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/427/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networking and the PC parallel</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/networking-and-the-pc-parallel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 23:24:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/networking-and-the-pc-parallel/</guid>
      <description>Pc and networking timeline. Commodity hardware. Custom hardware. Asics. White box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Headless VirtualBox host on CentOS</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/headless-virtualbox-host-on-centos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 21:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/headless-virtualbox-host-on-centos/</guid>
      <description>Starting from a base CentOS system with nothing configured, and referencing the CentOS wiki, here is how I like to set up a headless virtualbox environment: Disable selinux. It&amp;rsquo;s overly cumbersome and is enabled by default in CentOS. I like to permanently disable it even though the default is permissive. I ride the edge, I know.``` vi /etc/selinux/config
 and change  SELINUX=enabled
 to  SELINUX=disabled
 Then reboot. Using the methodology I originally found found [here](http://stackoverflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diff RANCID router configs with SVN</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/diff-rancid-router-configs-with-svn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 00:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/diff-rancid-router-configs-with-svn/</guid>
      <description>If you are running a network and aren&amp;rsquo;t using RANCID, you should give it a serious look. RANCID is a cross platform configuration management toolkit for backing up router configurations and certain environmental and hardware information into version control. It&amp;rsquo;s been around for as long as I can remember and supports nearly every platform I can think of, including a few modules that I cobbled together myself. There is are a few nice web based front ends for CVS and SVN, I prefer to use ViewVC because I have a lot of experience with it, however, there may be cases where a web server isn&amp;rsquo;t a good option, unavailable or just too much work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternate model for Service Provider networks; or how to keep net neutrality intact</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/alternate-model-for-sp-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 05:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/alternate-model-for-sp-networks/</guid>
      <description>There has been a lot of buzz about the service provider model, net neutrality and tiered access for consumers in the past few years. Just this week Google has been accused of paying Orange (more likely Orange is forcing google) for handling its traffic. This is a VERY slippery slope that teeters on the edge of what we all want to avoid as consumers or content creators. This recent story has sparked something I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about for a very long time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDN Across the WAN, part deux.  Primitives.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/sdn-across-the-wan-part-deux-primitives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2013 03:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/sdn-across-the-wan-part-deux-primitives/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been lamenting about the SDN WAN options for a while now. Having SDN/OpenFlow in a data center or campus is relatively well documented and already widely deployed. Google has been doing SDN across their private WAN in production. These pieces are easy. What isn&amp;rsquo;t easy is the ability to plumb SDN across many domains that are under disparate control. This part is hard. What is lacking is a fundamental framework, or set of primitives to build from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install and use the Airport utility under Mountain Lion</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/how-to-install-and-use-the-airport-utility-under-mountain-lion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 09:58:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/how-to-install-and-use-the-airport-utility-under-mountain-lion/</guid>
      <description>I have a bunch of Apple wireless gear at my house. It&amp;rsquo;s inexpensive, feature rich and easy to maintain. However, with the update to mountain lion a while ago, the ability to install the older Airport Utility stopped. This is annoying since I have what apple now considers &amp;ldquo;advanced&amp;rdquo; features like IPv6 at my home and essentially all my gear here is a lab (except for the plex server =) I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending a lot of time on cacti lately, and I wanted to test out the syslog plugin&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNS utilities on CentOS</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/dns-utilities-on-centos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 10:13:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/dns-utilities-on-centos/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s always annoying to me, being a convert from *BSD to Linux, that tools lke dig and host aren&amp;rsquo;t in the minimal base install. I realise that this makes me somewhat of a hypocrite, as I prefer an additive system rather than a subtractive base OS. Nevertheless, I&amp;rsquo;m continually surprised that &amp;ldquo;host&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t available after installing a minimal CentOS system without adding an additional package. So, since I always forget, here is a quick blog post to remind me and any other converts how to install those tools:``` yum -y install bind-utils</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HomeNet</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/homenet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 18:43:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/homenet/</guid>
      <description>Maybe It&amp;rsquo;s a bit overkill, but I used my home network as an exercise for building a Network Weathermap for another consulting gig I had. It continues to run. Why? Because it can =) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where will Cisco go from here?</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/where-will-cisco-go-from-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 00:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/where-will-cisco-go-from-here/</guid>
      <description>After reading Stephen Fosketts post &amp;ldquo;How Will Cisco Recover From The Consumer Strategy Blunder?&amp;rdquo;, it got me thinking. It&amp;rsquo;s a very different world than when Cisco got started all those years ago. I don&amp;rsquo;t have any brand loyalty to Cisco, I learned on cisco gear 14-15 years ago for the most part, but I try to keep the mentality of &amp;ldquo;the right tool for the job&amp;rdquo;, which means constantly surveying th emarket for new and interesting ways to do things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most popular posts of 2012</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/294/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 05:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/294/</guid>
      <description>I am very happy and flattered that this site actually proves to be useful to folks. It was always my intention to use this as a platform to try to give back a bit, to help with any data I may have run across that was interesting, useful, or obscure. I utilize sites like etherialmind.com, packetpushers.net, evilrouters.net, networkstatic.net and ioshints more than I can even measure. I wanted to try to contribute as much as I could to pay it back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing OwnCloud on CentOS</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/291/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2012 13:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/291/</guid>
      <description>wget http://dl.fedoraproject.org/pub/epel/6/x86\_64/epel-release-6-8.noarch.rpm wget http://rpms.famillecollet.com/enterprise/remi-release-6.rpm yum -y install apache2 php5 php5-json php-xml php-mbstring php5-zip php5-gd yum -y install php5-sqlite curl libcurl3 libcurl3-dev php5-curl php-pd  php5-sqlite isn&amp;rsquo;t available in the repos I use. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to find it elsewhere either. Per this page, I have to install it by source. cd /etc/yum.repos.d/ wget http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/isv:ownCloud:community/CentOS\_CentOS-6/isv:ownCloud:community.repo yum install owncloud</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Tech Predictions for 2013</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/random-tech-predictions-for-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 19:39:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/random-tech-predictions-for-2013/</guid>
      <description>I have a love-hate feeling about &amp;ldquo;predictions&amp;rdquo; about the upcoming year, especially tech predictions. I don&amp;rsquo;t like media sensationalism of any kind, and a lot of the tech predctions are just that, sensational, extreme talk to draw in readers or viewers. I&amp;rsquo;m choosing to go down a more subtle path, these are things I&amp;rsquo;ve thought about lately but will likely forget in the upcoming year, unless they actually happen, in which case I&amp;rsquo;d likely do an &amp;ldquo;ah, I remember thinking that may happen&amp;rdquo; gesture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CentOS sshguard install for limiting ssh scans</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/centos-sshguard-install-for-limiting-ssh-scans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 03:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/centos-sshguard-install-for-limiting-ssh-scans/</guid>
      <description>Securing SSH is a form or art. It&amp;rsquo;s often debated, much like blocking all ICMP packets (which I normally disagree with). If you need good proof, read these posts by Bob Plankers. There is a camp that likes to promote moving to a non-standard port. There is a faction that likes to block it completely except from a handful of hosts. Then there are those that like to leave it open all together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDN</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/sdn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 21:22:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/sdn/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Center</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/data-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 21:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/data-center/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNIX</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/unix/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 21:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/unix/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Routing</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 21:04:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/routing/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramblings</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ramblings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 21:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ramblings/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv6</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ipv6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 18:23:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ipv6/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A day with only IPv6</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/a-day-with-only-ipv6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 17:58:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/a-day-with-only-ipv6/</guid>
      <description>IPv6 is coming. Like SDN, we can&amp;rsquo;t ignore it. Are you ready? Are you apps ready? I&amp;rsquo;ll wager the answer is no. Mine aren&amp;rsquo;t. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on IPv6 for about 11 years, from early days of tunnels to full native IPv6 at home and at work. In teaching the IPv6 workshop for internet2, one of the things that I always suggest is to have a dual stacked host and an IPv6 only host available for testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plexxi could be WDM for the rest of us.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/plexxi-could-be-wdm-for-the-rest-of-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 05:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/plexxi-could-be-wdm-for-the-rest-of-us/</guid>
      <description>Plexxi is an interesting product that has recently emerged in the data center space. While data center, fabric and cloud are all the rage in the buzzword world of data networking, this one caught my attention because it was something unique that I&amp;rsquo;d not seen before. Their TOR boxes have a few interesting additions to them, the first of which is a WDM port on the back. Now, I&amp;rsquo;m not really a stranger to the WDM world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brocade VDX First Impressions....</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/brocade-vdx-first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 17:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/brocade-vdx-first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>I recently had the opportinity to work with the much-anticipated Brocade VDX &amp;ldquo;Ethernet Fabric&amp;rdquo; platform. I do admit tha tI&amp;rsquo;m intrigued by this product. I&amp;rsquo;d seen it work multiple times in demos and it worked so well and looked to easy that we actively tried to throw curve balls at the demo organizer to prove it wasn&amp;rsquo;t canned. It succeeded. The hardware hashing across the VLAGs is very slick. The VMware VSwitch integration worked well and was handy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/topicssecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 15:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/topicssecurity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sonicwall - Old dog learns [some] new tricks</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/sonicwall-old-dog-learns-some-new-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/sonicwall-old-dog-learns-some-new-tricks/</guid>
      <description>~12 years ago I had a drinking buddy that worked with me at the regional ISP. We had a lot in common, he had been an icon back in the didjits era of punk rock in Champaign Urbana and we had briefly been in a terrible band together. He introduced me to a dude that to this day I just knew as &amp;ldquo;Ravi Sonicwall&amp;rdquo;. He had apparently been recruited from the U of I, written a lot of the low level pieces of the original sonicwall and retired to enjoy life and buy beers (he actually scolded me at a bar for buying him a beer saying &amp;ldquo;when I&amp;rsquo;m in town, I buy the beers&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workflow and my mobile device setups.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/95/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 21:28:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/95/</guid>
      <description>Like many others, I rely heavily on my mobile devices to get my work done. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a user of the iPhone since the original, with a year on a Nexus one android device. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a strong preference and there are no &amp;ldquo;religious arguments&amp;rdquo; to be had with me on platform. In fact, I&amp;rsquo;d probably choose PamlOS if I had a choice, it&amp;rsquo;s simple elegance and stability were a comfort to me&amp;hellip;it just didn&amp;rsquo;t make it to modernization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting (back) to wordpress from Blogger</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/converting-back-to-wordpress-from-blogger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 19:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/converting-back-to-wordpress-from-blogger/</guid>
      <description>For a long time I ran a blog called tech.buraglio.com that was a self hosted wordpress site. After having kids and getting a bit busier at work, I decided to move everything that I had been hosting (images, scripts, hacks, blogs and DNS) to &amp;ldquo;the cloud&amp;rdquo;. I managed to do this for everything but my primary DNS resolver, which I had always intended to keep, and one wordpress blog that I hosted for someone else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDN across domains in the WAN - a novice look</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/sdn-across-domains-in-the-wan-a-novice-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 05:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/sdn-across-domains-in-the-wan-a-novice-look/</guid>
      <description>There has been a flurry of discussion on SDN in the WAN lately, specifically, why and how. Brent Salsbury laid out a few use cases here. The why seems pretty straightforward. I do believe it will happen, however, the how is the interesting part. Admittedly, I&amp;rsquo;m a tad of a greenhorn in the SDN space, I&amp;rsquo;ve made it work in a lab, I participate as much as I can in the working groups and I attempt (poorly) to keep up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a Brocade MLXe as a replicator to an IDS</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/using-a-brocade-mlxe-as-a-replicator-to-an-ids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 17:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/using-a-brocade-mlxe-as-a-replicator-to-an-ids/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever needed to replicate a lot of data transparently to an IDS without the use of a rack of optical taps? Not enough budget for a Gigamon or cPacket? Have a spare MLXe laying around? you&amp;rsquo;re in luck, we were in that boat too. Let me first preface this by saying that this would be fairly trivial using OpenFlow / SDN. That being said, we didn&amp;rsquo;t have the time to set that up, so this is what we came with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workflow and my every day workstation setup.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/workflow-and-my-every-day-workstation-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/workflow-and-my-every-day-workstation-setup/</guid>
      <description>Recently, there was a thread over at Packet Pushers about what folks use for their daily workflow. I quickly realized that my setup is pretty simple (as I like it) and relied on a large amount of terminal based tools, which makes sense since I have been a UNIX (or UNIX based) OS user since my migration from the original MacOS back in the 1990s. Anyway, Since I wrote most of this up already, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d post it here:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VDXrancid contrib scripts</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/vdxrancid-contrib-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 16:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/vdxrancid-contrib-scripts/</guid>
      <description>For the Supercomputing 2012 show, as in years past, I was &amp;ldquo;the guy who installed and maintained RANCID&amp;rdquo; as part of my duties for the SCinet routing team. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know about RANCID for change management and config back up, check the link. It&amp;rsquo;s ree and works on a huge amount of gear. Every year there is a new and interesting platform, this year is was Juniper qfabric and Brocade VDX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SCinet, a privileged few</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/scinet-a-privileged-few/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 11:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/scinet-a-privileged-few/</guid>
      <description>Every year there is an international conference for High Performance Computing, or HPC as it is often called. This is a bit of a niche in that it&amp;rsquo;s something that many enterprises and researchers need but don&amp;rsquo;t do themselves and so many don&amp;rsquo;t have a grasp as to what all is invoved. It&amp;rsquo;s a specialized, potentially expensive and very different environment as well as mindset than the general sysadmin or network engineer will ever see.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juniper EX 4200 ARP / NDP problem; or things I&#39;d like to see in a TAC</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/juniper-ex-4200-arp-ndp-problem-or-things-id-like-to-see-in-a-tac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 03:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/juniper-ex-4200-arp-ndp-problem-or-things-id-like-to-see-in-a-tac/</guid>
      <description>Recently we&amp;rsquo;ve run into an odd issue while routing on an EX4200 series. These little JunOS boxes are a nice alternative for an entry level building router, they support L2/L3 functionality, a PVST+-ish protocol and, with advanced licensing, IPv6, ISIS and BGP. They have multi 10G interface options and come in a pluggable fiber option. We use them all over for light layer 3. They can also be stacked via stacking cables and fiber, which is very handy and makes them extremely versatile but not really applicable for the purpose of this entry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And a purple pony.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/and-a-purple-pony/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 10:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/and-a-purple-pony/</guid>
      <description>If I had my perfect world where I lived in a gumdrop house with lollypop trees and everything smelled like butterfly kisses, here is what I would like to see in WAN networking gear. I can build a list for LAN and edge gear as well. It&amp;rsquo;s not a golden rocket ship I&amp;rsquo;m looking for. OK, maybe it is.
 Full MPLS support  Full IPv6 support, all the features, not just pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISIS or OSPFv2/3; a caveman case study</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/isis-or-ospfv23-a-caveman-case-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/isis-or-ospfv23-a-caveman-case-study/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Directionality</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/directionality-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 21:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/directionality-2/</guid>
      <description>As I sit here thinking if this site is worth my time, some words that someone said to me recently ring true. &amp;ldquo;Take from things you&amp;rsquo;re doing every day&amp;rdquo; is what Brent Salisbury of networkstatic.net said to me. He was right.
&amp;hellip;And it was why I originally started this site, in a way. The original goal was to make a site I could take notes on and possibly help out someone trying to solve the same issues as me or look at something from the same perspective I had.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Directionality</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/directionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 16:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/directionality/</guid>
      <description>As I sit here thinking if this site is worth my time, some words that someone said to me recently ring true. &amp;ldquo;Take from things you&amp;rsquo;re doing every day&amp;rdquo; is what Brent Salisbury of networkstatic.net said to me. He was right.
&amp;hellip;And it was why I originally started this site, in a way. The original goal was to make a site I could take notes on and possibly help out someone trying to solve the same issues as me or look at something from the same perspective I had.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certifications, worth the money in todays market?</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/certifications-worth-the-money-in-todays-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 22:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/certifications-worth-the-money-in-todays-market/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juniper to IOS conversion chart</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/juniper-to-ios-conversion-chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 20:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/juniper-to-ios-conversion-chart/</guid>
      <description>Moving to JunOS from IOS can be a daunting task. It&amp;rsquo;s a completely different command structure and the config, by default, looks like a programming language. I was fortunate enough to have gotten in on using JunOS very early in my career, 1&amp;frasl;3 in to be exact (as of this writing). Not to mention that wen I got started, IOS wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only game in town. Remember Xylan? Gandalf? OpenRoute?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDN, the disjointed project we all need to know about</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/sdn-the-disjointed-project-we-all-need-to-know-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 08:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/sdn-the-disjointed-project-we-all-need-to-know-about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Host based sflow, or, sflow for more than just network traffic</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/host-based-sflow-or-sflow-for-more-than-just-network-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 02:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/host-based-sflow-or-sflow-for-more-than-just-network-traffic/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m an awful sysadmin. Running services permanently isn&amp;rsquo;t really my forte, I tend to lean more on the &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll get this proof of concept all working, prove that it works or doesn&amp;rsquo;t, then roll it on for polishing by someone else&amp;rdquo; kinda guy. That final 15% is something I&amp;rsquo;m constantly working to refine and better myself at accomplishing. I&amp;rsquo;m decent at debugging network services, and can be handy in a &amp;ldquo;oh crap, it&amp;rsquo;s down!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MicroFlow policing on Cisco Sup2T</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/microflow-policing-on-cisco-sup2t/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 07:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/microflow-policing-on-cisco-sup2t/</guid>
      <description>Let me save you some time&amp;hellip;.Microflow Policing on the Catalyst 6500 / Sup2TXL doesn&amp;rsquo;t yet work. Inbound it &amp;ldquo;kinda works&amp;rdquo;. You can configure it and it applies as a service policy, but even though outbound is &amp;ldquo;supported in hardware on the Supervisor2TXL&amp;rdquo;, there is no software support for it in either the 15.0SY or 12.2(50)SY. It took me a month to suss this out&amp;hellip;..
Yes, I should have suspected. I dont work on Cisco every day, I have Juniper MX, Brocade MLX and a multitude of other platforms to work on daily, so it took a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A tale of two ISPs...</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/a-tale-of-two-isps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 11:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/a-tale-of-two-isps/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing research, carrier and service provider networking for a long time. I my first real service provider experience was beta testing DSL for GTE back in the 1990s, I prototyped and proposed a CLEC for an employer in 1998 and went to work for the only ISP in the area rolling it&amp;rsquo;s own DSL over ATM in early 2000.
Everything seems to come full circle, though, given enough time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Centers.....</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/data-centers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 09:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/data-centers/</guid>
      <description>Data centers are one of the hot things in networking tech right now. Combine SDN, cloud, buzzword of the day, mix with data center and serve over ice.
I end up doing a lot with data centers for whatever reason. This, however, is something I found interesting.
&amp;ldquo;DCTCP is an enhancement to the TCP congestion control algorithm for data center networks. It leverages Explicit Congestion Notification (ECN), a feature which is increasingly becoming available in modern data center switches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>conditional route advertisement</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/conditional-route-advertisement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 02:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/conditional-route-advertisement/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been tasked with bringing up a tertiary path into a multi-building research facility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSR and ISSU on Juniper MX series with logical routers.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nsr-and-issu-on-juniper-mx-series-with-logical-routers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nsr-and-issu-on-juniper-mx-series-with-logical-routers/</guid>
      <description>Lets just say, for instance, that you have an MX series router at somewhere on your network. Lets also say that said router is carved into more than just the main logical system. For the sake of this writing, lets say that your eBGP sessions are in the default logical system and your IGP is in the logical system, lets call it &amp;ldquo;internal&amp;rdquo;.
JunOS has some wonderful mechanisms for keeping things running, one is called NSR (Non Stop Routing), the other is called ISSU (In Service Software Upgrade).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking more deeply into iMessage</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/looking-more-deeply-into-imessage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 23:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/looking-more-deeply-into-imessage/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at iMessage from time to time as my schedule permits, for some reason that I can&amp;rsquo;t really explain I&amp;rsquo;m fixated on it. So, just like I did with FaceTime, I started doing network sniffing to see just what it&amp;rsquo;s doing. The results were not terribly unexpected.  iPhone.buraglio.com.53140 &amp;gt; st11p01st-courier143-bz.push.apple.com.5223: Flags [R], cksum 0x5ec8 (correct), seq 4109691913, win 0, length 0
14:07:51.665485 IP (tos 0x20, ttl 49, id 11699, offset 0, flags [DF], proto TCP (6), length 64, bad cksum 0 (-&amp;gt;8fc7)!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A quick post about ARP Networks hosting.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/a-quick-post-about-arp-networks-hosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/a-quick-post-about-arp-networks-hosting/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a co-located server in one way or another for the last 11 years. From hosting a bare metal box at the ISP I worked for for a while, to sharing a bare metal box at a colo provider to switching to a VPS service, I&amp;rsquo;ve always had an &amp;ldquo;offsite box&amp;rdquo;.
I just wanted to post a quick &amp;ldquo;these guys are great&amp;rdquo; comment to my current VPS provider, ARP Networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A security oversight in Mail.app, or, a hidden bcc: field</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/a-security-oversight-in-mail-app-or-a-hidden-bcc-field/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2011 08:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/a-security-oversight-in-mail-app-or-a-hidden-bcc-field/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was poking around Mail.app, setting up my new machine. I like to keep redundant copies of everything, email being no exception. I have backups of all of my email dating back to 1998, for the most part. It has come in handy from time to time and I like it for reference reasons. It&amp;rsquo;s a small amount of actual data as far as space goes, and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iMessage: I&#39;ve been left wanting</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/imessage-ive-been-left-wanting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2011 20:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/imessage-ive-been-left-wanting/</guid>
      <description>I had very high hopes for iMessage. With the release of iOS 5, one of the big new features was iMessage, the ability to do Blackberry messenger style messaging on an iOS device. I had really hoped that this would be something like wifisms or the DeskSMS app for Android. At the very least I was hoping for iChat integration with iMessage.
This didn&amp;rsquo;t happen.
Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, iMessage is still really cool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ftps (secure ftp) from the command line</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ftps-secure-ftp-from-the-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 04:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ftps-secure-ftp-from-the-command-line/</guid>
      <description>I have recently enabled Duo Security for many of my personal services, and I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend them enough. Personal two factor authentication is very useful and really powerful. It works on my iPhone and I have yet to run into any real issues&amp;hellip;.except for one. I can&amp;rsquo;t use automation to scp or sftp anything anymore and keep my two factor auth working in a way I&amp;rsquo;m comfortable with.
Enter ftps. FTP is a terrible, yet immensely useful protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Hole routing</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/black-hole-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/black-hole-routing/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s no secret or ground breaking area to do black hole routing.
ISPs and NSPs have been doing it forever to allow for a very low cost, very scriptable and very effective way to wholesale block a layer3 address. However, it can seem like a bit of a black box to anyone who has never done it.
I recently did some work spinning this up in a good sized network that it didn&amp;rsquo;t currently exist, and remembered how monumentally useful (and simple) it actually is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoogleCL, command line based google blogger, picasa, calendar and much, much more.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/googlecl-command-line-based-google-blogger-picasa-calendar-and-much-much-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 03:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/googlecl-command-line-based-google-blogger-picasa-calendar-and-much-much-more/</guid>
      <description>Google has introduced a very powerful set of python based command line (CLI) tools called GoogleCL. This post was made using GoogleCL from my Mac. I highly recommend checking it out if you like to automate or script stuff.
[[ This is a content summary only. Visit my website for full links, other content, and more! ]]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching from MacPorts to Homebrew</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/switching-from-macports-to-homebrew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 17:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/switching-from-macports-to-homebrew/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently decided that even though I love the BSD style MacPorts system, it can be too clunky to maintain and doesn&amp;rsquo;t handle dependancies as well as I&amp;rsquo;d like (much like the actual BSD ports collection). So, in doing a little looking I found that Fink is still out of date, but Homebrew is very simple and also really elegant comparatively speaking.
Since homebrew doesn&amp;rsquo;t wrk well with other packge systems installed, and I already</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MacOS 10.7 and IPv6 privacy addressing</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/macos-10-7-and-ipv6-privacy-addressing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 02:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/macos-10-7-and-ipv6-privacy-addressing/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of IPv6 privacy addressing. I understand the logic behind it, I really doo, obfuscate the LLADDR (MAC address) of the host in question, but I really dont&amp;rsquo;t see the realistic purpose. If someone wanted to use my mac address, what good would that really get them, unless they&amp;rsquo;re on the same layer 2 segment? More importantly, if they;re on the same layer 2 segment, they have my MAC address anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSX (10.7; Lion) DHCPv6 client working with pfsense server.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/osx-10-7-lion-dhcpv6-client-working-with-pfsense-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 18:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/osx-10-7-lion-dhcpv6-client-working-with-pfsense-server/</guid>
      <description>It looks like MacOS 10.7 (Lion) has fully functioning DHCPv6. It&amp;rsquo;s about time.
Before:

After:

pfSense setup:

Using Internet Systems Consortium DHCP Server 4.2.1-P1 as the server (on my pfSense box) I am able to get not only a privacy address (via stateless autoconfigure) but also a normal EUI-64 address as well as an IPv6 address via dhcpv6.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything except use the &amp;ldquo;Automatic&amp;rdquo; setting in the network control panel, so out of the box OSX 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint Techs Summer 2011 IPv6 talks</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/joint-techs-summer-2011-ipv6-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 09:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/joint-techs-summer-2011-ipv6-talks/</guid>
      <description>If anyone is interested in the talks I participated in at Joint Techs in Fairbanks, AK, they are now on the internet2 sites.
IPv6 feature support
IPv6 campus panel discussion
They&amp;rsquo;re apparently not embeddable, but can be watched from the Joint Techs site.
[[ This is a content summary only. Visit my website for full links, other content, and more! ]]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>alurancid and pfrancid</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/alurancid-and-pfrancid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 20:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/alurancid-and-pfrancid/</guid>
      <description>I did some minor tweaking to the Alcatel Lucent RANCID scripts and some modifications to make RANCID work under my pfsense environment (originally m0n0rancid code from John Skopis). Since I don&amp;rsquo;t really do much dev work and am not interested in maintaing a box do be an SVN server for the public, I threw it up onto google code.
I&amp;rsquo;ll be adding a brief how-to on making RANCID work with pfSense as soon as I get some time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better support for Linux (and annoyed about it)</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/better-support-for-linux-and-annoyed-about-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 08:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/better-support-for-linux-and-annoyed-about-it/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a *BSD user since around 1997, when I installed NetBSD on a Mac SE 30 that I got for free. I was always intrigued with alternative operating systems like BeOS, *BSD, Plan9 and Linux so it made sense that I&amp;rsquo;d poke around with different systems.
I&amp;rsquo;d gone back and forth from OpenBSD to FreeBSD but eventually settled on FreeBSD as my OS of choice. I ran it as a desktop before MacOS X came out and was generally happy with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juniper interface type naming convention</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/juniper-interface-type-naming-convention/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 01:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/juniper-interface-type-naming-convention/</guid>
      <description>I found most of this on a web page somewhere tha tI can&amp;rsquo;t seem to find again. Below are some common useful junos tidbits regarding routing tables and interface types/names:
JunOS CLI supports the basic grep command (like | include) so any show commands can be grepped. I believe the grep command implies the -i flag for case insensitivity.
The routing table is presented in such a way to group types of routes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv6 Features matrix for Network Hardware</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ipv6-features-matrix-for-network-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 21:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ipv6-features-matrix-for-network-hardware/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot of IPv6 stuff lately, and one of the things I didn&amp;rsquo;t find (and kinda just wanted to put one together for my own benefit) is a matrix of features I thought were important to have on the IPv6 side for common network hardware. Below is a work in progress of what I have so far, which will automatically publish changes from this spreadsheet. Please email me if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in adding to this or correcting anything I may be incorrect on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sync catalogs (iPhoto, iTunes) on a mac</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/sync-catalogs-iphoto-itunes-on-a-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 12:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/sync-catalogs-iphoto-itunes-on-a-mac/</guid>
      <description>I have huge iPhoto and iTunes catalogs. This can present a problem for both loading the applications and for backup. I have learned to deal with the Application load times, but backups are very important to me.
I&amp;rsquo;d gone through the iPhoto backup process and restore more than once, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the fact that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have an offsite backup, so I paid for a flickr pro account ($24/yr, supports iPhoto export and RAW format).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading a new SRX 3600</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/upgrading-a-new-srx-3600/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 22:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/upgrading-a-new-srx-3600/</guid>
      <description>We are putting a few new SRX 3600 clusters into production soon, and we&amp;rsquo;ve had them for about 6 months in boxes. This presented a fairly significant issue, one that I didn&amp;rsquo;t think about until it smacked me in the face.
The code on these boxes was old. Very old. JunOS 9.2 old.
No problem, lets just upgrade them to 10.4R something.
Wrong.
the code that shipped on these boxes was so old, and we waited so long to upgrade them that I was unable to upgrade them straight to anything modern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seagate FreeAgent 3T drive on a mac</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/seagate-freeagent-3t-drive-on-a-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2011 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/seagate-freeagent-3t-drive-on-a-mac/</guid>
      <description>I was recently helping my brother-in-law out with the new Seagate FreeAgent GoFlex Desk 3 TB USB 3.0 External Hard Drivehe had purchased to do time machine backups on his mac. I personally have the 2t version and have been pretty happy with it, save for one small incident that I think was my fault that required some basic data recovery.
Since the drive comes in a file system that is not HFS+ Journaled, it needed to be reformatted to support time machine backups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving JunOS code between SRX cluster nodes</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/moving-junos-code-between-srx-cluster-nodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 02:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/moving-junos-code-between-srx-cluster-nodes/</guid>
      <description>Regardless of the fact that there is now a good ISSU-like service for the SRX (named Low-Impact Cluster Upgrade; LICU for short), if you&amp;rsquo;re upgrading your Active/Active cluster from something that isn&amp;rsquo;t 10.4, or if you just aren&amp;rsquo;t comfortable with how baked LICU actually is, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to know how to move the junos code around. This is easy if you have physical access to both nodes, but for those that have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JunOS ISSU</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/junos-issu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2010 00:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/junos-issu/</guid>
      <description>I recently needed to upgrade a few MX480 routers and decided that it would be a good opportunity to get some experience with Juniper&amp;rsquo;s in service software upgrade.
I&amp;rsquo;d read a bit about it but I&amp;rsquo;d not had the chance to really use it. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty straightforward and it does what it claims. The following are my notes from rolling through this on my test lab MX480.
A few things are necessary to get going with ISSU, first and foremost, you need to have a box with two routing engines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A bit of IPv6 humor for the holidays</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/a-bit-of-ipv6-humor-for-the-holidays/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 03:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/a-bit-of-ipv6-humor-for-the-holidays/</guid>
      <description>A quick screen grab from here
[[ This is a content summary only. Visit my website for full links, other content, and more! ]]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alcatel Lucent RANCID scripts</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/alcatel-lucent-rancid-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 07:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/alcatel-lucent-rancid-scripts/</guid>
      <description>At the 2010 Supercomputing conference this year, one of my tasks was to get RANCID working on the Alcatel Lucent 77xx series. for some this may have been a simple task, but for me, a self taught and inefficient programmer, it was something that took some time.
The Alcatel Lucent boxes were good performers, but their CLI is pretty awful. The prompt changes based on having unsaved configuration items, and can contain things liks an asterisk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling IPv6 on Juniper SRX 5800 cluster</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/enabling-ipv6-on-juniper-srx-5800-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2010 21:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/enabling-ipv6-on-juniper-srx-5800-cluster/</guid>
      <description>After enabling the IPv6 Flow based processing, we decided to get rolling with making our IPv6 path congruent with everything else (IPv4 unicast and multicast). With all of the other things we had going on, we thought this would be a low hanging fruit that would be easily plucked from the routing tree. Well, a minor oversight on our part caught us by surprise.
According to this handy dandy matrix for JunOS 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multicast through Juniper SRX 5800</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/multicast-through-juniper-srx-5800/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2010 23:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/multicast-through-juniper-srx-5800/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been working toward a more simplified model for our network path, and in doing so, we desired a congruent path for IPv6, IPv4 Multicast and IPv4 Unicast.
However, this is actually pretty hard when dealing with the link speeds, amounts of traffic and flows that we do, in conjunction with Firewall&amp;hellip;..and IDP/IPS&amp;hellip;
Lots of research, reading and testing was done.
Juniper SRX series has full support for 90% of this, with IPv6 IDP coming in Q2 of 2011.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android (Nexus One) or iPhone?</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/android-nexus-one-or-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 09:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/android-nexus-one-or-iphone/</guid>
      <description>*Cross posted from my personal blog since it&amp;rsquo;s a technical subject*

That is the million dollar question on many phone geeks minds.
The iPhone is really a love it or hate it kind of device, much like Apple stuff in general. Android, on the other hand, is still new enough that some folks are still ignoring it. Well, I wanted to know which worked better for me, and so I set out to test them both.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone 4 or Android 2.2?</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/iphone-4-or-android-2-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2010 17:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/iphone-4-or-android-2-2/</guid>
      <description>I have been fortunate enough to have had a decent smartphone for the last 8 or so years, and mid to</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SRX IPv6 flow based processing</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/srx-ipv6-flow-based-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2010 17:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/srx-ipv6-flow-based-processing/</guid>
      <description>One of our plans is to consolidate as many of the egress trafic paths as possible. To facilitate this, we had to do some things like buy carrier grade equipment. Enter the SRX 5800. No one really does IPS/IDP+Firewall quite like the SRX. After extensive research and exhaustive hands on testing with quite a bit of equipment, that is what we settled on. Even the IBM &amp;ldquo;technical evangelist&amp;rdquo; guy that came to talk to us said &amp;ldquo;No one really does it like they do&amp;rdquo; when referring to Juniper and 10G firewall/IPS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAT IPv4 and Public IPv6</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nat-ipv4-and-public-ipv6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2010 23:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nat-ipv4-and-public-ipv6/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently taken to thinking a lot more about IPv6. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using an HE tunnel for as long as I can remember at home. This poses an interesting question about addressing. Since I have not had a public address block at home for almost 7 years, I have been using NAT for IPv4. However, my IPv6 netblocks are a /64 and a /48, which are both far more address space than I could ever possibly use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFS mounting a NAS with MacOS 10.6 (Snow Leopard)</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nfs-mounting-a-nas-with-macos-10-6-snow-leopard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2010 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/nfs-mounting-a-nas-with-macos-10-6-snow-leopard/</guid>
      <description>I know this is documented elsewhere, but this was a pain for me, so I wanted to take some notes. I have several Snow Leopard (MAcOS 10.6) Macs and a Netgear DNS-323. I want to mount the drive using NFS and any good UNIX admin would.
Unlike older versions of the Mac OS, NFS mounts are now handled under the Disk Utility application (which seems odd to me, but whatever).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viewing ipv6 router advertisements</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/viewing-ipv6-router-advertisements/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2010 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/viewing-ipv6-router-advertisements/</guid>
      <description>I knew a tool like this had to exist, but I had never needed to look in the past. While debugging a RA problem, I come upon the need to view IPv6 router advertisements. How can one do this? tcpdump? Yeah, I guess that could work. It&amp;rsquo;s almost like using a bulldozer when a wheelbarrow is all you need, though. I could use ndpmon, I suppose, but that, too seems like overkill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting IPv6 precedence under FreeBSD</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/setting-ipv6-precedence-under-freebsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 18:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/setting-ipv6-precedence-under-freebsd/</guid>
      <description>I had been discussing IPv6 address precedence recently and realized that I&amp;rsquo;d never really messed with it. I have a FreeBSD host that has multiple IPv6 addresses, an EUI-64 address as well as a statically assigned address. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what IPv6 or EUI-64 is, I suggest you brush up because IPv6 is coming and it&amp;rsquo;s coming sooner than you thing.
Using the ip6addrctl command I can manipulate which address is preferred for outbound connections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating SRX IDP signatures</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/updating-srx-idp-signatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 18:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/updating-srx-idp-signatures/</guid>
      <description>*IDP signatures need to be updated often. On the SRX platform, there is also the notion of a &amp;ldquo;detector&amp;rdquo;. This also meeds to be updated on a regular basis. it seems. Over the past few weeks, we&amp;rsquo;ve needed to update the IDP signatures and detector on our SRX 5800 cluster several times, and the results have normally been fine.
Updating the IDP signatures has never been that big of a problem (see postings about updating stuff on cluster nodes).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RADIUS and AAA on IOS</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/radius-and-aaa-on-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 00:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/radius-and-aaa-on-ios/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not the greatest at AAA on Cisco&amp;rsquo;s IOS. I always have to think about how to order things, and to test fallback (which you should do anyway). One of the caveats that I always overlook, no matter how many times I set this up, is that Cisco IOS software attempts authentication with the next listed authentication method only when there is no response from the previous method. If authentication fails at any point in this cycle—meaning that the security server or local username database responds by denying the user access—the authentication process stops and no other authentication methods are attempted*.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SRX Timeouts and the differences with Netscreen</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/srx-timeouts-and-the-differences-with-netscreen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 04:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/srx-timeouts-and-the-differences-with-netscreen/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juniper SRX Cluster</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/juniper-srx-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 04:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/juniper-srx-cluster/</guid>
      <description>I have had the opportunity to work pretty extensively on the Juniper SRX firewall/IDS platform over the last few months. In doing so, I&amp;rsquo;ve found many &amp;ldquo;gotchas&amp;rdquo; the hard way.
Here are a few that I&amp;rsquo;ve found so far:
Clustering is a beast in and of itself. I think it needs a bit more polishing, but it could be that we just need to refine our design.
On the SRX 650 it works, but you must be on the right code version (I got it to work under 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SRX ALGs</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/srx-algs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 04:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/srx-algs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;IOS-Like&#34; stifles innovation</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/888/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/888/</guid>
      <description>In the day and age of SDN, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the tried and true CLI. Lets be honest, in a world where there are 10+ year old network devices still in production, it&amp;rsquo;s not going away any time soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Next-Generation&#34; is a bunk term</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/889/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/889/</guid>
      <description>I recently had a conversation with Brent Salisbury that re-introduced a bit of a hot button with me. The term &amp;ldquo;next-generation&amp;rdquo; is over used and at this point arguably meaningless. So many things are labeled &amp;ldquo;next-generation&amp;rdquo; that, while technically true, they may be the next in a line of product, the term has entered marketing typecast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100G on a Juniper MX480</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/278/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/278/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a new RANCID group</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/806/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/806/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BGP is not a routing protocol</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/793/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/793/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BGP-LS</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/916/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/916/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BGPPlay</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1055/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1055/</guid>
      <description>This has been a favorite troubleshooting and information tool of mine since its inception as a Java App. Now re-written by the RIPE NCC&amp;hellip;.BGPlay!
ripestat.init(&amp;ldquo;bgplay&amp;rdquo;,{&amp;ldquo;unix_timestamps&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;TRUE&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;ignoreReannouncements&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;rrcs&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;0,1,6,7,11,14,3,4,5,10,12,13,15&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;resource&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;141.142.0.0/16&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;starttime&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;1410023700&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;endtime&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;1410207300&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;instant&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;null&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;type&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;bgp&amp;rdquo;},null,{&amp;ldquo;show_controls&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;disable&amp;rdquo;:[]})</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a [net/s]flow collector with CentOS, nfdump and nfsen</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/332/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/332/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a logical networking inside one Juniper MX</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/601/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/601/</guid>
      <description>Logical systems are something that JunOS has done very, very right. Regardless of if you need to create segregated administrative domains, routing domains or just labbing something up, this is a fantastic tool in the Juniper toolbox. If you&amp;rsquo;re lucky enough to have an MX series available for testing, you&amp;rsquo;re already half way there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLI rosetta stone</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/968/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/968/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting from Brocade (Foundry) MLX to Juniper MX</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/750/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/750/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps vs. SDN: It&#39;s the left hand vs. the right.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1035/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1035/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t fear the reaper</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/664/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/664/</guid>
      <description>I have been buried in stuff to work on lately. The amazing part of this is that it is all very interesting and things I want to do and learn. The exhausting part is that there is an overwhelming amount of it. It is a good problem to have. The list of things goes on and on (and obviously I don&amp;rsquo;t do all of this stuff by myself, we have an amazing team) but the short list is a pretty tall order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ElastiFlow Base VM</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1706/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1706/</guid>
      <description>Included here is a vanilla Ubuntu 18 LTS VM with a basic Elastiflow install. This includes all of the components of an ElasticStack plus the front end pieces of the ElastiFlow project. Most of the install is based on this how-to. Included in the image is also a base install of NGINX and certbot so that you can reverse proxy the access and have a valid SSL certificate. This was build and validated on Proxmox 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Floodlight OpenFlow Firewall</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/610/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/610/</guid>
      <description>curl http://localhost:8080/wm/firewall/module/enable/json `````` curl http://localhost:8080/wm/firewall/module/status/json  Add allow rule: curl -X POST -d &#39;{&amp;quot;[00:00:00:12:f2:91:58:00](http://128.174.43.242:8080/switch/00:00:00:12:f2:91:58:00)&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;00:00:00:00:00:00:00:01&amp;quot;}&#39; http://localhost:8080/wm/firewall/rules/json  http://docs.projectfloodlight.org/display/floodlightcontroller/Firewall+%28Dev%29</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Floodlight OpenFlow Firewall</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/614/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/614/</guid>
      <description>curl http://localhost:8080/wm/firewall/module/enable/json `````` curl http://localhost:8080/wm/firewall/module/status/json  Add allow rule:
curl -X POST -d &#39;{&amp;quot;[00:00:00:12:f2:91:58:00](http://128.174.43.242:8080/switch/00:00:00:12:f2:91:58:00)&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;00:00:00:00:00:00:00:01&amp;quot;}&#39; http://localhost:8080/wm/firewall/rules/json `````` http://docs.projectfloodlight.org/display/floodlightcontroller/Firewall+%28Dev%29  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Lab for, security OpenFlow and Virtualizaation</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/934/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/934/</guid>
      <description>http://ethancbanks.com/2014/03/15/my-home-lab-esxi-5-5-server-build-and-the-logic-behind-it-all/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I made a Sup2T-XL very unhappy</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/162/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/162/</guid>
      <description>Some people have a need to push hardware to it&amp;rsquo;s limits. Generally, I end up being one of those people. I must admit, I enjoy seeing how far things can be pushed, especially when it yields new and or interesting gains or knowledge. One of the things that I needed to do was to rate limit a large set of addresses, but to allow unfettered access to other resources. It&amp;rsquo;s possible there may be a better way to do this, but all of my other attempts to do this failed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the internet really works in practice</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1111/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1111/</guid>
      <description>The Border Gateway Protocol (BGPv4) is the foundation of the modern internet. Without it we would still be in the information dark ages and interconnectivity as we know it would not exist. One would assume, quite incorrectly I might add, that this foundational protocol is robust, secure and optimally configured to shepherd us through the daily use of this critical resource. While BGP has the capability of being all of those things, in practice it&amp;rsquo;s really not done that way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to index your flow data and why you should</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1396/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1396/</guid>
      <description>Are you indexing your flow data? You should be. My new favorite flow collector isn&amp;rsquo;t even a flow collector. It&amp;rsquo;s two of the three parts of an ELK stack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Floodlight Forwarding Module under CentOS</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/465/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/465/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing my base CentOS system</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/324/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/324/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing nprobe and ntop-ng for flow analysis</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/installing-nprobe-ntop-ng-flow-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/installing-nprobe-ntop-ng-flow-analysis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juniper EX4550 first impressions.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/336/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/336/</guid>
      <description>Much less noise. That was my initial thought when this box was first powered. The 4500 sounds like a jet engine. I was particularly excited about the Juniper EX4550 because it addressed a number of things that were less than ideal about the EX4500. Soem of the differences ciuyld be argued as either oa pro or con depending on deployment scanerio, but for what we&amp;rsquo;re looking for, the 4550 is far better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juniper make an SDN play that I can get [a little] excited about</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/811/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/811/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juniper to purchase WANDL and why it&#39;s important</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/856/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/856/</guid>
      <description>It was recently announced that Juniper Networks would be purchasing WANDL, a long time partner and</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Network Namespaces for multihomed hosts</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1014/</guid>
      <description>sudo ip netns exec uc2b ip link list ip netns exec uc2b ifconfig uc2b1 192.80.111.58&amp;frasl;24 up sudo ip netns exec uc2b ifconfig uc2b1 192.80.111.58&amp;frasl;24 up sudo ovs-vsctl add-port br-int uc2b1 ip netns exec uc2b ip link set uc2b1 up sudo ip netns exec uc2b ip link set uc2b1 up sudo brctl addbr uc2bbr sudo brctl ifbr uc2bbr uc2b1 sudo brctl addif uc2bbr uc2b1 sudo brctl delbr uc2bbr sudo ovs-vsctl add-port br-int uc2b1 sudo ovs-vsctl add-port br-int uc2b1 sudo ovs-vsctl add-br uc2bbr uc2b1 sudo ovs-vsctl add-br uc2bbr sudo ovs-vsctl add-port uc2bbr uc2b1 sudo ovs-vsctl add-port uc2bbr eth1 sudo ip netns exec uc2b ifconfig uc2b1 192.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networks are insecure. Here&#39;s why.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1409/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1409/</guid>
      <description>Networks are insecure, they just are. I once worked with an FBI agent who said that if you wanted a secure network you should turn everything off, smash it, then set it on fire - and I don&amp;rsquo;t disagree. However, there are things we can do to understand our networks that will aid immeasurably in how they are secured and initially and how they remain secured over time. At their very core networks are not secure based simply on the fact that humans are involved in their construction, operation, and use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFD Disclaimer</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1138/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1138/</guid>
      <description>NFD Disclaimer: Tech Field Day is covering my travel and miscellaneous costs for this event. They in turn are paid by their sponsors. I am under no obligation to write anything about any of the presentations, favorable or otherwise. All opinions expressed are my own and in no way reflect any other entities other than myself. In addition, they are simply opinions based on my experiences and the facts known at the time of posting and should be thought of as such.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenFlow migration paths</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/595/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/595/</guid>
      <description>SDN gateways have a much more traditional look and feel. They have a flat SDN OpenFlow network with a default gateway for client traffic by either controller proxy or direct reachability by the client host. Note that both approaches suffer from lack of adoption and maturity, which adds risk to any early production SDN. IPv6-like</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>perfSonar and Rasberry pie.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/576/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/576/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PerfSonar tools on a raspberry pi</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/821/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/821/</guid>
      <description>I want to preface this by saying that this was an experiment for me. That said, I know there are folks that want to run everything under the sun on a pi. So, since I love the platform as well, I set out to try to make the raspberry pi a perfsonar &amp;ldquo;probe&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RYU OpenFlow controller</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/435/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/435/</guid>
      <description>Ryu, an openflow controller, was new to me. After doing 5 minutes of reading I knew I needed to get it up in the lab. The thing that caught my eye was that the project page was boasting support for OpenStack. Now, I don;t really have much experience with openstack, but it has a cult like following and it&amp;rsquo;s on my short list of stuff to get involved with. This seemed like a great excuse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SD-WAN: The service provider perspective.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1371/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1371/</guid>
      <description>Buzz, Buzz, Buzz. The SDN sites are all abuzz with talk about how your enterprise network can take advantage of the deluge of new products and services out there aimed at that market, and that&amp;rsquo;s great - there are some cool options out there for that space. But, like I always do, I want to talk about the other pieces that most people do not see. The gritty plumbing and complex interconnections of the last mile providers, because there are a lot of very interesting moving parts there that the typical data center engineers don&amp;rsquo;t see, care about, or perhaps even know exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security as a service</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/699/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/699/</guid>
      <description>I recently had a very interesting and enjoyable conversation about firewall placement in a campus environment. Firewall in the center Firewall at the edge Firewall closest to the resource it needs to protect</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Onion for the Network Engineer: Flows</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/803/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/803/</guid>
      <description>Argus Netflow IPv6</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing and using Wireguard</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1580/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1580/</guid>
      <description>https://www.wireguard.com/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The unrealized expectations of SDN</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1374/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/1374/</guid>
      <description>I have been remiss in writing in the last year, the reasons are unimportant, but regardless, I&amp;rsquo;ve been paying very close attention. It&amp;rsquo;s 2017 and it is SOAPBOX time again! SDN has been a &amp;ldquo;thing&amp;rdquo; since ~2008, with the publication and popularization of the OpenFlow protocol. It&amp;rsquo;s 2017. How much has this industry changing technology is running outside of the hyper scale data centers? We&amp;rsquo;ve seen companies rise and companies disappear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The value of not being involved</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/808/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/808/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transparency in a competitive industry</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/397/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/397/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing the network with LLDP</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/965/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/965/</guid>
      <description>http://www.reeleysoft.com/?p=105</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMWare, NSX, homogeneity and even Cisco..</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/788/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/788/</guid>
      <description>The networking world has been abuzz with talk of VMWares NSX announcement, Cisco&amp;rsquo;s CTO response to that, and heavy speculation of what that means. If you&amp;rsquo;re curious about NSX, Ivan Pepelnjak over at ioshints has a great write up explaining what it is and isn&amp;rsquo;t. I enjoyed the read quite a bit. Speculation generally makes me jittery, so I have spent some time thinking about this, reading and trying to understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why hardware firewalls are the walking dead, part II</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/900/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/900/</guid>
      <description>FlowSpec.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I want OpenFlow (it&#39;s not what you think)</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/951/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/951/</guid>
      <description>OpenFlow is a game changer, no question about it. With all of the buzz about it, I really don&amp;rsquo;t think we&amp;rsquo;re seeing past its real value, most are focusing on the data center and potentially not seeing the forest for the trees. I don&amp;rsquo;t really care about the gooey center of the data center. I&amp;rsquo;ve built, maintained, consulted on or in some way supported so many HPC data centers in the last 12 years that I find them dull at this point*.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you need a privacy screen</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/953/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/953/</guid>
      <description>In a slight deviation from a lot of deep networking, I thought it would be a</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>