<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Crystal Ball on ForwardingPlane.net</title>
    <link>https://forwardingplane.net/tags/crystal-ball/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Crystal Ball on ForwardingPlane.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2019, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 22:53:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://forwardingplane.net/tags/crystal-ball/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategy Series: Build vs. Buy (sorta)</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/strategy-series-build-vs-buy-sorta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 22:53:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/strategy-series-build-vs-buy-sorta/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Build vs. buy is an often lamented and always hotly debated question in all aspects of IT, however, if one is able to truly look at all angles the answer is typically straightforward and can be rooted in one simple strategy: don&amp;rsquo;t reinvent the wheel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;don-t-reinvent-the-wheel&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t reinvent the wheel&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too many times we as an industry don&amp;rsquo;t do our homework - we are all guilty of it - and we reinvent a wheel. Make no mistake, there are true reasons to revisit, revise and reinvent. Lets use an example that &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/buraglio/pfrancid&#34;&gt;I&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/buraglio/vdxrancid&#34;&gt;am&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/buraglio/alurancid&#34;&gt;fairly&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/buraglio/sonrancid&#34;&gt;familiar&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/buraglio/cienarancid&#34;&gt;with&lt;/a&gt;: RANCID &lt;a href=&#34;http://shrubbery.net/rancid/&#34;&gt;RANCID&lt;/a&gt; code is 20+ years old and pretty messy. RANCID3 is a rewrite that in my opinion makes the already confusing ball of Perl, Expect, and shell even more confusing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ytti/oxidized&#34;&gt;Oxidized&lt;/a&gt; made that process more elegant and arguably more flexible and extensible. That was a good call. Build vs buy is a tough question and as an industry we tend to think about resources in a lopsided way, which further increases that complexity. Resources have always been and will always be finite, and no matter if you build or buy, you are expending your resources. Lets break down the resources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s pretty much the extent of it. Everything else is driven by this. Time coasts money. It costs money in the form of salaries, overtime, downtime, etc. In IT we describe things in terms of uptime. Five 9&amp;rsquo;s is the uptime we strive for. When we have downtime, it costs money in the form of lost income or expense to repair and often both. Salaries are paid based on time, hourly, weekly, monthly, yearly. Employes trade their time for that salary regardless of how it is structured. You pay for resources that make more efficient use of time. Employers often fall into one of two buckets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Able to hire FTE (OPEX)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Able to pay vendors (CAPEX)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously this isn&amp;rsquo;t always the case, but it&amp;rsquo;s very common - and if we conveniently overlook those environments that are jut to conservative to consider OPEX (i.e. they always choose buy and generally fall into the &amp;ldquo;able to pay vendors&amp;rdquo; category), it&amp;rsquo;s fairly easy to map build vs buy into those models. Can you support running open source or white box solutions, operationally? Will the OPEX actually save you money when compared to the CAPEX changes they require to make happen? Should you pay for an off the shelf solution and hope that the support you buy can address the issues you&amp;rsquo;ll have? [&lt;em&gt;My strong opinion is that they almost never can, but the comfort that they provide to legal departments and C level execs is what they actually purchase&lt;/em&gt;] It is important to note that different environments introduce very different edge cases, and with many highly technical people, these edge cases have a tendency to creep in and drive a large part of our architectures, but it also gives us a veneer over our needs and requirements process that makes it easier to say &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;re special and we have hard requirements for not only A and B but also C, D, E and F&amp;rdquo;. C, D, E, and F are likely so edge case that we really don&amp;rsquo;t *need* them. This is where It gets messy and where the hyperscalers have done it right: Say no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com/gifs/reactionseditor-3o7btT1T9qpQZWhNlK&#34;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt; Interdomain multicast? Nope. Requirements for full global tables on every device? Nope. If we really ask ourselves if the requirements are actually requirements or if they are simply desirable because they may make things easier or may satisfy a 5-10% use use case, then maybe we should revisit how we&amp;rsquo;re actually developing our needs and requirements. Mapping business (or other strategic) requirements into technology can be difficult, especially if there is no direct correlation to profit or loss. We are a culture of wheel inventors and we embrace it, but 80-85% of the time our wheels can be dead simple and still roll us where we need to go. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What we get &amp;ldquo;for free&amp;rdquo; with that is standardization and ease of management&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (lower CAPEX). If we look back at history as an example, no sane person wants to run a network that routes AppleTalk, IPX, IPv4, IPv6 and transits DECNet. that sucked. It was too complicated. It was buggy. We simplified it down to IPv[&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;] and low and behold most of the gear got more stable, configurations got simpler, and networks got easier to run. We should learn from that. Make no mistake, I realize that reinventing wheels to make them roll faster, longer, etc. is called innovation. However, along with our needs and requirements we need to put serious consideration into our business strategy. Is our business to innovate? Are we going to see direct or indirect improvements to CAPEX or OPEX if we &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; innovate. Are we factoring in the &lt;em&gt;cost&lt;/em&gt; of the innovation? Where this starts to get even more fuzzy is in the opensource world. In this space &amp;ldquo;build&amp;rdquo; can be defined as self supporting, meaning &amp;ldquo;use of opensource products with no formal or contractual support structure&amp;rdquo;, which a very large amount of organizations are very wary of (and many actively avoid). These are all important questions that must be addresses when deciding on the strategy of build vs buy - it&amp;rsquo;s not as straight forward and simple of a question as &amp;ldquo;build or buy&amp;rdquo;, it seems. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a different perspective on a very similar topic, check &lt;a href=&#34;https://rule11.tech&#34;&gt;Russ White&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s (yes, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/riw777/&#34;&gt;THAT Russ White&lt;/a&gt;) post on &lt;a href=&#34;https://rule11.tech/enterprise-versus-provider/&#34;&gt;Enterprise vs. Provider&lt;/a&gt;. While not entirely similar, it points out that we have problems and solutions, and that knowing what both of those are is critical to success regardless of their ecosystem. This is key. We need to look at the whole picture. &lt;em&gt;My take: We need to look at the entire picture. It&amp;rsquo;s not as simple as one question. Personally I tend to lean more toward build, but for the majority of my career I was in environments that had extremely clued engineers and support staff. Is this for everyone? Nope. Is it a viable option, absolutely. You invest in people or you invest in contracts. I&amp;rsquo;d rather invest in really, really good people. &lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;When it comes down to innovation, it&amp;rsquo;s a little more complicated:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;1. if wheel exists don&amp;rsquo;t build wheel.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;2. If the wheels aren&amp;rsquo;t exactly the shape or size you need, augment the wheels and contribute your augmentations back for review and inclusion in the wheel plans and inventory where possible and appropriate.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;3. If the wheels don&amp;rsquo;t exist, build a wheel and share the plans for the wheel whenever you can.&lt;/em&gt;```
#!/usr/bin/python&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if wheel == &amp;lsquo;yes&amp;rsquo;:
 print(&amp;lsquo;use existing wheel&amp;rsquo;)
 elseif &amp;lsquo;yes, but incomplete&amp;rsquo;:
 print(&amp;ldquo;augment wheel, contribute wheel changes&amp;rdquo;)
 elseif no:
 print(&amp;ldquo;build wheel, share plans&amp;rdquo;)
 print &amp;ldquo;Miller Time&amp;rdquo;
```* Code is provided as-is and is likely incorrect, we take no responsibility for poor code or fallout from running said code&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No privacy may be the new privacy.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/no-privacy-may-new-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 18:06:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/no-privacy-may-new-privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Taking politics and putting them aside, what the new administration has &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/03/23/technology/congress-moves-to-strike-internet-privacy-rules-from-obama-era.html?_r=0&#34;&gt;been attempting to change&lt;/a&gt; with regard to internet privacy is something we should &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; be informed about. Wether you have a tin foil hat or don&amp;rsquo;t care, &amp;ldquo;knowing is half the battle&amp;rdquo;. The other half is doing - which I will also lend some brief insight to (sorta). What&amp;rsquo;s changing? Nothing yet (as of the time of this writing). What will likely change? The ability of your internet (mobile or not) to sell your browsing habits and personal usage data. What does this mean? Well, it means that if you visit facebook, amazon, JC Penny, or buy-adult-toys.com a lot, that information can be sold to advertisers, private companies, etc., etc. &amp;ldquo;But I use SSL, I&amp;rsquo;m safe&amp;rdquo;. Nope. DNS query data - the requests made for a domain name like google.com, used to map a name to an IPvX address - that can be sold too. The content of the browsing is great, but the knowledge that a site was visited is just as useful&amp;hellip;and this data is generated not just by traditional &amp;ldquo;browsing&amp;rdquo;, everything that touches the internet uses it. Apps, Games, everything. Removing these rules also means that there is no oversight into how this collection can be done, what kind of data - sensitive or not - can be collected and sold and to whom. That&amp;rsquo;s what deregulation looks like, folks.&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/personal.info_.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/personal.info_.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; What does this mean for the average internet user like, say, my Mom or Dad? It means that when they look at ANYTHING online, it&amp;rsquo;s likely going to be collected, indexed, data mined, and then sold to be further data mined and then these users will get targeted for a barrage of advertising. Worse yet, this data is ripe for misuse. What if the data is compromised? Sorry. That&amp;rsquo;ll suck for sure. Even worse that than, what if that data is used by nation states? What if it&amp;rsquo;s misinterpreted? It&amp;rsquo;s a mess. Has this data been used in this manner in the past? Sure. All of the providers use it internally. &lt;a href=&#34;http://money.cnn.com/2016/07/25/technology/yahoo-verizon-deal-sale/&#34;&gt;Verizon bought yahoo&lt;/a&gt; for this reason.  The real issue is that most people do not understand what all of this means. Since the internet is a completely traceable environment in 99.999% of cases, unlike really anything prior, this is paramount. What can you do? Well, if you&amp;rsquo;re not technical, good luck. Perhaps if this happens it will spark a new industry of private overlays like Tor to be commercialized and widely adopted. Wait with the FCC leaning toward rolling back net neutrality those services could likely be slowed or blocked completely. Sorry. On the fringes are the mom-and-pop ISPs - they still exist. WISPs, small and rural providers. These are less likely to be the safest bet in the future should this come to pass. Mobile metadata - what will generate the majority of the controversy - is likely to be the most often sold because there will be such a diverse and deep pool of data. Another of the side effects is this could potentially be an even higher adoption of SSL, which is good, but may also lead to a higher adoption of the vile SSL decryption practice. Lets hope not. What will I do? Not sure. I have extensive experience running DNS servers and VPNs. I may just start connecting to one of my VPS devices and run everything over OpenVPN from both mobile and traditional connections. There are some super simple &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kylemanna/docker-openvpn&#34;&gt;docker how-tos&lt;/a&gt; out there that Ive used in the past. VPS service are cheap, I have a few but my &lt;a href=&#34;https://prgmr.com/xen/&#34;&gt;prgmr.com&lt;/a&gt; VPS is my favorite. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to tunnel IPv6 too. Welcome to 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brocade does a double down on SDN</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/brocade-does-a-double-down-on-sdn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 16:09:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/brocade-does-a-double-down-on-sdn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/event/nfd9/&#34;&gt;Network Field Day 9&lt;/a&gt;, I have spent more and more time mentally grinding on what Brocade is doing. I have been a pretty vocal critic of the foundry hardware and software platform since my first experience with it years and years ago. I found it to be lacking in completed features, Layer 3 functionality and general stability.&lt;br /&gt;
This is one reason that anyone reading this should take pause and think about the background this post is sourcing from and how much of a shift it is. I tend to be a pretty harsh critic and have (more than once) been labeled as irreverent when it comes to what is stated in the network and security industry, instead focusing on what is actually necessary in a production network. Brocade has added some good products and features, keeping their SDN features at the forefront, as expected. These are great, but while useful and innovataive, I am less interested in those technical abilities. Brocade has been a long standing icon in the SDN and specifically in the openflow and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opendaylight.org&#34;&gt;OpenDayLight&lt;/a&gt; space since the very early days. In fact, from an outsiders perspective they&amp;rsquo;ve bet their networking arm on it. They were one of the first to market and are able to make software changes quickly and add significant features due to the fact that their larger boxes are FPGA based. This is where it gets interesting for me as someone that had to manage large Foundry/Brocade networks for a number of years and who sports the scars and experiences to prove it. Knowing that the majority of the issues with their platform were software related things like lack of full featured protocols, buggy Layer 3 features and their infamously poor multicast support, the fact that they are laser focused on software defined networking has my wheels turning, and let me tell you why:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brocade is slurping up pretty much all of the thought leaders, idea producers, and game changers in the SDN community. This isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly ground breaking news, but it is worth repeating because it is significant. It signals, in a very public way, that they are not messing around. They&amp;rsquo;re embracing SDN and they are ready to stop selling sugar water and change the [networking]world. There is a related branch to this, bear with me, I&amp;rsquo;ll come back to it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brocade purchased &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brocade.com/launch/vyatta/&#34;&gt;Vyatta&lt;/a&gt;, a completely software based company and they did not just absorb the IP and rebadge it. They are actively integrating it, as a product, into their portfolio.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brocade is &lt;strong&gt;supporting&lt;/strong&gt; an open sourced based commercialized SDN controller. This signals that they are ready for someone to buy it, deploy it and use it in production. And to answer support questions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Circling back to my first point:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brocade hired &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelbushong&#34;&gt;Michael Bushong&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may ask, why does that really matter? I assert that this indicates a very key element inside of Brocade: they know that they need to adapt and that they need a visionary to help direct that change. Bushong has a long history of enacting significant change. He is also a smart guy (see degree from UC Berkeley in advanced heat transfer &amp;amp; fluid dynamics). Bushong was responsible for the SDN group and the One Junos initiative at Juniper. He was also a key player at Plexxi, a very innovative networking company with a unique product. He knows how to motivate and promote change and has built a culture that is open to it. In fact, after the NFD9 presentation several of the team members approached a handful of us and asked us to elaborate on the things we were asking about and requesting. I have also received follow ups on those items. These things may seem insignificant, but give some serious thought to how often network vendors ask these questions, follow up and actually &lt;em&gt;listen&lt;/em&gt; to needs and requirements that are non-standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of that opinion aside, Brocade is also bringing good featues and really thinking about how to change and more importantly, improve, a key element in a sucessful company (see H.G Wells: &amp;ldquo;Adapt or perish, now as ever, is nature&amp;rsquo;s inexorable imperative.&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remain intrigued.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crystal Ball: Cisco buying tail-f.  What does it mean?</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/crystal-ball-cisco-buying-tail-f-what-does-it-mean/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 16:24:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/crystal-ball-cisco-buying-tail-f-what-does-it-mean/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the recent &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tail-f.com/cisco-announces-intent-acquire-tail-f-acquisition-advances-ciscos-cloud-virtualization-portfolio-industry-leading-network-service-orchestration-technology/&#34;&gt;announcement of Cisco Systems intent to purchase tail-f&lt;/a&gt;, proponents of a multi-vendor environment are waiting with baited breath to see how the networking giant will deal with support of competitor hardware and CLIs. Yang is here to stay, there is no doubt about that. As is netconf. Both of these are good things for the industry as a whole, having a standard way to communicate with network hardware [&lt;a href=&#34;http://searchsdn.techtarget.com/opinion/OpenFlow-as-a-network-control-protocol-goes-deeper-than-data-center&#34;&gt;that isn&amp;rsquo;t openflow&lt;/a&gt;] is necessary and immeasurably useful. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go into the politics, the internal technical bits or even the details of who stays and who goes. Smarter folks than me have &lt;a href=&#34;http://lamejournal.com/2014/06/18/thoughts-cisco-acquiring-tail-f-systems/#more-2999&#34;&gt;already done that&lt;/a&gt;. Instead, I want to think about what this means for operators, architects and engineers when looking for a management platform. I wrote &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2014/02/tail-f-ncs-upsetting-network-management-in-a-good-way/&#34; title=&#34;Tail-F NCS: upsetting network management…in a good way.&#34;&gt;before about how Tail-f was a Rosetta Stone&lt;/a&gt; for networking equipment. With the Cisco acquisition looming, this potentially and very likely changes this and there now exists a gaping hole in this type of management system. So, what does that mean? If I had to guess, I&amp;rsquo;d say that even though Cisco has been a bit more friendly in the opensource world, it makes absolutely no sense for them to support a platform that allows for the use of any network platform. Perhaps I&amp;rsquo;m being cynical, but I doubt it. What this does is leave the majority of us looking for a cross vendor management solution, where the tail&amp;ndash;f NCS lives, out in the cold. However, there is a silver lining. The cup is half full in the forwarding plane today. My hopes is that the lack of a real commercial product that does what NCS does, and the awareness raised that such a product existed in the first place will kick start the FOSS world into building something. Only since RANCID have I seen a really viable option for cross platform management [and in the case of RANCID management=change and configuration tracking]. This also opens the door for an existing management protocol ::cough:: openflow ::cough:: to emerge as a really viable management and control protocol and mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Net Neutrality changes could force better fiber networks</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/net-neutrality-changes-could-force-better-fiber-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2014 18:40:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/net-neutrality-changes-could-force-better-fiber-networks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many regular internet users are extremely upset about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://techcrunch.com/2014/05/15/fccs-proposed-net-neutrality-rules-pass-3-2-enter-4-month-comment-period/&#34;&gt;recent proposed changes the FCC has opened for comments&lt;/a&gt; about the delivery and provisioning of internet services.  Watch this video if you&amp;rsquo;re unaware of the high emotions it has evoked: While these are proposed rules and are not in any way finalized, there is real concern that they may become law.  Where this is problematic is that it opens up the possibility of some real misuse, abuse or simple misunderstanding of needs and services. Do you want your service to be so heavily monitored that your every source and destination is billed for?  Yeah, that&amp;rsquo;s bananas, not to mention confusing and wrought with the possibility of erroneous and/or over billing.  It also required the consumer to be more acutely aware of everything they do, which isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily a bad thing, but most won&amp;rsquo;t or can&amp;rsquo;t bother to learn, so they become easy targets for predatory companies to charge for services that consumers may not realize they&amp;rsquo;re using. As someone who has run a production ISP on more than one occasion, I can see the huge draw of being able to bill for services.  From a technical perspective, it&amp;rsquo;d be a challenge to manage effectively and fairly and I hate to say it, but from a purely technical standpoint SDN actually makes this kind of granular billing, metering and shaping easier.  From a consumer perspective, it&amp;rsquo;s a nightmare.  Imagine ala cart &amp;ldquo;services&amp;rdquo; like channels on your cable TV.  Hulu? That&amp;rsquo;s $10 more a month.  NetFlix?  That&amp;rsquo;s $15, you get the point.  Fair and open access is the only way to do right be the consumer.  Being an ISP is hard, it&amp;rsquo;s a fine line between quality and profitability and wether folks like it or not, it is a fact that the money comes from oversubscription. What will this possible change in policy mean in the long and short term?  Let me tell you (in a bulleted list!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud data storage services for small businesses become a liability because now they can be double billed for them by IP provider and cloud provider which could _&lt;strong&gt;significantly&lt;/strong&gt; _change how cloud services work and force consumers and businesses to either build their own data centers back up, change their model for data services or forgo cloud services all together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users and businesses may be forced into cloud service provided by their ISP to get around large transit fees and become locked into a proprietary service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The use of guerilla networks start to pop up again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wide spread encrypted overlays and VPNs are used to get around  service fees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data caps become normal for every large provider (already happening).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open access municipal and private fiber networks become far more common than they are now.  This is &lt;a href=&#34;http://city-council.cityofdavis.org/Media/Default/Documents/PDF/CityCouncil/CouncilMeetings/Agendas/20140422/04G-RFEI-for-Davis-Broadband.pdf&#34;&gt;already happening&lt;/a&gt; on a smaller scale.  See &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uc2b.net&#34;&gt;UC2B&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.utopianet.org/&#34;&gt;UtopiaNet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cirbn.org/&#34;&gt;CIRBN&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://fiber.google.com/about/&#34;&gt;Google fiber&lt;/a&gt; and many others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settlement free, unmetered peerings and local peering hubs  become far more common between municipal networks, large enterprises and other entities in a given locality and eventually between the peering hubs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Horse trading between fiber resources becomes commonplace to reach other resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Purchasing managed transport services from CLECs to get to exchange points to purchase transit from real providers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last mile consumer broadband providers start to feel the pinch and realize they missed the boat.  Remember when cell phone minutes were billed by the minute and everything was an add-on feature?  Me too.  Now it&amp;rsquo;s a capped data plan and everything else is just free. You get the point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion the internet providers need to be re-classified as common carriers, and frankly, and the only reason it has not been is that law makers don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; understand it and they&amp;rsquo;re being preyed upon by the large telco and service provider lobbyists.  Ala Cart Image via&lt;a href=&#34;http://yates2.com/&#34;&gt; http://yates2.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blending the Network; Pluribus ServerSwitch</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/blending-the-network-pluribus-serverswitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 04:44:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/blending-the-network-pluribus-serverswitch/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I firmly believe that blending disciplines is the way of the future in IT. I&amp;rsquo;ve rambled about it here at &lt;a href=&#34;http://packetpushers.net/are-certifications-tests-still-worth-your-resources-in-the-day-of-hybrid-it/&#34;&gt;other venues&lt;/a&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;m vocal (some would probably say brash) about it on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/buraglio&#34;&gt;twitters&lt;/a&gt;.  Be it Networking and System, Systems and Security, Programming and Networking, most of us that have been around any length of time already do it but now it&amp;rsquo;s happening out in the open and &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DevOps&#34;&gt;DevOps&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;, a form of the hybrid IT worker, has seemingly become the BOTD (Buzzword of the day). With &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;hybrid&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; in mind, it was very apt that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pluribusnetworks.com/&#34;&gt;Pluribus Networks&lt;/a&gt; presented an intriguing spin on &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;hybrid&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; from the hardware point of view at &lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/event/nfd7/&#34;&gt;Network Field Day 7&lt;/a&gt;.  Remember the days or routers &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; switches? Sure you do. Then along came the L3 Switch and shook everything up.  Now you could do both on the same box simplifying OPEX and potentially CAPEX as well as maintenance fees. It became possible to simplify the architecture and even to to collapse it if so desired.  I certainly did not expect to see anything like that in Pluribus.  In fact, to be honest, I really was not sure what to expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/PBNet.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/PBNet.png&#34; alt=&#34;PBNet&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What pluribus brings is merchant based hardware but it has a spin that I  didn&amp;rsquo;t see coming.  A pretty innovative one, too. What others began by creating flexible, programmable and highly resilient OSs and/or feature rich hardware without big name fuss (and prices to accompany said fuss), &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pluribusnetworks.com/&#34;&gt;Pluribus&lt;/a&gt; has evolved one step further, added some serious steroids to the hardware and infused very flexible OS with many management vectors (CLI, API, GUI and even good &amp;lsquo;ol UNIX commands).  &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/800px-1968_El_Camino.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;800px-1968_El_Camino&#34; /&gt; Like a Reese&amp;rsquo;s peanut butter cup, Pluribus has blended two things that seem to work well together: a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pluribusnetworks.com/products/freedom-server-switch-line/&#34;&gt;powerful server platform&lt;/a&gt; for processing and potentially acting on massive amounts of data and a merchant based silicon switch with a good number of fast interfaces.  It&amp;rsquo;s a software driven hardware solution.  A host router, but so much more.  I&amp;rsquo;ve long thought that host based routing and switching was a powerful tool, having worked on several &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pfsense.org&#34;&gt;open source platforms&lt;/a&gt; that do just that.  However, the issues that inevitably came up were a lack of commercial hardware and software support, a structured, well defined market or the risk of the fracture of a community based product.  This provides answers to all of those concerns and offers a unique product to boot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;swerver&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Swerver&amp;rdquo;  &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the word that jumps into my brain when I try to categorize this nifty hybrid.  It&amp;rsquo;s a server, no it&amp;rsquo;s a switch no it&amp;rsquo;s a server &amp;hellip;It&amp;rsquo;s like an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chevrolet_El_Camino&#34;&gt;El Camino&lt;/a&gt; (or &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ford_Ranchero‎&#34;&gt;Ford Ranchero&lt;/a&gt;, depending on your persuasion), &amp;ldquo;Is it a car? Is it a Truck?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Yes.&amp;rdquo; Pluribus presents some interesting questions about how we can blend the network and systems into a more flexible platform with their server switch platform, creating an &lt;em&gt;infrastructure&lt;/em&gt; fabric as opposed to a &amp;ldquo;series of tubes&amp;rdquo; that &amp;ldquo;servers&amp;rdquo; connect to.  Their software suite is quite robust, too.  Anything from NAS to CDN, NAT to L3.  Oh, and they can run VMs, too.  I&amp;rsquo;m thinking a Bro IDS node, a blackhole router and a perfsonar node running right in the network fabric.  Very thought provoking stuff. I like to see ideas, products and people that lay it all out there and try to transform, to evoke thoughts and try to foster change.  This does that.  You can check out the videos from NFD7 &lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/appearance/pluribus-networks-presents-at-networking-field-day-7/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  I &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;dare&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; you to tell me you can not think of a use for something like this. &lt;a href=&#34;http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:1968_El_Camino.jpg&#34;&gt;El Camino Image Reference via WikiPedia&lt;/a&gt; Freedom Line image source Pluribus Networks   &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/about/disclaimer/&#34;&gt;Standard Disclaimer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenFlow Hybrid.  It&#39;s a must, not an option.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/openflow-hybrid-its-a-must-not-an-option/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 16:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/openflow-hybrid-its-a-must-not-an-option/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OpenFlow is, of course, a hot buzzword.  It&amp;rsquo;s the newest, and in my opinion, the most innovative thing to hit data networking since dynamic routing.  The ability to programmatically, systematically and potentially dynamically control traffic at the flow level through a network is innovative, exciting and terrifying [to many network engineers and architects] at the same time.  Allowing applications to touch the network change behavior is something that many engineers are not terribly comfortable with.  I will even admit that a few years ago I was pretty tentative about software changing network hardware.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2011/10/black-hole-routing/&#34; title=&#34;Black Hole routing&#34;&gt;Building a Blackhole router&lt;/a&gt; was an easy way for me to acquaint myself with this and get comfortable with software changing things without human interaction.   Most of my discomfort with this process was the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m not a good developer.  I can hack scripts and read most basic code in Shell, C, Perl, Python and Ruby but I don&amp;rsquo;t actively do anything but an occasional script or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2012/11/vdxrancid-contrib-scripts/&#34; title=&#34;VDXrancid contrib scripts&#34;&gt;hack&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2011/06/alurancid-and-pfrancid/&#34; title=&#34;alurancid and pfrancid&#34;&gt;to&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2010/12/alcatel-lucent-rancid-scripts/&#34; title=&#34;Alcatel Lucent RANCID scripts&#34;&gt;existing projects&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Enterprise-Network.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Enterprise-Network-265x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Enterprise Network&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Conversely, we&amp;rsquo;re all pretty comfortable with networks as they exist today.  The typical &amp;ldquo;enterprise pyramid&amp;rdquo; is best practice and works very well.  Good physical design is good physical design.  However, where this, and any other network gets hairy is when it scales to hyper scale or the operations team is thin. Here is where things get interesting.  Call it what you want, SDN is changing the way we as networking professionals think about this support model.  Remember managing fat wireless access points?  It became unruly and impossible at scale and once wireless ceased to be a convenience network it was nearly impossible.  Enter wireless controllers and thin access points.  5-7 years later this is now the standard.  The differences, though, is that wireless was still a relatively small footprint comparatively speaking and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a critical infrastructure before those changes had to happen. The problem that we face now is that we have critical infrastructure and legacy support mechanisms.  It is unreasonable to think that we&amp;rsquo;ll be ripping out a traditional, functional network and replacing it with a greenfield OpenFlow network, regardless of what the researchers and heavy proponents think.  Just like with the transitional mechanisms used in IPv6 deployments, there needs to be a transitional period where both traditional and OpenFlow networks can coexist.  There are a few options for this, but this is a problem that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://networkstatic.net/hybrid-openflow-using-the-normal-action/&#34;&gt;OFPP Normal action&lt;/a&gt; can potentially solve.     &lt;a href=&#34;https://openflow.stanford.edu/static/openflowj/releases/1.0.1/apidocs/org/openflow/protocol/OFPort.html#OFPP_NORMAL&#34;&gt;OFPP Normal&lt;/a&gt; will send a packet in the openflow pipeline to the native switching mechanisms for traditional forwarding, much like having a default route in an IGP handles anything without a more specific route. Based on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openflow.org/documents/openflow-spec-v1.0.0.pdf&#34;&gt;OpenFlow 1.0 spec&lt;/a&gt;, an OpenFlow enabled switch is not required to support all actions, &lt;strong&gt;may&lt;/strong&gt; support the NORMAL action.  I am here to say that my opinion is that this is something that has to happen.  It&amp;rsquo;s is reasonable to say that my understanding of OpenFlow is still evolving, but building networks is something I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing for 15 years.  Green fielding a totally OpenFlow network is almost certainly not going to happen in 95% of cases.  Backwards compatibility with existing networking is going to have to happen. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/tantrum.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/tantrum.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tantrum&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;As a case study, lets look at the adoption of IPv6.  We actually *need* IPv6.  Has adoption been smooth?  No.  Entities have been dragged into it kicking and screaming and tightly holding on to mechanisms like NAT as a way to delay the inevitable.  I could go on forever about how enterprises, service providers and any other network has caused more harm, pain and unnecessary expense than good by delaying IPv6 over and over&amp;hellip;.but I digress. We [mostly] don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;strong&gt;need&lt;/strong&gt; OpenFlow yet.  Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s useful.  Yes, it has use cases that make a lot of sense.  Making it easy (read: painless) is the key to deployment.   My first reaction is that hybrid mode is the way to do this.  If your vendor doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a hybrid strategy, make them aware that they need one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daylight, a new dawn is approaching.</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/daylight-a-new-dawn-is-approaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 04:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/daylight-a-new-dawn-is-approaching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The SDN world is abuzz with the announcement that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opendaylight.org&#34;&gt;OpenDaylight controller&lt;/a&gt; came from stealth mode today.  Why is this important?  Well, SDN and OpenFlow are fractured.  It is Mac vs. PC, Beta vs VHS, Coke vs. Pepsi all over again&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;multiplied by 100x and with a handful of players. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/logo_opendaylight.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/logo_opendaylight.png&#34; alt=&#34;logo_opendaylight&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Vendor zealots and brand loyalists will nearly always side with their camp.  Heck, even I have some biases of personal preference.  But at the end of the day, the greater good is always most important.  This is why I&amp;rsquo;m cautiously optimistic about the daylight project.  From their about page: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;At this early stage of SDN adoption, the industry acknowledges the benefits of establishing an open, reference framework for programmability and control through an open source SDN solution. Such a framework maintains the flexibility and choice to allow organizations to deploy SDN as they please, yet still mitigates many of the risks of adopting early stage technologies and integrating with existing infrastructure investments.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; I find this refreshing.  I understand that there will be a bit of the &amp;ldquo;NDA this&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;closed that&amp;rdquo;.  These are new grounds being forged.  Vendors and humans in general don&amp;rsquo;t like to feel like they are giving away the farm and leaping into the fire. I tend to, personally, have a bit of the &amp;ldquo;jump and hope I have a parachute on&amp;rdquo; attitude.  I&amp;rsquo;m not risk averse and the thrill of the possibility of failure invigorates me.  That, obviously, is not how billion dollar companies think.  This is why the who&amp;rsquo;s who of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opendaylight.org/project/members&#34;&gt;Daylight members&lt;/a&gt; is so encouraging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bigswitch&lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/67/Collaboration_logo_V2.svg/607px-Collaboration_logo_V2.svg.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brocade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Juniper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cisco&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Citrix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ericsson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IBM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redhat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NEC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VMWare&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arista&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fujutsu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nuage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plumgrid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at that list.  Now look again.  There are names on there that I never would have expected. This project is associated with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linuxfoundation.org&#34;&gt;the linux foundation&lt;/a&gt;, an organization that has a core value of &amp;ldquo;Providing Neutral Collaboration and Education&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;  several names on this list are almost never associated with &amp;ldquo;Open&amp;rdquo;, Neutral&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Transparent&amp;rdquo;. This list and the implications of it by themselves are enough to raise heads, eyebrows and to potentially levitate &lt;a href=&#34;http://ghostbusters.wikia.com/wiki/Dana_Barrett&#34;&gt;Dana Barrett&lt;/a&gt; four feet above her covers. &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/levitate-dana.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;levitate-dana&#34; /&gt; Another double take piece of informationis that the project core components are based on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opendaylight.org/announcements/2013/04/industry-leaders-collaborate-opendaylight-project-donate-key-technologies&#34;&gt;Cisco OnePK&lt;/a&gt;.  The fact that the core is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/en/US/prod/iosswrel/onepk.html&#34;&gt;Cisco OnePK&lt;/a&gt; is certainly interesting, but the real gem of this is that there is potential collaboration and, more importantly, competition [and innovation] for an SDN controller and networking industry recognition that this &amp;ldquo;software defined networking revolution&amp;rdquo; is happening. Just like any complicated relationship there will be problems, posturing, compromise and impasses.  My thoughts are that the outcome of whatever daylight becomes or doesn&amp;rsquo;t is actually irrelevant.  There is now a far more powerful and encompassing movement happening.  ASIC companies are on board. The Linux foundation is involved.  Flexibility is implied.  Community involvement is encouraged.  Mountains are moving.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why hardware firewalls are the walking dead</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/why-hardware-firewalls-are-the-walking-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 11:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/why-hardware-firewalls-are-the-walking-dead/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OK, maybe they&amp;rsquo;re not totally dead, but they&amp;rsquo;re being demoted. To the mail room. During the course of my career I&amp;rsquo;ve always had at least some responsibility for firewall and security devices.  In those ~15 years, how these boxes are built and function has shifted.  From the perspective of my career, there were IOS ACLs (yes, I know, not a firewall), there was the IOS firewall versions and there were software packages such as gauntlet, checkpoint.  There was the Cisco PIX. One installation I worked on in a past life even chose to use IPFW on BSD boxes.   Then came was the Sonicwall, a newer take on how to manage a security appliance via a web interface. There was the FWSM.  A few things stayed the same. Dedicated hardware. &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Firewall-1024x670.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Free Firewall Clipart Illustrations at http://free.ClipartOf.com/&#34; /&gt; Being a networking guy by nature, it always irritated me that the inline security devices were 3 years behind networking&amp;hellip;.at best. Working in a service provider and in research and education has given me a bit of a different take on firewalls and IPS devices as well and has only solidified this belief.   There are a few things that make firewalls and IPS devices an unholy thing in the world that I live in. Since I &lt;strong&gt;love&lt;/strong&gt; bulleted lists, this is an opportunity to use one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They get in the way.&lt;/strong&gt;  Of course they to, that is their job.  Big data flows, Multicast, jumbo frames, IPv6.  There are boxes that can &lt;strong&gt;finally&lt;/strong&gt; do these things, but they are 5-7 years behind and even now are often lacking in support and features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re expensive.&lt;/strong&gt;  When considering CAPEX, they are often prohibitively expensive compared to something like a passive IDS.  Not many budget for a firewall / IPS that can do multi 10G at line rate, IPv6, Multicast and can handle things like GridFTP flows, because until recently they didn&amp;rsquo;t exist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speeds and Feeds are always first.&lt;/strong&gt;  I worked on 10G and OC192 on the WAN around 2002 with 10G on the LAN around the same time.  The first real firewall I saw that could even fall into consideration for that was the &lt;a href=&#34;http://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:pLu75PgugigJ:www.force10networks.com/news/pressreleases/2006/pr-2006-08-28_2.asp+&amp;amp;cd=1&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ct=clnk&amp;amp;gl=us&amp;amp;client=safari&#34;&gt;FPGA based P10&lt;/a&gt; from Force10 in 2005 (we had an early demo).  It was a really innovative device but even it was very clunky since it was an FPGA and caused service interruptions every time you needed to push rules to the FPGAs.  The Juniper SRX came much later at 2009, and even &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2010/09/updating-srx-idp-signatures/&#34; title=&#34;Updating SRX IDP signatures&#34;&gt;it&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2011/01/moving-junos-code-between-srx-cluster-nodes/&#34; title=&#34;Moving JunOS code between SRX cluster nodes&#34;&gt;had&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2010/10/enabling-ipv6-on-juniper-srx-5800-cluster/&#34; title=&#34;Enabling IPv6 on Juniper SRX 5800 cluster&#34;&gt;some&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2010/09/srx-ipv6-flow-based-processing/&#34; title=&#34;SRX IPv6 flow based processing&#34;&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt; back then.  There exists a handful of options now, the Sonicwall SuperMassive, the Juniper SRX  and the Palo Alto come to mind but they&amp;rsquo;re late.  10G is old hat to some of us.  We&amp;rsquo;re on to 40G and 100G.  What now?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, lets get down to the buzzwords.  Cloud.  Data Center.  Virtualization.  SDN.  OpenFlow.  Ironically enough, being &amp;ldquo;buzzword compliant&amp;rdquo; is actually relevant to this commentary. With the advent of virtualization of nearly everything, including the network, vendors are adding things like virtualized firewalls.  Juniper has added the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.juniper.net/us/en/dm/edge/products/&#34;&gt;JunosV Firefly&lt;/a&gt;, Cisco has added the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/en/US/products/ps12233/index.html&#34;&gt;VSG&lt;/a&gt;.  There are surely others.  This movement is just in it&amp;rsquo;s infancy, but it&amp;rsquo;s big and I would venture to say that it is game changing.  With the huge amounts of cores and memory in virtual machine hosts, it makes sense that the network become part of that for management, total cost of ownership and usability. The really interesting part of all of this comes not with the virtualization of firewalls, but with the commoditization of network silicon.  Chip makers that are spinning ASICS need to make sure their ducks are in a row since, in my personal opinion, there are a lot of options for LAN and data center equipment.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aristanetworks.com&#34;&gt;Arista&lt;/a&gt; is already on top of this.  Others vendors will adopt this methodology as merchant silicon adds more abilities.  Firewalls will are on their way now.  Eventually WAN gear will come around. What I&amp;rsquo;m really excited about is the prospect of a merchant silicon based, 40 or 100G OpenFlow based &amp;ldquo;Firewall&amp;rdquo;.  The foundation is already laid for this.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openflowhub.org/display/floodlightcontroller/Firewall+(Dev)&#34;&gt;Floodlight already has a dev module for building a firewall with OpenFlow&lt;/a&gt;.  I&amp;rsquo;ve not tested this extensively yet.  It&amp;rsquo;s on my short list but wether it works or not isn&amp;rsquo;t really even relevant.  The fact of the matter is that this is the way to a comfortable security perimeter at a reasonable speed for a far more reasonable price tag. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/OF-Firewall.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/OF-Firewall.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;OF-Firewall&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Think of buying an OpenFlow capable device with 40 and 100G interfaces in it as your firewall and IPS device.  Port cost is very low.  CAPEX is low.  OPEX is also fairly low since it is just a normal piece of network hardware.  Management is accomplished via an OpenFlow controller. Rules are pushed manually or programmatically based entirely on site policy.  IPS functions can be performed via a passive system like BroIDS or Snort triggering rules in OpenFlow much like is being commonly done with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2011/10/black-hole-routing/&#34; title=&#34;Black Hole routing&#34;&gt;black hole routers&lt;/a&gt; now. This will happen.  It&amp;rsquo;s already happening. Firewall vendors take notice.  Have a strategy for Virtualization.  Have a strategy for dealing with OpenFlow and SDN. It is my belief that once the reporting and management is even half as good as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.paloaltonetworks.com&#34;&gt;Palo Alto&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sonicwall.com&#34;&gt;Sonicwall&lt;/a&gt;, the market will start to change based solely on cost.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://openflow.marist.edu/avior.html&#34;&gt;There is already work being done on this as well&lt;/a&gt;. Am I right?  Time will be the judge, but I suspect I am.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Field Day 5 - Participate Remotely</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/network-field-day-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 14:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/network-field-day-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year, &lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/event/nfd5/&#34;&gt;Networking Field Day&lt;/a&gt; was something that I&amp;rsquo;d heard of but wasn&amp;rsquo;t really aware of what is really was.  I occasionally looked at Twitter and saw the hash tags but did not know much about how it was set up or what it was about.  In fact, I actually thought it was supposed to be like the HAM radio field day stuff where you go out and build out an emergency network on the fly.  OK, I should have done more homework, admittedly. Fast forward 6 months. I&amp;rsquo;m working more and more with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.networkstatic.com&#34;&gt;Brent Salisbury&lt;/a&gt; on day job stuff and he&amp;rsquo;s encouraging me to brush the dust off of my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net&#34;&gt;old blog&lt;/a&gt; (which became this site). I&amp;rsquo;m working more on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2013/02/building-a-floodlight-openflow-controller-on-centos-6/&#34; title=&#34;Building a Floodlight OpenFlow controller on CentOS 6&#34;&gt;OpenFlow&lt;/a&gt;,  virtualization stuff like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2013/03/centos-kvm-install-quick-start-to-a-vm/&#34; title=&#34;CentOS KVM Install – Quick Start to a VM&#34;&gt;KVM&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2013/01/headless-virtualbox-host-on-centos/&#34; title=&#34;Headless VirtualBox host on CentOS&#34;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com&#34;&gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt; and bringing up 100G WAN links.  I even had the extremely cool opportunity to do a &lt;a href=&#34;http://packetpushers.net/show-131-golf-cart-in-my-fibre-tunnel/&#34;&gt;Packet Pushers Podcast&lt;/a&gt;. Many of these things are a direct result of becoming more engaged in the larger community, a networking community I had pretty much carved myself out of back in 2002 when I left the service provider world for R&amp;amp;E.  This self isolation was a bit of an oversight on my part. What I did not realize was that, as someone in R&amp;amp;E, I had a unique perspective on some of the industry products and direction and was often seeing things a lot sooner than the general enterprise world. As I got more and more engaged I realized that there were a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt; of great folks out there that like to collaborate, share and write about their professional experiences in our field of choice.  These same people were doing innovative and interesting things that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/event/nfd5/&#34;&gt;NFD&lt;/a&gt; was one of those things.  So, I started to write down more of the things I was thinking and doing.  I figured that at least someone would find them useful or interesting or at least fodder for solving insomnia.  When I was asked to participate and come out to NFD5, I was both ecstatic and humbled at the same time.  This was the place where the networking industry thought leaders go to convene and discuss directionality as well as current networking technologies. Just to relay the scale and scope of the folks involved, here is the list of delegates for NFD5:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/brandon-carroll/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/Carroll-wpcf_60x60.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/Carroll-wpcf_60x60.jpeg&#34; title=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/Carroll-wpcf_60x60.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/brandon-carroll/&#34;&gt;Brandon Carroll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/BrandonCarroll&#34;&gt;@BrandonCarroll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CCIE Instructor, Blogger, and Technology Enthusiast&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/brent-salisbury/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/brent-salisbury1-wpcf_60x60.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/brent-salisbury1-wpcf_60x60.jpeg&#34; title=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/brent-salisbury1-wpcf_60x60.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/brent-salisbury/&#34;&gt;Brent Salisbury&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/NetworkStatic&#34;&gt;@NetworkStatic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brent Salisbury works as a Network Architect, CCIE #11972.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/colin-mcnamara/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/cmcnamara-headshot-2011-color-scaled-wpcf_42x60.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/cmcnamara-headshot-2011-color-scaled-wpcf_42x60.jpg&#34; title=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/cmcnamara-headshot-2011-color-scaled-wpcf_42x60.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/colin-mcnamara/&#34;&gt;Colin McNamara&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ColinMcNamara&#34;&gt;@ColinMcNamara&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colin McNamara is a seasoned professional with over 15 years experience with network and systems technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/ethan-banks/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/ethan-banks-headshot-500x667-wpcf_44x60.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/ethan-banks-headshot-500x667-wpcf_44x60.jpg&#34; title=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/ethan-banks-headshot-500x667-wpcf_44x60.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/ethan-banks/&#34;&gt;Ethan Banks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ECBanks&#34;&gt;@ECBanks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethan Banks, CCIE #20655, is a hands-on networking practitioner who has designed, built and maintained networks for higher education, state government, financial institutions, and technology corporations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/greg-ferro/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/Ferro-wpcf_60x39.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/Ferro-wpcf_60x39.jpg&#34; title=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/Ferro-wpcf_60x39.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/greg-ferro/&#34;&gt;Greg Ferro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/EtherealMind&#34;&gt;@EtherealMind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last twenty odd years, Greg has worked Sales, Technical and IT Management but mostly he delivers Network Architecture and Design. Today he works as a Freelance Consultant for F100 companies in the UK &amp;amp; Europe focussing on Data Centres, Security and Operational Automation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/john-herbert/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/johnherbert-wpcf_60x60.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/johnherbert-wpcf_60x60.jpeg&#34; title=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/johnherbert-wpcf_60x60.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/john-herbert/&#34;&gt;John Herbert&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/MrTugs&#34;&gt;@MrTugs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John has worked in the networking industry for 14 years, and obtained his CCIE Routing &amp;amp; Switching in early 2001.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/jon-langemak/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/profile_picture-wpcf_52x60.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/profile_picture-wpcf_52x60.jpg&#34; title=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/profile_picture-wpcf_52x60.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/jon-langemak/&#34;&gt;Jon Langemak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/blinken_lichten&#34;&gt;@blinken_lichten&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jon Langemak is a Network Engineer, tech blogger, and dedicated tech enthusiast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/josh-obrien/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/OBrien-wpcf_60x60.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/OBrien-wpcf_60x60.jpeg&#34; title=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/OBrien-wpcf_60x60.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/josh-obrien/&#34;&gt;Josh O’Brien&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/JoshOBrien77&#34;&gt;@JoshOBrien77&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Josh has worked in the industry for 14 years and is now serving as CTO in the Telemedicine sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/paul-stewart/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/IMG_0264-002-wpcf_60x60.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/IMG_0264-002-wpcf_60x60.jpg&#34; title=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/IMG_0264-002-wpcf_60x60.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/paul-stewart/&#34;&gt;Paul Stewart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/PacketU&#34;&gt;@PacketU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul Stewart is a Network and Security Engineer, Trainer and Blogger who enjoys understanding how things really work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/pete-welcher/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/DSC6539smaller2-wpcf_60x47.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/DSC6539smaller2-wpcf_60x47.jpg&#34; title=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/DSC6539smaller2-wpcf_60x47.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/pete-welcher/&#34;&gt;Pete Welcher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/pjwelcher&#34;&gt;@pjwelcher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pete is a 15+ year CCIE who loves network design, and is currently avidly learning various datacenter technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/terry-slattery/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/Slattery-wpcf_60x50.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/Slattery-wpcf_60x50.jpg&#34; title=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/Slattery-wpcf_60x50.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/terry-slattery/&#34;&gt;Terry Slattery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Terry Slattery, CCIE #1026, is a senior network engineer with decades of experience in the internetworking industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/tom-hollingsworth/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/bwry5mviq6ss0pe6m517-wpcf_46x60.png&#34; alt=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/bwry5mviq6ss0pe6m517-wpcf_46x60.png&#34; title=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/bwry5mviq6ss0pe6m517-wpcf_46x60.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/delegate/tom-hollingsworth/&#34;&gt;Tom Hollingsworth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/NetworkingNerd&#34;&gt;@NetworkingNerd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Hollingsworth, CCIE #29213, is a Senior Solutions Architect for a small VAR focusing primarily on K-12 education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the above folks, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.fosketts.net&#34;&gt;Steven Foskett&lt;/a&gt;, who is as prolific of a tech writer as he is experienced in the industry holds it all together and brings it to the public. The list of vendor participants is also deep.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com&#34;&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.juniper.net&#34;&gt;Juniper&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ruckuswireless.com&#34;&gt;Ruckus Wireless&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;www.plexxi.com/&#34;&gt;Plexxi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;www.brocade.com/&#34;&gt;Brocade&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.solarwinds.com&#34;&gt;SolarWinds&lt;/a&gt; are all on the docket. Unfortunately for me, I was not able to attend due to work scheduling and coordination of family stuff, something I truly lament.  To think that I was even considered to be on that list is truly humbling and something I&amp;rsquo;m very proud of. Not being able to attend, I wanted to participate as much as I could, so I started looking around and talking to folks and found the link to the live feed as well as the Twitter hashtag. It seems like a good idea to put this out there to as many folks as possible to not only bring attention to the fact that this is happening, but that you can participate from wherever you are.  I would encourage anyone who reads this and is interested in Networking as a profession, or is already in our industry, to pay attention to the Tech Field Day events.  Watch the live stream.  Ask questions and make comments on Twitter via the hashtag &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23NFD5&#34;&gt;#NFD5&lt;/a&gt;.  Get involved. During the event you should be able to do a live stream from right inside this post or from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/event/nfd5/&#34;&gt;NFD5 page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open source or open standards?</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/427/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 19:39:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/427/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networking and the PC parallel</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/networking-and-the-pc-parallel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 23:24:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/networking-and-the-pc-parallel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pc and networking timeline. Commodity hardware. Custom hardware. Asics. White box.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
