<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Virtualization on ForwardingPlane.net</title>
    <link>https://forwardingplane.net/tags/virtualization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Virtualization on ForwardingPlane.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2019, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 17:03:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://forwardingplane.net/tags/virtualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>FreeRouter as a test environment</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/freertr-as-a-lab-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 17:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/freertr-as-a-lab-environment/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago Kevin Myers of IP Architechs introduced me to a really interesting project called FreeRouter. Being that I absolutely love alternative routing platforms and feature complete simulation environments, this really got me going. I tend to define &amp;ldquo;feature complete&amp;rdquo; in a routing platform as something that can do both IS-IS and MPLS. Given that there aren&amp;rsquo;t many platforms that do both correctly or within a reasonable budget, and offer simulation options, I was pretty excited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ravello Systems review and use case study</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ravello-systems-review-and-use-case-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 16:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/ravello-systems-review-and-use-case-study/</guid>
      <description>There are a vast number of entities that offer the seemingly ubiquitous “cloud”. “SaaS”, “IaaS”, “BLAHaaS”, buzzword compliance is truly a sought after thing by marketing folks. With the proliferation of virtualization, containers and other “time slicing” of hardware by software the chatter can quickly become noise. As technical professionals and the warm bodies with the responsibility for actually making things work and keeping them running, the onus is on us to be able to decipher the useful from the fluff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring VMware ESXi with SNMP and Cacti</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/monitoring-vmware-esxi-with-snmp-and-cacti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 10:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/monitoring-vmware-esxi-with-snmp-and-cacti/</guid>
      <description>VMWare is a powerful tool, and monitoring is a critical service. How does one monitor such an integral piece of infrastructure, and what do they monitor it with? There are powerful commercial ways of monitoring VMware, however, for those with existing SNMP based systems in place, specifically cacti, there are options. To that end, I&amp;rsquo;ll set aside my strong distaste for SNMP [yet again], because those are for a larger, less useful series of posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a secured network in a box</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/building-a-secured-network-in-a-box-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 05:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/building-a-secured-network-in-a-box-comments/</guid>
      <description>Depenetration, whuaat? | JRLZN - Sep 4, 2013
[…] Photo Credit: http://www.forwardingplane.net/2013/07/building-a-secured-network-in-a-box/ […] [Aaron]( &amp;ldquo;Iamenabled@hotmail.com&amp;rdquo;) - Jul 5, 2013
Nick, can you share the server hardware you are using for your VMware host? Nick Buraglio - Jul 5, 2013
For this case it&amp;rsquo;s an older Dell PowerEdge 2900 with 16G RAM, 4 x 1G NIC and 8x2.3Ghz cores Nick Buraglio - Jul 0, 2013
On a reliability note, uptime has been fantastic Nick Buraglio - Jul 0, 2013</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a secured network in a box</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/building-a-secured-network-in-a-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 05:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/building-a-secured-network-in-a-box/</guid>
      <description>In many environments, the move to virtualization is a path well traveled. My home and lab networks are no exception to this and I&amp;rsquo;m sure nearly everyone who reads these pages has at least been exposed to it in one way or another. I have played with nearly all of the virtualization platforms and am firmly in the camp that there will be a large segment of networking that will move to a virtualized platform especially in the data center and campus segments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMWare ESXi CLI reference</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/vmware-esxi-cli-reference-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 14:24:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/vmware-esxi-cli-reference-comments/</guid>
      <description>[mike]( &amp;ldquo;mike@marseglia.org&amp;rdquo;) - Sep 4, 2013
You would be happy to hear that William Lam, engineer at VMware, has an excellent blog at http://www.virtuallyghetto.com/ where he comes up with useful scripts/tools. Also, you should check out the vSphere Management Assistant (vMA) at http://www.vmware.com/support/developer/vima/ </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMWare ESXi CLI reference</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/vmware-esxi-cli-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 14:24:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/vmware-esxi-cli-reference/</guid>
      <description>One of my biggest complaints about VMware is that it is an enterprise application. It has historically catered to the masses, which I completely understand, but those of us that aren&amp;rsquo;t a fortune 500 company are figuratively and operationally shoved into a corner and forced to find hackish ways of doing things to work around the enterprise nature. One really, really good example of this is OS dependency. I hated architecture dependencies back in the old days (x86, SPARC, PPC) and I absolutely despise things that are OS platform dependent now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VNC Console on VMware ESXi</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/vnc-console-on-vmware-esxi-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 03:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/vnc-console-on-vmware-esxi-comments/</guid>
      <description>tom - Jun 6, 2013
Hi Is the port same for all? RemoteDisplay.vnc.enabled = &amp;ldquo;TRUE&amp;rdquo; RemoteDisplay.vnc.port = 5910 RemoteDisplay.vnc.password = &amp;ldquo;VNCPassword&amp;rdquo; You say port 5910 but is it same port for everyone? Nick Buraglio - Jun 0, 2013
Port should be different for each VM. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VNC Console on VMware ESXi</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/vnc-console-on-vmware-esxi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 03:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/vnc-console-on-vmware-esxi/</guid>
      <description>Let me preface this post by saying that I am absolutely not an enterprise IT or systems guy, take everything that I write here on out with that as a side dish. I&amp;rsquo;m also very, very cheap. That said, one of the things I really like about KVM is the ability to easily view the console of a guest system using free, non-windows software like VNC. However, much like everything in life, there are reasons to do one thing or another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why hardware firewalls are the walking dead</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/why-hardware-firewalls-are-the-walking-dead-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 11:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/why-hardware-firewalls-are-the-walking-dead-comments/</guid>
      <description>[cryptochrome (@cryptochrome)]( &amp;ldquo;sascha@picchiantano.de&amp;rdquo;) - Mar 4, 2013
What everybody seems to forget is that actually simple stateful inspection firewalls are the walking dead. Modern firewalls do a lot of inspection at layer 7 (think Palo Alto Networks). I want to see one of those white box Intel boxes push 20 gigabit of application level firewalled traffic. I highly doubt it. And I am also curious how you want to put OpenFlow to use here, when basically every flow would need to be forwarded to the Controller and passed on to the &amp;ldquo;OpenFlow Firewall&amp;rdquo; for inspection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why hardware firewalls are the walking dead</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/why-hardware-firewalls-are-the-walking-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 11:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/why-hardware-firewalls-are-the-walking-dead/</guid>
      <description>OK, maybe they&amp;rsquo;re not totally dead, but they&amp;rsquo;re being demoted. To the mail room. During the course of my career I&amp;rsquo;ve always had at least some responsibility for firewall and security devices. In those ~15 years, how these boxes are built and function has shifted. From the perspective of my career, there were IOS ACLs (yes, I know, not a firewall), there was the IOS firewall versions and there were software packages such as gauntlet, checkpoint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CentOS KVM Install - Quick Start to a VM</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/centos-kvm-install-quick-start-to-a-vm-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 01:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/centos-kvm-install-quick-start-to-a-vm-comments/</guid>
      <description>Nick Buraglio - Mar 4, 2013
Fixed a typo in the ifcfg-br0 section. Networking Field Day 5, participation. - Mar 3, 2013
[&amp;hellip;] old blog (which became this site). I’m working more on OpenFlow, virtualization stuff like KVM, VirtualBox and VMware and bringing up 100G WAN links. I even had the extremely cool opportunity [&amp;hellip;] vps - Mar 4, 2013
I really like your blog. You write about very interesting things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CentOS KVM Install - Quick Start to a VM</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/centos-kvm-install-quick-start-to-a-vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 01:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/centos-kvm-install-quick-start-to-a-vm/</guid>
      <description>I am a network engineer by profession, but with the proliferation of SDN and OpenFlow, I have had to spend a lot of time re-learning a lot of system admin skills that I&amp;rsquo;d shelved years ago. Now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been a virtualization user forever. From VMware (Fusion, ESX), VirtualBox, to Parallels, I&amp;rsquo;ve used them at least in testing if not in production environments. I&amp;rsquo;d not really spent any mentionable amount of time with XEN, qEMU or KVM, but some projects I was working on suggested it for the virtualization mechanism, so I figured I&amp;rsquo;d try to pick it up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Headless VirtualBox host on CentOS</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/headless-virtualbox-host-on-centos-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 21:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/headless-virtualbox-host-on-centos-comments/</guid>
      <description>[Matt Kazmar]( &amp;ldquo;mkazmar@uic.edu&amp;rdquo;) - Feb 3, 2013
Why use VirtualBox as opposed to KVM? KVM is included with CentOS and fits your quite well into your Windows-less world&amp;hellip; Nick Buraglio - Feb 3, 2013
Just simple experience. I know the vbox CLI pretty well already. Additionally, if I build a VM in VirtualBox on another platform I can easily import and export it. KVM is on my [very] short list to learn, I think it is actually better based on some talkes I&amp;rsquo;ve had, I just don&amp;rsquo;t know it yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Headless VirtualBox host on CentOS</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/headless-virtualbox-host-on-centos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 21:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/headless-virtualbox-host-on-centos/</guid>
      <description>Starting from a base CentOS system with nothing configured, and referencing the CentOS wiki, here is how I like to set up a headless virtualbox environment: Disable selinux. It&amp;rsquo;s overly cumbersome and is enabled by default in CentOS. I like to permanently disable it even though the default is permissive. I ride the edge, I know.``` vi /etc/selinux/config
 and change  SELINUX=enabled
 to  SELINUX=disabled
 Then reboot. Using the methodology I originally found found [here](http://stackoverflow.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>