<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NSP on ForwardingPlane.net</title>
    <link>https://forwardingplane.net/tags/nsp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NSP on ForwardingPlane.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2019, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 01:29:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://forwardingplane.net/tags/nsp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates, podcasts, and videos</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/updates-podcasts-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 01:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/updates-podcasts-videos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anyone that looks at this site with any regularity may have noticed that I have been pretty remiss in adding posts - for that I apologize, things have been busy. However, I have not been absent in the tech world&amp;hellip;quite the opposite, in fact. I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending more and more time on podcasts and other forms of tech media which I have not provided links for here. So, to help expose that, here are a few of the other media resources I&amp;rsquo;ve been popping up in. Professionally I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending a lot of my time testing things like &lt;a href=&#34;http://techfieldday.com/event/srr1/&#34;&gt;segment routing&lt;/a&gt;, software routing stacks for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nanog.org/sites/default/files/2_White_The_State_Of_Open_Source_Routers.pdf&#34;&gt;disaggregated routing&lt;/a&gt;, DDoS detection and DDoS mitigation. In the free time I would typically spend in my home lab, I&amp;rsquo;ve become enamored with Wireless ISPs and how they work. I&amp;rsquo;d done some WISP work off and on over the years but it was primarily focused on L3 - I&amp;rsquo;ve gone deeper and started learning about more RF strategy and detail as well as delved pretty deeply into a fair amount of the gear details. There is some &lt;em&gt;crazy&lt;/em&gt; good, innovative stuff going on in this space and it happily hums along well outside of the hype engines that are the juggernauts of hyperscale data center and enterprise networking. I find it a refreshing change from the marketing machine of the mainstream networking industry, representing more of what the real world of being a smaller service provider is like (which is where I got started, so there is an amount of nostalgic comfort there), and there are folks out there are serious use cases for things like SR and &lt;a href=&#34;https://rule11.tech/?s=disaggregated&#34;&gt;disaggregated routing&lt;/a&gt; just waiting to be tested. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/IMG_3777.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/IMG_3777.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; In addition, I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved in a few projects regarding security and DDoS detection and mitigation (CoreFlow) that have been pretty interesting, one of which which &lt;a href=&#34;https://tnc17.geant.org/core/presentation/30&#34;&gt;I recently presented on at TNC 17 in Linz, Austria&lt;/a&gt;. Slides can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://tnc17.geant.org/getfile/3728&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. More information can be found on the project CoreFlow in the published paper &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com.au/citations?view_op=view_citation&amp;amp;hl=fr&amp;amp;user=alONArcAAAAJ&amp;amp;citation_for_view=alONArcAAAAJ:_Ybze24A_UAC&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably talk more about this project focused on ISP DDoS detection and mitigation as the code matures, but feel free to contact me with questions/comments. &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ipspace.net/2017/06/packet-fabric-on-software-gone-wild.html&#34;&gt;Packet Fabric Podcast on IPSpace.net&lt;/a&gt; Also see Ivan&amp;rsquo;s page for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ipspace.net/Podcast/Software_Gone_Wild&#34;&gt;Software Gone wild&lt;/a&gt; for more podcasts (both that I have been involved in and other good content) Brothers WISP Video on the basics of DNS (see also &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2016/02/nix4neteng-6-dns-ad-blocking-and-quality-of-experience/&#34;&gt;NIX for NetEng DNS&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forwardingplane.net/2014/06/nix4neteng-2-ipv46-address-investigation-tools-whois-dig/&#34;&gt;NIX for NetEng address tools&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternate model for Service Provider networks; or how to keep net neutrality intact</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/alternate-model-for-sp-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 05:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/alternate-model-for-sp-networks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There has been a lot of buzz about the service provider model, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Net_neutrality&#34;&gt;net neutrality&lt;/a&gt; and tiered access for consumers in the past few years.  Just this week &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theverge.com/2013/1/19/3894182/french-isp-orange-says-google-pays-to-send-traffic&#34;&gt;Google has been accused of paying Orange&lt;/a&gt; (more likely Orange is forcing google) for handling its traffic.  This is a VERY slippery slope that teeters on the edge of what we all want to avoid as consumers or content creators. This recent story has sparked something I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about for a very long time. Rewind to 1999. I worked for a small, regional broadband provider what seems like a lifetime ago, back when broadband was new and shiny and not terribly common.  We provided ATM based DSL, T1, ISDN and on some occasions dry copper gorilla net access to southern Chicago communities, Champaign-Urbana, IL, Danville, IL, Kankakee, IL,  a bit of west Indiana and a handful of small communities in between.  It was a proving ground for a young, motivated networking guy.  I was the senior network engineer, technical lead and for a while had a handful of direct report employees and students. This was where I really cut my teeth with routing, switching, content delivery and service levels. I ended up leaving there and moving on to work on a lot of HPC work and bleeding edge WAN stuff (think n x 10Gbps across the country in 2003).  However, one thing I took away from that ISP job was something that wasn&amp;rsquo;t really a new idea as much as just a uniquely positioned service and a good idea.  There was this local POP connection run by the university that allowed for exchange of  routes between any network that could pay the local loop charge.  It was a way to get cheap, fast access to anything local.  Unmetered, unfiltered.  Exchange any routes you want (that you own), take whatever routes you need. This was a clever model because down where we are located, 2.5 hours south of Chicago, transit bandwidth wasn&amp;rsquo;t (and isn&amp;rsquo;t) cheap.  Every local provider connected as did the community hospital, the university and a handful of others.  We took FULL advantage of fast connectivity between each other and all saved on transit bandwidth.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_research_and_education_network&#34;&gt;This kind of thing has been in place in the R&amp;amp;E&lt;/a&gt; community for far longer than I&amp;rsquo;ve been around. Fast forward 11 years. I&amp;rsquo;m still a huge fan of bi-lateral BGP peerings.  I want as many as I can get.  As a service provider I want a default free network with a lot of peers in many geographically diverse locations. I propose a [not-so]new model for service providers.  Create peering points, meet me routers.  Allow any network to connect for a port fee and exchange local routes.  Make these local routes free, unlimited and unfiltered (do your proper capacity planning, of course).  Opening up exchanges promotes better, diverse paths to resources and allows for a better overall user experience. Data is where the telecom companies make their money nowadays.  Net Neutrality is constantly in the news and in danger of being compromised.  Tiered services are everywhere.  I understand the need to meter service.  I did the ISP thing, I know that 5% of the users use 80% of the bandwidth.  That&amp;rsquo;s not new either.  I challenge larger service providers to think about it in a new way, though.  We&amp;rsquo;re making it work.  It&amp;rsquo;s a smaller scale, but it works.  I think it can scale if architected correctly.  It may have more operational overhead, but I suspect it can also command a bit more in price.  It could also allow for the non-asterisked use of the word &amp;ldquo;unlimited&amp;rdquo;, so marketing guys will love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it more engineering? Sure.  Is it harder to manage? Maybe, but likely not harder than architecting around content providers that don&amp;rsquo;t want to pay.  It is a better idea and promoting better service for both content providers and consumers of their service than making content providers pay for transit?  Absolutely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re doing this on &lt;a href=&#34;http://uc2b.net&#34;&gt;UC2B&lt;/a&gt;. It played a part in winning us the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.natoa.org/2012/09/natoa-announces-recipients-of-4.html&#34;&gt;Community Broadband Project of the Year award from the NATOA&lt;/a&gt;.  It&amp;rsquo;s a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternate model for Service Provider networks; or how to keep net neutrality intact</title>
      <link>https://forwardingplane.net/post/alternate-model-for-sp-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 05:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forwardingplane.net/post/alternate-model-for-sp-networks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There has been a lot of buzz about the service provider model, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Net_neutrality&#34;&gt;net neutrality&lt;/a&gt; and tiered access for consumers in the past few years.  Just this week &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theverge.com/2013/1/19/3894182/french-isp-orange-says-google-pays-to-send-traffic&#34;&gt;Google has been accused of paying Orange&lt;/a&gt; (more likely Orange is forcing google) for handling its traffic.  This is a VERY slippery slope that teeters on the edge of what we all want to avoid as consumers or content creators. This recent story has sparked something I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about for a very long time. Rewind to 1999. I worked for a small, regional broadband provider what seems like a lifetime ago, back when broadband was new and shiny and not terribly common.  We provided ATM based DSL, T1, ISDN and on some occasions dry copper gorilla net access to southern Chicago communities, Champaign-Urbana, IL, Danville, IL, Kankakee, IL,  a bit of west Indiana and a handful of small communities in between.  It was a proving ground for a young, motivated networking guy.  I was the senior network engineer, technical lead and for a while had a handful of direct report employees and students. This was where I really cut my teeth with routing, switching, content delivery and service levels. I ended up leaving there and moving on to work on a lot of HPC work and bleeding edge WAN stuff (think n x 10Gbps across the country in 2003).  However, one thing I took away from that ISP job was something that wasn&amp;rsquo;t really a new idea as much as just a uniquely positioned service and a good idea.  There was this local POP connection run by the university that allowed for exchange of  routes between any network that could pay the local loop charge.  It was a way to get cheap, fast access to anything local.  Unmetered, unfiltered.  Exchange any routes you want (that you own), take whatever routes you need. This was a clever model because down where we are located, 2.5 hours south of Chicago, transit bandwidth wasn&amp;rsquo;t (and isn&amp;rsquo;t) cheap.  Every local provider connected as did the community hospital, the university and a handful of others.  We took FULL advantage of fast connectivity between each other and all saved on transit bandwidth.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_research_and_education_network&#34;&gt;This kind of thing has been in place in the R&amp;amp;E&lt;/a&gt; community for far longer than I&amp;rsquo;ve been around. Fast forward 11 years. I&amp;rsquo;m still a huge fan of bi-lateral BGP peerings.  I want as many as I can get.  As a service provider I want a default free network with a lot of peers in many geographically diverse locations. I propose a [not-so]new model for service providers.  Create peering points, meet me routers.  Allow any network to connect for a port fee and exchange local routes.  Make these local routes free, unlimited and unfiltered (do your proper capacity planning, of course).  Opening up exchanges promotes better, diverse paths to resources and allows for a better overall user experience. Data is where the telecom companies make their money nowadays.  Net Neutrality is constantly in the news and in danger of being compromised.  Tiered services are everywhere.  I understand the need to meter service.  I did the ISP thing, I know that 5% of the users use 80% of the bandwidth.  That&amp;rsquo;s not new either.  I challenge larger service providers to think about it in a new way, though.  We&amp;rsquo;re making it work.  It&amp;rsquo;s a smaller scale, but it works.  I think it can scale if architected correctly.  It may have more operational overhead, but I suspect it can also command a bit more in price.  It could also allow for the non-asterisked use of the word &amp;ldquo;unlimited&amp;rdquo;, so marketing guys will love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it more engineering? Sure.  Is it harder to manage? Maybe, but likely not harder than architecting around content providers that don&amp;rsquo;t want to pay.  It is a better idea and promoting better service for both content providers and consumers of their service than making content providers pay for transit?  Absolutely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re doing this on &lt;a href=&#34;http://uc2b.net&#34;&gt;UC2B&lt;/a&gt;. It played a part in winning us the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.natoa.org/2012/09/natoa-announces-recipients-of-4.html&#34;&gt;Community Broadband Project of the Year award from the NATOA&lt;/a&gt;.  It&amp;rsquo;s a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
